<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tio2.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2024-10-24T09:06:09.888Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2133.77</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/</id>
    <published>2024-10-24T09:06:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-24T09:06:09.888Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,436 and $8,998 per ton, with some low-price transactions in certain regions. The price of liquid chlorine has fluctuated significantly today, causing enterprises to be cautious with raw material procurement. The downstream market is also experiencing a decline in activity, putting pressure on the titanium tetrachloride market, though prices remain stable for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The market price for grade one sponge titanium is approximately $5,962 to $6,043 per ton. Inventory pressure remains high, and competition in the market is intense, putting pressure on enterprises to sell their products.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2133.77, which is a slight decrease of 1 from yesterday. Market demand is weak, leading to significant sales pressure and inventory challenges for manufacturers. According to market sources, leading companies might implement discount policies, and there have been minor price reductions for some new orders recently, indicating a weak titanium dioxide market.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable hi</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.67</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/</id>
    <published>2024-10-23T06:52:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-23T06:53:03.742Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $844.31-$900.36 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have seen lower prices, but the market has low operating rates. High costs of raw materials exert pressure on companies, and the market price remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $5,909.92-$6,051.40 USD&#x2F;ton. The inventory pressure remains high, and market competition is intense, creating pressure on companies to sell.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current titanium dioxide price index is 2134.67, a decrease of 4 from the previous day. New orders are not performing well, leading to increased inventory for some manufacturers. With high raw material costs, small and medium-sized manufacturers face significant production pressure. The market remains cautious, with prices weakly stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-11 to 2024-10-18</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/</id>
    <published>2024-10-18T02:11:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T02:16:50.899Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Demand remains lackluster, resulting in large inventory pressures on manufacturers. Environmental regulations and equipment maintenance have led to reduced production in several regions, including Southwest China, East China, and Shandong.</li><li>Despite high raw material costs, manufacturers face significant cost pressures. However, due to the weak domestic demand and the imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil on Chinese titanium dioxide, there is considerable pressure on export prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium dioxide pigments is also under pressure, with several companies reducing prices to stimulate demand. The market remains subdued, with transactions being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li><li>The imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil has added to the challenges faced by Chinese manufacturers. Duties include $578 per ton for LB Group and $654 per ton for Anhui Jin Xing, among others.</li><li>Domestic trade continues to be sluggish, and manufacturers are struggling to balance production and sales, with operating rates hovering around 80%.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Downstream demand is expected to remain weak, leading to continued pressure on titanium dioxide prices.</li><li>Manufacturers are likely to maintain reduced production levels due to environmental and market pressures.</li><li>Export challenges, due to international trade measures, will continue to impact the market, requiring strategic adjustments by manufacturers.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.
 * Demand remains lackluster, resulti</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/2024_10_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/2024_10_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/</id>
    <published>2024-10-18T02:10:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T02:12:32.999Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the downstream market remains sluggish. High-titanium material is significantly impacting the market, with production at slag factories being inverted. Some transaction prices in the market continue to weaken, making the operation of the titanium slag market difficult.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,442.56 and $9,003.41 per ton. In certain regions, lower prices have been observed. Raw material prices are relatively unstable, and production pressures are high. The sponge titanium industry is weak, while the demand from the pearlescent industry remains stable, providing strong support for the titanium tetrachloride market. The market price is temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium civilian products is approximately $5,964.18 to $6,047.13 per ton. Enterprises face significant sales pressure, and prices are relatively low. The production of sponge titanium has decreased, and market information is chaotic, maintaining prices at a low level.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2134.82, remaining unchanged from yesterday. Market demand is weak, and raw material costs are relatively high. Manufacturer quotes remain stable. Some major manufacturers are undergoing maintenance, and the titanium dioxide market is temporarily stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the downstream market remains sluggish. High-titanium material is significantly impacting the market, with production at slag factories being inverted</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/</id>
    <published>2024-10-17T08:43:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-17T08:43:55.705Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions where companies have not yet engaged in tendering this month. The downstream market is sluggish, and the influx of enriched titanium materials has had a substantial impact. Production at slag plants is inverted, and some transaction prices continue to weaken, making the slag market difficult to operate.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Prices range between 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 844.46 to 900.38 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have seen lower prices. The raw material price for liquid chlorine is unstable, while titanium raw material prices are stable. Titanium tetrachloride producers are under production pressure, but quoted prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium civilian products is approximately 42,000 to 43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 5,909.43 to 6,048.54 USD&#x2F;ton). The market demand is weak, and companies are under pressure to sell. Price competition is intense, with some transactions occurring at lower-than-average prices. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2134.82, a decrease of 9 from yesterday. Market demand remains weak, competition is intense, and new transactions are lacking momentum. The market is weakly stable, with prices being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.

Titanium Slag: The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions wh</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2144.14</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/</id>
    <published>2024-10-16T03:35:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-16T03:36:28.830Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered, downstream market demand is sluggish, market information is confusing, and production pressure on enterprises is high. Downstream market purchasing remains cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $847.71-$904.11 USD&#x2F;ton. In some regions, there are transactions at lower prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, and titanium raw material prices remain steady. Production pressure is high for titanium tetrachloride enterprises, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is about 4.2-4.3 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $593.42-$607.55 USD&#x2F;ton. Enterprises continue to face pressure to ship, and there are some transactions at lower prices in the market. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2144.14, down by 9 from yesterday. Manufacturers in the Southwest, East China, and Shandong regions are undergoing maintenance. Market demand remains weak, and enterprises face significant pressure to ship. This month, market operation has slightly declined, but supply remains adequate. Prices continue to be negotiated on a per-order basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered,</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.52</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/</id>
    <published>2024-10-15T02:17:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T02:18:29.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern enterprises not yet tendering this month. Downstream market demand is sluggish with mixed signals. Companies are facing significant production pressure, and downstream purchases are cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges between $8,504 and $9,068 per ton, with some regions experiencing lower transaction prices. Raw material liquid chlorine prices are unstable, but titanium raw material prices are steady. Production pressures are significant, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream market price for Grade 1 titanium sponge is approximately $6,007 to $6,099 per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, and as production declines, recent prices remain stable. Market sentiment is cautious, with new transactions still weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2152.52, unchanged from the previous working day. Market quotations remain stable, and some manufacturers have slightly eased inventory pressure compared to earlier, but demand is still poor. Many enterprises are adopting a wait-and-see approach, with transaction prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.

Titanium Slag: The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern e</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-08 to 2024-10-12</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T08:51:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T08:54:34.278Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices are stable, with Mozambique ore priced at approximately $368 per ton and Kenyan 47-49 grade ore at $362 per ton.</li><li>The titanium slag market remains weak due to oversupply and low demand, with prices under pressure from low rutile prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>Titanium dioxide pigment prices have decreased by $28-$42 per ton post-holiday. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Leading manufacturers like the LB Group have lowered prices for both sulfate and chloride process TiO2 by $28-$42 per ton, following the general market trend.</li><li>Weak end-user demand and high raw material costs continue to apply pressure on production, leading to reduced output as some companies have begun maintenance shutdowns.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Ilmenite supply will remain tight, and prices are expected to stay stable.</li><li>The titanium dioxide market remains weak, with prices expected to hold at lower levels.</li><li>Sponge titanium production is decreasing, maintaining weak price stability.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.
 * Imported titanium ore prices a</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.19</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T02:11:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T02:12:34.913Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market remains weak but stable. Northern enterprises have not announced any new tenders this month. Downstream demand is decreasing, creating significant pressure on the high titanium slag market. Some enterprises in the north are reducing or halting production, leading to insufficient market activity and pessimistic market sentiment. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges from 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $849 to $905 USD&#x2F;ton. Some low-price transactions occur in certain areas, but overall sales volume is low. Despite high raw material costs, the titanium tetrachloride market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 4.2 to 4.3 million CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $594,000 to $608,000 USD&#x2F;ton. There is high inventory pressure, and as production decreases, recent sponge titanium prices remain stable. The market is in a wait-and-see mode, with weak new orders. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, maintaining low prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2152.19, down by 1 point from yesterday. With Brazil’s anti-dumping preliminary ruling publicized, export tax rates for enterprises are high, contributing to the pessimistic market sentiment. Domestic demand remains unsatisfactory, and the titanium dioxide market is weak but stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market rem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.8</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/</id>
    <published>2024-10-11T01:22:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-11T01:23:06.082Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-demand imbalance and competition from rutile prices. The market is under pressure, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 6,000 to 6,400 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 849 to 905 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. External sales are low, but high raw material costs keep the market stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 42,000 to 43,000 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 5,943 to 6,084 USD per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, with excess supply keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2152.8, a decrease of 5 points from yesterday. New contract prices are being executed, but demand remains weak. Companies are adopting a wait-and-see approach, and the market remains weak.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.

Titanium Slag: Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-dem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2158.3</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/</id>
    <published>2024-10-10T01:12:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-10T01:13:46.814Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $851.43 to $907.96 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, the market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $596,056 to $610,165 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2158.3, a slight increase of 2 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><p>This summary provides an overview of the current state of various titanium-related markets, highlighting price trends, market pressures, and operational impacts.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2156.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/</id>
    <published>2024-10-09T02:18:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-09T02:19:29.213Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grade titanium slag, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY per ton, which is approximately 850.52-907.10 USD per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. The external market sales volume is low, and with high titanium raw material prices, the market for titanium tetrachloride continues to remain stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for grade one sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY per ton, which is approximately 5,954.63-6,097.70 USD per ton. Demand has significantly reduced, leading to an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to cut production in October, and the output of sponge titanium continues to decline.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2156.16, a decrease of 45 from the previous business day. As leading companies lower their prices, post-holiday titanium dioxide companies have gradually adjusted their prices, mostly by 200 CNY per ton, which is approximately 28.36 USD per ton. The price of titanium dioxide is stable but weakening.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grad</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.26</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/</id>
    <published>2024-10-01T09:29:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T09:30:46.794Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The downstream market is weak, and the high slag industry is sluggish.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 857.12 to 914.27 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices due to weak demand. The domestic titanium dioxide market is under pressure with high raw material costs, leading to stable prices.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 5999.14 to 6141.23 USD&#x2F;ton. Downstream demand is weak, and there is an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to reduce production in October, leading to a continued decline in output.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2201.26, unchanged from yesterday. The market is in a wait-and-see state before the holiday, with poor transaction conditions. Prices are negotiated on a case-by-case basis, and the market is on hold.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.

Titanium Slag: The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The do</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.26</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/30/2024_09_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/30/2024_09_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/</id>
    <published>2024-09-30T00:47:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T00:48:54.496Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $857.12 to $914.27 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $5998.14 to $6141.47 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2201.26, which remains unchanged from the previous working day. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.89</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/29/2024_09_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.89/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/29/2024_09_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.89/</id>
    <published>2024-09-29T00:51:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-29T00:52:13.319Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is operating at low levels, with market prices on the lower side. The cost of titanium ore remains high, putting immense pressure on production, and the market remains weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 857.15 and 914.30 USD&#x2F;ton (6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton). Some regions have lower transaction prices. The downstream sponge titanium market continues to be sluggish, putting pressure on titanium tetrachloride sales and prices. There have been minor price adjustments in some regions, and the market is running weak but stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is approximately 6143-6429 USD&#x2F;ton (4.3-4.5 CNY&#x2F;ton). The demand for sponge titanium is weak, with market inventory present. Prices are low, downstream purchasing is cautious, and the price trend is weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2201.89, up by 3 from yesterday. Recently, the prices for raw materials and sulfuric acid have been declining, slightly reducing production costs. However, due to weak market demand, some titanium dioxide companies in the southwest and Shandong regions have made minor price adjustments, and the market continues to operate weakly.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is operating at low levels, with market prices on the lower side. The cost of titanium ore remains high, putting immense pressure on production, and the market remains weak.

Titanium Tetrachloride: The market price for titaniu</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-09-20 to 2024-09-27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:33:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:35:04.521Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices remain steady, with Mozambique titanium ore priced at around $368 per ton and Kenyan 47%-49% grade ore priced at around $362 per ton. The supply of imported titanium ore remains tight, and domestic signing is cautious.</li><li>The high titanium slag market is weak, with prices around $831-$839 per ton. Production costs are high, and enterprises are running at a loss, leading to reduced production and weak market conditions.</li><li>Titanium tetrachloride prices are stable at around $857-$914 per ton. The price of liquid chlorine is fluctuating, and high raw material prices are putting production pressure on titanium tetrachloride manufacturers.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak and stable. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2162-$2302 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2049-$2104 per ton.</li><li>With order volumes decreasing, some enterprises are experiencing inventory increases. As the holiday approaches, there is slight stocking in the downstream market, but overall demand remains weak. Some enterprises have temporarily halted production due to environmental and maintenance reasons, leading to a slight decrease in titanium dioxide production.</li><li>The market remains competitive, and downstream procurement is cautious due to high costs. The mainstream prices of titanium dioxide are stable, with some prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>After a brief period of market activity in the first half of this month, the market has returned to silence. Demand has been below expectations, the supply side is under significant cost pressure, and inventory has not yet bottomed out, indicating that weakness may persist. However, on the capital side, the purchasing power of the US dollar continues to decline, while the Chinese yuan has rebounded strongly. In summary, transaction prices denominated in US dollars will continue to rise slightly due to exchange rate fluctuations.</li><li>As the US dollar continues to weaken, the purchasing power of the global southern markets will continue to strengthen. With the peak demand season gradually approaching, the overall market price is likely to continue its slow upward trend.</li><li>There is an imbalance in the supply and demand of sponge titanium, and prices are expected to remain weak.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.
 * Imported titanium ore prices remain steady</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2199.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:05:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:54.850Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6,124.23 to $6,410.11 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.16, unchanged from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.

Titanium Tetrachloride: Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. S</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2199.47</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/</id>
    <published>2024-09-26T02:28:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:22.506Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide (TiO2):</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.74 to $911.65 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6125.01 to $6410.57 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.47, a slight increase of 5 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2194</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/</id>
    <published>2024-09-25T03:12:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:40.356Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p>Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions remain weak.</p><p>Titanium Slag The high-temperature market has low production activity, with market prices remaining low. The high cost of raw titanium ore puts immense pressure on enterprises, and the market remains sluggish.</p><p>Titanium Tetrachloride The market price for Titanium Tetrachloride is 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 852.47-909.24 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have lower transaction prices. Enterprises face significant cost pressures, and downstream cost pressures are also high. The price of Titanium Tetrachloride remains stable.</p><p>Titanium Sponge The mainstream price for first-grade Titanium Sponge in the market is about 4.3-4.5 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 611.08-639.90 USD&#x2F;ton). The demand for Titanium Sponge is weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices at a low level.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide Today’s Titanium Dioxide price index is 2193.57, unchanged from the previous working day. The market demand for Titanium Dioxide is weak, with enterprise orders gradually decreasing, and export pressures increasing. Some enterprises are gradually adjusting new order prices, and the market sentiment is cautious.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions re</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 price index hits a new low of the last year</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</id>
    <published>2022-08-18T06:58:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-18T07:14:44.613Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.<br><img src="https://tio2.pro/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/%E4%B8%8B%E8%BD%BD-1536x647.png" alt="TiO2 price index trend"><br>It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off seasonal, but the truth is far more than this.</p><p>After a strong period of growth since the late of 2020, the whole industry is getting to chill, party is over. And everything will final back to real life. And the value is getting back to its reality.<br>The global inflation. Food, energy, and very thing price is increasing. People is consuming on the things really matters, as to the pigments, is that really matter? The paints manufacturers are reporting of high stocks after the shortage of the first half of the year, and less willing to making new.<br>But long this could continues?</p><p>Based on our experience, this time price withdraw is basically a good sign to show that the global inflation is haling. And it will finally go back into the real track. To our estimation, without any blackswan inccidents, the index will finally wave at 1800~2100 level. And it could take 2 years to arrive at the postition where it belongs.<br>The original article:<a href="https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"> https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.

It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off s</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
