<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tio2.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2024-10-17T08:43:18.748Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/</id>
    <published>2024-10-17T08:43:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-17T08:43:18.748Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions where companies have not yet engaged in tendering this month. The downstream market is sluggish, and the influx of enriched titanium materials has had a substantial impact. Production at slag plants is inverted, and some transaction prices continue to weaken, making the slag market difficult to operate.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Prices range between 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 844.46 to 900.38 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have seen lower prices. The raw material price for liquid chlorine is unstable, while titanium raw material prices are stable. Titanium tetrachloride producers are under production pressure, but quoted prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium civilian products is approximately 42,000 to 43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 5,909.43 to 6,048.54 USD&#x2F;ton). The market demand is weak, and companies are under pressure to sell. Price competition is intense, with some transactions occurring at lower-than-average prices. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2134.82, a decrease of 9 from yesterday. Market demand remains weak, competition is intense, and new transactions are lacking momentum. The market is weakly stable, with prices being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.

Titanium Slag: The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions wh</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2144.14</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/</id>
    <published>2024-10-16T03:35:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-16T03:36:28.830Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered, downstream market demand is sluggish, market information is confusing, and production pressure on enterprises is high. Downstream market purchasing remains cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $847.71-$904.11 USD&#x2F;ton. In some regions, there are transactions at lower prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, and titanium raw material prices remain steady. Production pressure is high for titanium tetrachloride enterprises, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is about 4.2-4.3 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $593.42-$607.55 USD&#x2F;ton. Enterprises continue to face pressure to ship, and there are some transactions at lower prices in the market. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2144.14, down by 9 from yesterday. Manufacturers in the Southwest, East China, and Shandong regions are undergoing maintenance. Market demand remains weak, and enterprises face significant pressure to ship. This month, market operation has slightly declined, but supply remains adequate. Prices continue to be negotiated on a per-order basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered,</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.52</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/</id>
    <published>2024-10-15T02:17:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T02:18:29.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern enterprises not yet tendering this month. Downstream market demand is sluggish with mixed signals. Companies are facing significant production pressure, and downstream purchases are cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges between $8,504 and $9,068 per ton, with some regions experiencing lower transaction prices. Raw material liquid chlorine prices are unstable, but titanium raw material prices are steady. Production pressures are significant, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream market price for Grade 1 titanium sponge is approximately $6,007 to $6,099 per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, and as production declines, recent prices remain stable. Market sentiment is cautious, with new transactions still weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2152.52, unchanged from the previous working day. Market quotations remain stable, and some manufacturers have slightly eased inventory pressure compared to earlier, but demand is still poor. Many enterprises are adopting a wait-and-see approach, with transaction prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.

Titanium Slag: The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern e</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-08 to 2024-10-12</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T08:51:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T08:54:34.278Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices are stable, with Mozambique ore priced at approximately $368 per ton and Kenyan 47-49 grade ore at $362 per ton.</li><li>The titanium slag market remains weak due to oversupply and low demand, with prices under pressure from low rutile prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>Titanium dioxide pigment prices have decreased by $28-$42 per ton post-holiday. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Leading manufacturers like the LB Group have lowered prices for both sulfate and chloride process TiO2 by $28-$42 per ton, following the general market trend.</li><li>Weak end-user demand and high raw material costs continue to apply pressure on production, leading to reduced output as some companies have begun maintenance shutdowns.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Ilmenite supply will remain tight, and prices are expected to stay stable.</li><li>The titanium dioxide market remains weak, with prices expected to hold at lower levels.</li><li>Sponge titanium production is decreasing, maintaining weak price stability.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.
 * Imported titanium ore prices a</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.19</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T02:11:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T02:12:34.913Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market remains weak but stable. Northern enterprises have not announced any new tenders this month. Downstream demand is decreasing, creating significant pressure on the high titanium slag market. Some enterprises in the north are reducing or halting production, leading to insufficient market activity and pessimistic market sentiment. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges from 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $849 to $905 USD&#x2F;ton. Some low-price transactions occur in certain areas, but overall sales volume is low. Despite high raw material costs, the titanium tetrachloride market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 4.2 to 4.3 million CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $594,000 to $608,000 USD&#x2F;ton. There is high inventory pressure, and as production decreases, recent sponge titanium prices remain stable. The market is in a wait-and-see mode, with weak new orders. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, maintaining low prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2152.19, down by 1 point from yesterday. With Brazil’s anti-dumping preliminary ruling publicized, export tax rates for enterprises are high, contributing to the pessimistic market sentiment. Domestic demand remains unsatisfactory, and the titanium dioxide market is weak but stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market rem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.8</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/</id>
    <published>2024-10-11T01:22:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-11T01:23:06.082Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-demand imbalance and competition from rutile prices. The market is under pressure, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 6,000 to 6,400 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 849 to 905 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. External sales are low, but high raw material costs keep the market stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 42,000 to 43,000 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 5,943 to 6,084 USD per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, with excess supply keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2152.8, a decrease of 5 points from yesterday. New contract prices are being executed, but demand remains weak. Companies are adopting a wait-and-see approach, and the market remains weak.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.

Titanium Slag: Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-dem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2158.3</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/</id>
    <published>2024-10-10T01:12:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-10T01:13:46.814Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $851.43 to $907.96 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, the market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $596,056 to $610,165 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2158.3, a slight increase of 2 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><p>This summary provides an overview of the current state of various titanium-related markets, highlighting price trends, market pressures, and operational impacts.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2156.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/</id>
    <published>2024-10-09T02:18:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-09T02:19:29.213Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grade titanium slag, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY per ton, which is approximately 850.52-907.10 USD per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. The external market sales volume is low, and with high titanium raw material prices, the market for titanium tetrachloride continues to remain stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for grade one sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY per ton, which is approximately 5,954.63-6,097.70 USD per ton. Demand has significantly reduced, leading to an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to cut production in October, and the output of sponge titanium continues to decline.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2156.16, a decrease of 45 from the previous business day. As leading companies lower their prices, post-holiday titanium dioxide companies have gradually adjusted their prices, mostly by 200 CNY per ton, which is approximately 28.36 USD per ton. The price of titanium dioxide is stable but weakening.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grad</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.26</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/</id>
    <published>2024-10-01T09:29:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T09:30:46.794Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The downstream market is weak, and the high slag industry is sluggish.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 857.12 to 914.27 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices due to weak demand. The domestic titanium dioxide market is under pressure with high raw material costs, leading to stable prices.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 5999.14 to 6141.23 USD&#x2F;ton. Downstream demand is weak, and there is an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to reduce production in October, leading to a continued decline in output.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2201.26, unchanged from yesterday. The market is in a wait-and-see state before the holiday, with poor transaction conditions. Prices are negotiated on a case-by-case basis, and the market is on hold.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.

Titanium Slag: The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The do</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.26</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/30/2024_09_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/30/2024_09_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/</id>
    <published>2024-09-30T00:47:57.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T00:48:54.496Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $857.12 to $914.27 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $5998.14 to $6141.47 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2201.26, which remains unchanged from the previous working day. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.89</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/29/2024_09_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.89/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/29/2024_09_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.89/</id>
    <published>2024-09-29T00:51:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-29T00:52:13.319Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is operating at low levels, with market prices on the lower side. The cost of titanium ore remains high, putting immense pressure on production, and the market remains weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 857.15 and 914.30 USD&#x2F;ton (6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton). Some regions have lower transaction prices. The downstream sponge titanium market continues to be sluggish, putting pressure on titanium tetrachloride sales and prices. There have been minor price adjustments in some regions, and the market is running weak but stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is approximately 6143-6429 USD&#x2F;ton (4.3-4.5 CNY&#x2F;ton). The demand for sponge titanium is weak, with market inventory present. Prices are low, downstream purchasing is cautious, and the price trend is weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2201.89, up by 3 from yesterday. Recently, the prices for raw materials and sulfuric acid have been declining, slightly reducing production costs. However, due to weak market demand, some titanium dioxide companies in the southwest and Shandong regions have made minor price adjustments, and the market continues to operate weakly.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is operating at low levels, with market prices on the lower side. The cost of titanium ore remains high, putting immense pressure on production, and the market remains weak.

Titanium Tetrachloride: The market price for titaniu</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-09-20 to 2024-09-27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:33:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:35:04.521Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices remain steady, with Mozambique titanium ore priced at around $368 per ton and Kenyan 47%-49% grade ore priced at around $362 per ton. The supply of imported titanium ore remains tight, and domestic signing is cautious.</li><li>The high titanium slag market is weak, with prices around $831-$839 per ton. Production costs are high, and enterprises are running at a loss, leading to reduced production and weak market conditions.</li><li>Titanium tetrachloride prices are stable at around $857-$914 per ton. The price of liquid chlorine is fluctuating, and high raw material prices are putting production pressure on titanium tetrachloride manufacturers.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak and stable. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2162-$2302 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2049-$2104 per ton.</li><li>With order volumes decreasing, some enterprises are experiencing inventory increases. As the holiday approaches, there is slight stocking in the downstream market, but overall demand remains weak. Some enterprises have temporarily halted production due to environmental and maintenance reasons, leading to a slight decrease in titanium dioxide production.</li><li>The market remains competitive, and downstream procurement is cautious due to high costs. The mainstream prices of titanium dioxide are stable, with some prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>After a brief period of market activity in the first half of this month, the market has returned to silence. Demand has been below expectations, the supply side is under significant cost pressure, and inventory has not yet bottomed out, indicating that weakness may persist. However, on the capital side, the purchasing power of the US dollar continues to decline, while the Chinese yuan has rebounded strongly. In summary, transaction prices denominated in US dollars will continue to rise slightly due to exchange rate fluctuations.</li><li>As the US dollar continues to weaken, the purchasing power of the global southern markets will continue to strengthen. With the peak demand season gradually approaching, the overall market price is likely to continue its slow upward trend.</li><li>There is an imbalance in the supply and demand of sponge titanium, and prices are expected to remain weak.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.
 * Imported titanium ore prices remain steady</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2199.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:05:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:54.850Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6,124.23 to $6,410.11 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.16, unchanged from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.

Titanium Tetrachloride: Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. S</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2199.47</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/</id>
    <published>2024-09-26T02:28:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:22.506Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide (TiO2):</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.74 to $911.65 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6125.01 to $6410.57 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.47, a slight increase of 5 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2194</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/</id>
    <published>2024-09-25T03:12:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:36:40.356Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p>Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions remain weak.</p><p>Titanium Slag The high-temperature market has low production activity, with market prices remaining low. The high cost of raw titanium ore puts immense pressure on enterprises, and the market remains sluggish.</p><p>Titanium Tetrachloride The market price for Titanium Tetrachloride is 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 852.47-909.24 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have lower transaction prices. Enterprises face significant cost pressures, and downstream cost pressures are also high. The price of Titanium Tetrachloride remains stable.</p><p>Titanium Sponge The mainstream price for first-grade Titanium Sponge in the market is about 4.3-4.5 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 611.08-639.90 USD&#x2F;ton). The demand for Titanium Sponge is weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices at a low level.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide Today’s Titanium Dioxide price index is 2193.57, unchanged from the previous working day. The market demand for Titanium Dioxide is weak, with enterprise orders gradually decreasing, and export pressures increasing. Some enterprises are gradually adjusting new order prices, and the market sentiment is cautious.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions re</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 price index hits a new low of the last year</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</id>
    <published>2022-08-18T06:58:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-18T07:14:44.613Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.<br><img src="https://tio2.pro/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/%E4%B8%8B%E8%BD%BD-1536x647.png" alt="TiO2 price index trend"><br>It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off seasonal, but the truth is far more than this.</p><p>After a strong period of growth since the late of 2020, the whole industry is getting to chill, party is over. And everything will final back to real life. And the value is getting back to its reality.<br>The global inflation. Food, energy, and very thing price is increasing. People is consuming on the things really matters, as to the pigments, is that really matter? The paints manufacturers are reporting of high stocks after the shortage of the first half of the year, and less willing to making new.<br>But long this could continues?</p><p>Based on our experience, this time price withdraw is basically a good sign to show that the global inflation is haling. And it will finally go back into the real track. To our estimation, without any blackswan inccidents, the index will finally wave at 1800~2100 level. And it could take 2 years to arrive at the postition where it belongs.<br>The original article:<a href="https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"> https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.

It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off s</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide market analysis July 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/07/26/Titanium-dioxide-market-analysis-July-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/07/26/Titanium-dioxide-market-analysis-July-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-07-26T09:12:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-26T09:21:24.102Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-ore"><a href="#Titanium-ore" class="headerlink" title="Titanium ore"></a>Titanium ore</h2><p>As of now, the transaction price of 46.10 titanium ore from small and medium-sized manufacturers is 2150-2180 yuan &#x2F; ton, 47&#x2F;20 ore is quoted at 2400-2450 yuan &#x2F; ton, 38&#x2F;42 titanium ore is not The quotation including tax is 1530-1580 yuan &#x2F; ton; the iron ore construction has declined, the supply of medium-sized mines continues to be tight, the price is high and strong, and the cost of concentrate is under great pressure; the downstream titanium dioxide market continues to weaken, and the small and medium-sized miners of 10 mines are under relatively high pressure on shipments. The high-level price has also been adjusted back compared with the previous period, the high-low price difference has gradually narrowed, and the titanium ore market continues to run strongly.<br>The price of imported titanium ore has remained stable. As of now, the Australian titanium ore market is priced at US$460&#x2F;ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore market is priced at 480 US dollars&#x2F;ton, and Kenya’s 47-49 mines are temporarily unavailable. The international market for titanium raw materials is tight, and in the first half of the year The amount of imported ore returned to China decreased by 12.27% compared with the same period of last year; however, the downstream market remained weak, some prices were at a loss, and the price of non-mainstream imported ore was slightly adjusted, while the output of chlorinated titanium dioxide increased by 26% compared with the same period last year, and the demand for imported ore It is also increasing steadily, coupled with the release of new production capacity in the market in the third quarter, the price of titanium raw materials for the chloride process will continue to run at a high level. </p><h2 id="Titanium-slag"><a href="#Titanium-slag" class="headerlink" title="Titanium slag"></a>Titanium slag</h2><p>The high-titanium slag market continues to operate weakly. This month, the new bidding price of the northern 90 general slag high-titanium slag is 10,200 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the bidding price of low-calcium-magnesium high-titanium slag is 10,650 yuan&#x2F;ton. New production capacity is released, while the downstream market is under great pressure, some prices have already lost money, the market is oversupplied, and the high-titanium slag is running weakly.<br>This week, the acid residue market continued to run steadily and weakly. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 5,600 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price including tax in Yunnan is 5,000-5,550 yuan&#x2F;ton. Recently, the downstream titanium dioxide market has declined, and the acid residue market has shipped The pressure is high, the inventory of some manufacturers is high, the pressure of enterprises continues to increase, and the market transaction price is also weak.</p><h2 id="Titanium-tetrachloride"><a href="#Titanium-tetrachloride" class="headerlink" title="Titanium tetrachloride"></a>Titanium tetrachloride</h2><p>The market price of titanium chloride continued to decline this Thursday. The prices in Sichuan, Henan, Yunnan and other regions were reduced by 300 yuan&#x2F;ton. The current market price of titanium tetrachloride is 8500-8700 yuan&#x2F;ton; Although the price of titanium tetrachloride has been lowered, the profit of the enterprise is still good, but the downstream chlorination method titanium dioxide market is weak, and the titanium tetrachloride enterprises are also under certain pressure on the shipment, and the price of titanium tetrachloride will be adjusted in the later stage.</p><h2 id="Titanium-dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium dioxide"></a>Titanium dioxide</h2><p>This week, the market price of titanium dioxide is stable and weak. As of now, the ex-factory price of China’s rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 17300-18700 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 16300-17000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The market is in the off-season, the downstream market is under-operated, the demand for titanium dioxide is reduced, and enterprises are under great pressure, and some prices continue to fall; The price is in a state of loss; at present, the market price is relatively chaotic, the supply of low-priced goods continues to increase, and the competition pressure of enterprises is relatively large, and under the multiple negative factors, the titanium dioxide market will continue to be weak.</p><h2 id="sulfuric-acid"><a href="#sulfuric-acid" class="headerlink" title="sulfuric acid"></a>sulfuric acid</h2><p>This week, the domestic sulfuric acid market continued to decline sharply, with a decline of 50-300 yuan&#x2F;ton. As of now, the ex-factory price of 98% smelting acid in Anhui is 540-580 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price of 98% smelting acid in Yunnan is 370-470 yuan. &#x2F; ton, the price of 98% smelting acid in Shandong area is 330-350 yuan &#x2F; ton; the price of raw material sulfur continues to weaken, and the cost of sulfuric acid is reduced; the downstream market demand continues to be weak, the market demand for chemical fertilizers and phosphate fertilizers is weak, and the cost pressure of enterprises is great. The price continued to fall; and the sulfuric acid market started relatively high, the market was oversupplied, and the supply of low-priced goods in the market increased significantly, and the sulfuric acid market continued to operate weakly in the short term. Sponge titanium<br>The titanium sponge market remained stable this week. At present, the transaction price of grade 1 titanium sponge in the market is 74,000-85,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. In June, the export market of titanium sponge remained relatively good, and the downstream domestic and foreign demand was good. The inventory of titanium sponge enterprises was still low. The cost of raw materials is high, and the price of sponge titanium will continue to run high.</p><h2 id="Market-outlook-forecast"><a href="#Market-outlook-forecast" class="headerlink" title="Market outlook forecast:"></a>Market outlook forecast:</h2><ol><li>The price of medium and small mines is high, and the quotations of small and medium-sized mines continue to be firm;</li><li>The titanium dioxide market is off-season, the market demand is weak, and the price continues to run weakly;</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium ore
As of now, the transaction price of 46.10 titanium ore from small and medium-sized manufacturers is 2150-2180 yuan / ton, 47/20 ore is quoted at 2400-2450 yuan / ton, 38/42 titanium ore is not The quotation including tax is 1530-1580 yuan / ton; the iron ore construction has declined, t</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="titanium dioxide market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market-analysis/"/>
    
    <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
    <category term="titanium dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market review of June 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/29/TiO2-market-review-of-June-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/29/TiO2-market-review-of-June-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-06-29T07:33:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-29T07:45:43.447Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="1-Titanium-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1 Titanium Market Analysis"></a>1 Titanium Market Analysis</h1><h2 id="1-1-Market-price-analysis-of-titanium-series"><a href="#1-1-Market-price-analysis-of-titanium-series" class="headerlink" title="1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series"></a>1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series</h2><p>In June, the transaction price of Panxi Titanium Mine rose steadily. The cumulative increase of 46,10 mines was 30-50 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38,42 mines rose by 30 yuan&#x2F;ton at the end of the month. The prices of major manufacturers remained stable. So far ,<br>The price of Panxi Dachang 47,20 titanium ore is 2400-2450 yuan&#x2F;ton, the transaction price of small and medium 46,10 titanium ore is about 2160-2200 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38,42 ore excluding tax is 1530-1580 yuan&#x2F;ton. There are three main reasons for the increase in market prices: 1. The cost of raw ore is high, and the cost pressure of small and medium-sized factories is relatively large, and the enterprises are not operating enough; 2. The iron ore market is sluggish, and the supply of medium-sized mines is tight; The market has seen a lot of destocking of 10 mines, and the transaction price has risen slightly. At present, the overall demand for titanium ore is relatively stable, and some enterprises are still under-operated, and the supply of large enterprises in Xichang is still tight. As the titanium dioxide market enters the off-season, the cost pressure of enterprises Large, coupled with weak terminal demand, titanium ore prices are not expected to rise significantly.</p><p>Imported titanium ore prices remained stable, and market quotations remained firm. Up to now, the price of Australia 50 titanium ore is 460 US dollars &#x2F; ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore price is 480 US dollars &#x2F; ton, Kenya 47-49 ore is temporarily not quoting, and Vietnam imported ore is not temporarily quoting; downstream titanium dioxide and titanium slag market capacity Continued release, stable market demand, but the price of imported ore is high, the cost pressure of enterprises is relatively large, and the high-priced orders are under pressure; according to customs statistics, imported titanium ore in May was 205,400 tons, a year-on-year decrease of 9.41%. In May, China imported about 1.4676 million tons of titanium ore, a year-on-year decrease of 9.46%. This year, the mainstream importing countries have declined severely, and domestic supply is still tight. In addition, in the second half of the year, there will be new production capacity released by the chlorination method, and the price of imported titanium ore will also continue. run high.</p><p>The price of titanium slag<br>in the acid slag market fell sharply in June. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 5,600 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price in Yunnan is 5,000-5,550 yuan&#x2F;ton. The downstream titanium dioxide market continues to be weak, and is affected by the Panxi part Influenced by the conversion of slag from manufacturers to mines, the demand for acid slag has decreased, enterprises are under great pressure on shipments, and prices have fallen; manufacturers’ inventories have increased, and companies have been under great pressure.</p><p>The high-slag market remains stable. 6 The bidding price of ordinary high-slag in the north is 10,400 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the bidding price of low-calcium-magnesium high-slag is 11,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The bidding in July will start soon, and the price is expected to be the same as last month. The market is running well, companies in the north are actively working, and some companies in the south are converting acid residues to high-slag production, and the market supply has increased; the downstream market demand is stable. Multi-dimensional stable operation.</p><p>The price of titanium tetrachloride<br>maintained stable operation this month. The market quotation of titanium tetrachloride was 8700-9100 yuan&#x2F;ton; the price of raw materials was high, the cost of titanium tetrachloride increased, and the market demand was relatively stable. The overall titanium tetrachloride market Relatively stable; while the downstream titanium sponge market is running well, and the price remains stable, the price of titanium tetrachloride is expected to continue to run steadily.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide<br>The titanium dioxide market in June was relatively chaotic, and the quotations of manufacturers were reduced by different degrees, and the price was reduced to 800-1200 yuan&#x2F;ton. The ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide including tax is 17500-18500 yuan &#x2F; ton; in June, the price of dragon enterprises remained stable, and the rebate discount did not change compared with the previous period. Influenced by other factors, the market economy is not good, the demand in East China and other regions has been greatly reduced, and enterprises are under great pressure to ship goods; the export market has remained stable in the past two months, but the domestic sales market is still weak, the competition pressure of enterprises is large, and market prices are running chaotically; raw material prices High, some low prices are on the verge of loss, and market competition is under great pressure. At the end of the month, the prices of individual companies have been lowered again, and the market has entered a traditional off-season. In July, market prices will continue to run weakly.</p><p>Sponge titanium<br>The sponge titanium market performed well in June. At present, the first-grade sponge titanium market price is 74,000-85,000 yuan &#x2F; ton. The price of raw magnesium ingots continues to fall. The pressure on semi-process enterprises has eased, and enterprises have gradually resumed construction; domestic and foreign market demand Continued to be strong, the export market for civilian products has increased significantly, the inventory of sponge titanium manufacturers will remain low, the new production capacity in the market will continue to be released, the market supply will increase, and the price of sponge titanium will continue to be high.</p><p>July market forecast:</p><ol><li>The demand for titanium ore is stable, the market supply is tight, and the price may rise slightly;</li><li>The titanium dioxide market has entered the off-season, the demand is still weak, and the market will continue to operate weakly;</li><li>The market demand for sponge titanium increases, the market supply is stable, and the market price runs smoothly.</li></ol><h2 id="1-2-Import-and-Export"><a href="#1-2-Import-and-Export" class="headerlink" title="1.2 Import and Export"></a>1.2 Import and Export</h2><p>Titanium ore<br>China imported 205,400 tons of titanium ore in May 2022, with a monthly average price of US$422&#x2F;ton, a year-on-year decrease of 9.41% and a month-on-month decrease of 56.06%; the top three countries in terms of import volume in May are: Mozambique, Norway, Vietnam; 2022 From January to May of this year, China imported about 1.4676 million tons of titanium ore, a year-on-year decrease of 9.46%, and the import volume decreased by about 153,400 tons.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide<br>China imported about 15,000 tons of titanium dioxide in May 2022, a year-on-year decrease of 5.06% and a month-on-month decrease of 2.57%; the top three imported regions in May were Taiwan, Mexico, and Australia; the cumulative import volume of titanium dioxide from January to May 2022 About 67,100 tons, a decrease of 17.17% compared with the same period last year, and the import volume decreased by about 13,900 tons.</p><p>According to customs data, China’s titanium dioxide exports in May 2022 will be about 115,700 tons, a year-on-year increase of 10.31% and a month-on-month decrease of 2.48%; the top three countries in terms of titanium dioxide exports in May are: India, Vietnam, and South Korea; January-May 2022 The cumulative export volume of titanium dioxide in the month was about 622,300 tons, a year-on-year increase of 15.24%, and the export volume increased by about 82,300 tons.</p><p>Titanium sponge<br>In May 2022, the import of titanium sponge was about 1357.4 tons, an increase of 55.56% year-on-year and a month-on-month increase of 23.26%; from January to May 2022, the cumulative import volume of titanium sponge in China was about 6548.9 tons, an increase of 66.37% year-on-year, and the import volume increased by about 2612.6 Ton.</p><p>In May 2022, China’s export of titanium sponge was about 256.8 tons, a year-on-year increase of 98.87% and a month-on-month decrease of 25.40 %; the cumulative export from January to May 2022 was about 748.2 tons, an increase of 45.71% year-on-year, and the import volume increased by about 234.72 tons.</p><h1 id="2-Production-of-titanium-dioxide-and-titanium-sponge-in-May"><a href="#2-Production-of-titanium-dioxide-and-titanium-sponge-in-May" class="headerlink" title="2 Production of titanium dioxide and titanium sponge in May"></a>2 Production of titanium dioxide and titanium sponge in May</h1><p>2.1 Yield Analysis:<br>According to Tu Duoduo’s statistics, in May 2022, China’s titanium dioxide output was 344,100 tons, a month-on-month increase of 2.28% and a year-on-year increase of 4.49%; Production increased by about 135,800 tons. In May, the regional output increased and decreased. Due to the overhaul of some devices and the influence of inventory pressure, the production of enterprises decreased. In May, some enterprises completed the maintenance, the output increased, and the overall output increased slightly.</p><p>The top three regions in May output were Sichuan, Henan, and Shandong, accounting for 21%, 15%, and 14% of the total output.</p><p>According to Tu Duoduo’s statistics, China’s titanium sponge output in May 2022 was 12,500 tons, a year-on-year increase of 0.24%. The output of titanium sponge in April 2022 increased by 9.65%. In May, China’s titanium sponge production maintained a steady and moderate growth trend. In June, semi-process titanium sponge enterprises Shengfeng Titanium Industry and Anshan Massive Plant will resume production. The production capacity of each enterprise will gradually be released, and the output of sponge titanium will reach a new record high.</p><p>In May, Liaoning, Xinjiang, and Henan, the top three domestic production areas of titanium sponge in China, accounted for 23%, 19% and 15% of the total domestic output respectively.</p><h1 id="3-Industry-News-of-the-Month"><a href="#3-Industry-News-of-the-Month" class="headerlink" title="3 Industry News of the Month"></a>3 Industry News of the Month</h1><p>“Invest 1 billion! The 500,000-ton paint project was officially put into production! 》<br>The first phase of the Jiangxi Tulian Waterborne Coatings Industrial Base Project invested and constructed by Jiangxi Tulian Group, the Yaka architectural paint production workshop in the first phase was completed and put into production recently. The project started construction on July 10, 2020, with a total area of ​​500 acres, of which: the first phase of the project covers an area of ​​300 acres and a total construction area of ​​230,000 square meters.</p><p>The total investment of the project is 1 billion yuan. It is designed to produce 500,000 tons of water-based environmental protection coatings, 200,000 tons of dry powder putty, 20 million square meters of polymer waterproof materials, 1 million square meters of thermal insulation and decoration integrated boards, and 50,000 tons of annual output. The construction emulsion and the annual output of 200,000 sets of coating packaging materials are expected to achieve an annual sales income of more than 1.5 billion yuan and an annual tax revenue of more than 45 million yuan after the project is completed.</p><p>“Anning Shares: At present, the company is going all out to promote the energy titanium project”<br>Anning Shares (002978.SZ) stated on the investor interaction platform on May 30 that the company’s fundamentals are good, cash flow is sufficient, and the asset-liability ratio is low. The company will always adhere to the prudent and stable business philosophy and adopt the strategy of “implementation in stages and dynamic adjustment”. At present, the company is going all out to promote the energy titanium project.</p><p>“China Nuclear Titanium Dioxide: Acquiring 50% Equity of China Nuclear Times with its Own Funds”<br>China Nuclear Titanium Dioxide (002145) (002145.SZ) issued an announcement on June 7, the company transferred its own funds of 977,900 yuan to Times Yongfu Technology Co., Ltd. Some have a 50% stake in Baiyin China Nuclear Times New Energy Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as “China Nuclear Times”). After the completion of this transaction, the company holds 100% of the equity of China Nuclear Times, and China Nuclear Times has become a wholly-owned subsidiary of the company.</p><p>Previously, in order to better implement the new requirements of the “dual carbon” goal and build a new green and circular economy, CNNC Titanium Dioxide and Times Yongfu signed the “Shareholders Agreement on the Establishment of a Joint Venture” on May 27, 2021. In the nuclear era, to promote the investment, construction and operation of comprehensive smart new energy projects such as photovoltaics, wind power, and energy storage. Among them, CNNC Titanium Dioxide and Times Yongfu subscribed for 50 million yuan respectively, each accounting for 50% of the registered capital of CNNC Times.</p><p>“Longbai Group develops efficiently and does a good job in extending, supplementing and strengthening the chain”<br>Longbai Group is in a period of rapid development. Since its successful listing in July 2011, the company has made two private placements, implemented equity incentives and employee stock ownership plans twice, and gave full play to its capital market advantages. In ten years, it has invested nearly 40 billion yuan in total. In project construction investment, product technology innovation and mergers and acquisitions, to help the rapid development of enterprises. Jiaozuo Park has built a 250,000-ton&#x2F;year sulfuric acid method titanium dioxide production line and a 400,000-ton&#x2F;year chloride method titanium dioxide production line, and implemented technological transformation and expansion. For the first time in 2021, the revenue will exceed 10 billion yuan; In the year of merger and acquisition, the production was resumed and the profit was made in the same year. At present, the production lines of chlorinated titanium dioxide and titanium sponge are in stable production, and the technological transformation and expansion are also progressing steadily. The company’s raw material base, the group will also make great efforts to increase investment, and spare no effort to carry out the investment and construction of extension chain and supplementary chain deep processing projects. In recent years, the average annual investment of the Group’s bases is about 4 billion to 5 billion yuan.</p><p>“Huiyun Titanium Industry Plans to Establish Three Subsidiaries to Expand Main Business Operations”<br>Huiyun Titanium Industry (300891) (300891.SZ) issued an announcement that in order to meet the needs of expanding main business operations and enhancing market competitiveness, the company plans to invest 10 million yuan (100% of the registered capital), establish a wholly-owned subsidiary Yunfu Huiyun Calcium Industry Co., Ltd.; plan to invest 10 million yuan (100% of the registered capital) to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary Yunfu Huiyun New Materials Co., Ltd.; It is proposed to invest 12 million yuan (60% of the registered capital); Yao Chuan, a natural person, will invest 8 million yuan (40% of the registered capital) to jointly establish a holding subsidiary Sichuan Yanyan Mining Co., Ltd.</p><p>The investment in the establishment of Huiyun Calcium Industry is mainly to produce calcium oxide to meet the needs of the company’s titanium dioxide production facilities and surrounding steel, chemical, environmental protection and other enterprises. The company invested in the establishment of Huiyun New Materials, under the background of the national “carbon peak” and “carbon neutral” policies and the rapid development of new energy technology, the company will use by-product waste acid, ferrous sulfate, etc. as iron phosphate. Produce raw materials, cut into the new energy iron phosphate industry, and realize the coupling of the titanium industry chain and the new energy industry chain. The investment in the establishment of Yanyan Mining is due to the intention of both parties to use their respective expertise and competitive advantages to jointly expand, integrate advantageous resources, and expand and strengthen related businesses, which is conducive to enhancing the company’s core competitiveness.</p><p>“Anning Shares: Bidding to Acquire 2.776% Equity of Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining”<br>Anning Co., Ltd. (002978) announced on the evening of June 22 that the company bid to obtain 2.776% equity of Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining Co., Ltd., and the final price was 140 million yuan. The target enterprise is one of the large vanadium-titanium magnetite mining and dressing enterprises in the Panxi region. The target enterprise completed and put into production in 2012 the mining and dressing scale of 3 million tons per year, and is currently actively applying for the mining right certificate of 10 million tons per year.</p><p>“Panshan Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium: The Company’s Comprehensive Energy Consumption of Titanium Dioxide Meets National Standards”<br>Panzhihua Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium (000629.SZ) stated on the investor interaction platform on June 21 that the company’s “2021 Panzhihua Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium ESG Report” comprehensively includes titanium dioxide The energy consumption of 1091.70Kgce&#x2F;t refers to the value of titanium dioxide by sulfuric acid method. According to the “Energy Consumption Limit of Titanium Dioxide Per Unit Product”, the comprehensive energy consumption of titanium dioxide of the company conforms to the national standard.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">1 Titanium Market Analysis
1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series
In June, the transaction price of Panxi Titanium Mine rose steadily. The cumulative increase of 46,10 mines was 30-50 yuan/ton, and the price of 38,42 mines rose by 30 yuan/ton at the end of the month. The prices of major manuf</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>In 2021, Sichuan&#39;s titanium concentrate production account for more than 90% of the country&#39;s</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/17/In-2021-Sichuan-s-titanium-concentrate-production-account-for-more-than-90-of-the-country-s/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/17/In-2021-Sichuan-s-titanium-concentrate-production-account-for-more-than-90-of-the-country-s/</id>
    <published>2022-06-17T02:53:46.783Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-17T03:08:08.815Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2021, the supply of titanium concentrate in Sichuan Province will reach a new high. The province’s annual output of titanium concentrate will reach 6.38 million tons, an increase of 460,000 tons or 8% year-on-year, accounting for more than 90% of the country’s total titanium concentrate.</p><p>The Panxi area of Sichuan Province is the main production base of titanium concentrate in my country. In 2021, Panzhihua City and Liangshan Prefecture contributed 5.3 million tons and 1.075 million tons of titanium concentrate respectively, providing solid raw materials for the development of my country’s titanium chemical industry and titanium metal industry. Assure. At the same time, Sichuan Province has formed an titanium concentrate industry cluster with Panzhihua Iron and Steel as the leader and LB Mining and Metallurgy, Anning Co., Ltd. and Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining as the backbone. Anning Co., Ltd. and Xichang Mining are the leading enterprises in the production of titanium concentrate with millions of tons, and they are the backbone enterprises in the supply of titanium concentrate in China.</p><p>Relying on its unique resource endowment and technological advantages, Sichuan Province has formed a whole industry chain of vanadium and titanium enterprises and industrial advantages represented by Panzhihua Iron and Steel Group, Longbai Group and Anning. Chemical and titanium production base.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">In 2021, the supply of titanium concentrate in Sichuan Province will reach a new high. The province’s annual output of titanium concentrate will reach 6.38 million tons, an increase of 460,000 tons or 8% year-on-year, accounting for more than 90% of the country’s total titanium concentrate.

The Pan</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="titanium concentrate production" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-concentrate-production/"/>
    
    <category term="sichuan&#39;s titanium" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/sichuan-s-titanium/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market review of May 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/08/TiO2-market-review-of-May-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/08/TiO2-market-review-of-May-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-06-08T02:03:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-08T08:23:49.097Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In May, the Panxi titanium mine market was stable and weak, and the prices of small and medium-sized titanium mines continued to decline, ranging from 50-100 yuan&#x2F;ton. The prices of some large manufacturers fell by 50 yuan&#x2F;ton from the end of last month. The prices of small and medium-sized mines continued to decline in the first half of the month. The price is quite high; as of now, the price of 47 and 20 titanium ore in Panxi Dachang is 2400-2450 yuan&#x2F;ton, the transaction price of 46 and 10 titanium ore is around 2150 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38 and 42 ore excluding tax At 1500-1550 yuan &#x2F; ton; the downstream titanium dioxide market demand continues to be weak, the titanium ore market demand weakens, the orders of small and medium-sized manufacturers have decreased significantly, and the price has fallen; In the second half of the month, the inquiries and purchases of downstream enterprises increased, the confidence of small and medium-sized titanium ore manufacturers increased, and the miners were more willing to support prices; the price of raw ore remained stable at a high level, and the cost pressure of small and medium-sized mine manufacturers was relatively large, and the price of low-priced titanium ore rebounded slightly at the end of the month . The market demand for titanium dioxide is temporarily stable, and the overall supply of titanium ore is still tight. The prices of large manufacturers will remain stable in June, and the prices of small and medium manufacturers will also remain stable, and individual quotations may continue to rise.</p><p>The market price of imported titanium ore has remained stable. As of now, the price of Australian 50 titanium ore is 460 US dollars &#x2F; ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore price is 480 US dollars &#x2F; ton, Kenya 47-49 ore is temporarily not quoting, and Vietnam’s imported ore is not temporarily quoting; The demand for imported titanium ore in domestic and foreign markets continued to be strong, and the amount of imported titanium ore increased significantly in April. According to customs data, China imported 467,500 tons of titanium ore in April 2022, and the domestic production capacity of chlorinated slag and chlorinated titanium dioxide was gradually released. Market demand is also gradually increasing; at present, the supply of imported titanium ore continues to maintain a tense situation, and some prices have been slightly increased.</p><h2 id="Titanium-slag"><a href="#Titanium-slag" class="headerlink" title="Titanium slag"></a>Titanium slag</h2><p>The acid residue market is running weakly and steadily this month. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 6,060-6,250 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price including tax in Yunnan is 5,800-6,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The downstream titanium dioxide market is weak, and the acid residue market is oversupplied. , the price has been under pressure, some small and medium-sized enterprises have made a small profit, and the mainstream price has remained basically stable; this month, with most acid residue enterprises in Yunnan reducing the operation, the supply and demand of the acid residue market is balanced, and the cost price is high and firm, the acid residue price is expected to continue. Hold steady.</p><p>The high slag market continued to rise in May. This month, the new tender price of ordinary high slag in the north was 10,400 yuan&#x2F;ton, up 200 yuan&#x2F;ton from the previous month. The downstream market demand of high slag continues to be strong, the inventory of manufacturers is not high, and the market supply is tight. In addition, the prices of raw materials and other materials continue to rise.</p><h2 id="Titanium-tetrachloride"><a href="#Titanium-tetrachloride" class="headerlink" title="Titanium tetrachloride"></a>Titanium tetrachloride</h2><p>This month, the market price of titanium tetrachloride has risen collectively, and the cost price has continued to rise. Titanium tetrachloride is under great pressure. At the beginning of the month, Longbai Group sent a letter to increase the price of titanium tetrachloride by 500 yuan&#x2F;ton. The titanium market quotation is 8,700-9,100 yuan &#x2F; ton; the cost price of raw materials and other materials remains high, coupled with the resumption of production and the release of new production capacity in the downstream sponge titanium market, the supply of titanium tetrachloride is tight, and the quotation rises; the price of titanium tetrachloride is high Enterprise profits have increased, some titanium tetrachloride manufacturers have resumed production, and the market supply and demand is balanced. It is expected that the price of titanium tetrachloride will remain stable.</p><h2 id="Titanium-dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium dioxide"></a>Titanium dioxide</h2><p>The titanium dioxide market improved in May. A total of five domestic companies sent letters to adjust prices, with an increase of 500-700 yuan &#x2F; ton. The international company Tenor issued a letter to increase the price by 200 US dollars &#x2F; ton since July 1; as of the end of this month, China The ex-factory price of rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 19,300-20,500 yuan &#x2F; ton, and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 17,800-18,500 yuan &#x2F; ton including tax; last month, factories that cut production and stopped production gradually resumed production, and the titanium dioxide market remains high; raw materials Titanium ore and sulfuric acid prices fluctuated at a high level, the overall pressure on titanium dioxide enterprises is still relatively large, and the cost price support is strong; the domestic demand market continues to be sluggish, titanium dioxide enterprises are under pressure to receive orders, and the market competition pressure is large; the foreign trade market remains good, according to customs The data shows that in April 2022, the export of titanium dioxide was 118,600 tons, a year-on-year increase of 10.64%. From January to April 2022, the cumulative export volume of titanium dioxide was 506,600 tons, an increase of 16.42% compared with the same period last year; the international market demand was temporarily stable, and the domestic market It will enter the traditional off-season, and the titanium dioxide market will continue to be strong in June.</p><h2 id="Sponge-titanium"><a href="#Sponge-titanium" class="headerlink" title="Sponge titanium"></a>Sponge titanium</h2><p>The market price of titanium sponge remained high in May. The current market price of titanium sponge is 74,000-85,000 yuan &#x2F; ton. The domestic and foreign market demand for titanium sponge is strong, the market supply is tight, and the inventory of manufacturers is not high. The export volume of titanium sponge in the international market in April There has been an increase, mainly due to the influence of Russia and Ukraine, and the shortage of titanium sponge resources in some countries; in June, the semi-process enterprises of titanium sponge will resume operation, and the new production capacity of other enterprises will be released, and the market supply of titanium sponge will continue to increase. Prices held steady.</p><p> June market forecast:</p><ol><li>The downstream demand is weak and stable, the cost is firm, and the price of titanium ore is stable;</li><li>The market demand for titanium dioxide is sluggish, and the market will continue to operate weakly;</li><li>The market supply of sponge titanium will increase, and the price will be firm.</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">In May, the Panxi titanium mine market was stable and weak, and the prices of small and medium-sized titanium mines continued to decline, ranging from 50-100 yuan/ton. The prices of some large manufacturers fell by 50 yuan/ton from the end of last month. The prices of small and medium-sized mines co</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
