<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tio2.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2024-12-19T01:11:34.821Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2199.47</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/12/19/2024_12_19-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/12/19/2024_12_19-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/</id>
    <published>2024-12-19T01:11:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-19T01:11:34.821Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide (TiO2):</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.74 to $911.65 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6125.01 to $6410.57 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.47, a slight increase of 5 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2025.24</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/12/18/2024_12_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2025.24/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/12/18/2024_12_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2025.24/</id>
    <published>2024-12-18T01:33:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-12-18T01:37:44.019Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The downstream market remains sluggish, with small and medium mining enterprises facing significant pressure to sell. Market transactions are at a standstill, with high prices for raw materials and high production costs at processing plants. Some companies have temporarily stabilized their quotations, and there is a strong sense of caution in the titanium ore market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> In December, northern enterprises quoted a price of 6,950 CNY&#x2F;ton for 90% low-calcium-magnesium high-titanium slag, which is an increase of 200 CNY&#x2F;ton from the previous month. The cost of raw materials remains high, leading to pressure from high slag costs. There is a tight supply of goods in the north, and market quotations are firm. Converted price is approximately $955.51 USD&#x2F;ton.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6,000 and 6,400 CNY&#x2F;ton. The cost is at a high level, and prices are stable. The downstream sponge titanium market has risen again, which may benefit the titanium tetrachloride market in the future. Converted price is approximately $825.08 to $879.91 USD&#x2F;ton.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> First-grade sponge titanium is quoted at approximately 44,000 to 46,000 CNY&#x2F;ton for civilian products. Previous market orders were stable, and current orders are gradually reducing market inventory. Given the cost prices, sponge titanium prices are steadily rising. Converted price is approximately $6,048.14 to $6,325.71 USD&#x2F;ton.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index for titanium dioxide is 2025.24,726.95, down by 6 from yesterday. The high price of raw materials is putting pressure on titanium dioxide prices. Companies are still struggling with sales, and market prices are chaotic. However, future market sentiment is mixed, influenced by raw material supply and prices.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The downstream market remains sluggish, with small and medium mining enterprises facing significant pressure to sell. Market transactions are at a standstill, with high prices for raw materials and high production costs at processing plants. Some compan</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2054.97</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/19/2024_11_19-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2054.97/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/19/2024_11_19-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2054.97/</id>
    <published>2024-11-19T01:11:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-19T01:19:49.721Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The inspection by the central environmental protection group in the Panxi region has ended. Some processing plants might resume operations, but as it is the off-season, inquiries for titanium ore remain weak. Due to tight supply, quotations from ore traders continue to remain stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> This month, northern enterprises have set the bidding price for 90% low-calcium, magnesium high-titanium slag at 6,750 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $935.37&#x2F;ton at the exchange rate of 7.21780. The downstream market is weak, and the high-titanium slag market is also running weakly. The bidding price for 85% low-calcium, magnesium high-titanium slag in Yunnan has not been announced yet. Due to high production costs, slag factories are facing challenges.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6,000-6,400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $831.50-$886.92&#x2F;ton. The high price of liquid chlorine is putting significant cost pressure on companies, making it difficult for both upstream and downstream sectors, hence, the price of titanium tetrachloride remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream market price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, translating to approximately $5,819.58-$5,958.94&#x2F;ton. Sponge titanium production remains stable, and while there is some relief in cost pressures due to the declining price of magnesium ingots, the market price remains temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The price index for titanium dioxide today is 2054.97, unchanged from the previous working day. Overall demand for titanium dioxide is weak, the market is sluggish, and there is a high eagerness to sell. However, due to poor downstream demand, titanium dioxide prices are steadily weakening, and market sentiment is quite pessimistic.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The inspection by the central environmental protection group in the Panxi region has ended. Some processing plants might resume operations, but as it is the off-season, inquiries for titanium ore remain weak. Due to tight supply, quotations from ore tra</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-11-08 to 2024-11-15</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/15/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-11-08-to-2024-11-15/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/15/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-11-08-to-2024-11-15/</id>
    <published>2024-11-15T01:41:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T01:42:36.810Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) is experiencing weakness, with prices of small and medium manufacturers around $283-$288 per ton (converted from 2040-2080 yuan&#x2F;ton using the exchange rate of 7.21640), and 38% titanium ore (excluding tax) priced at around $205-$212 per ton (converted from 1480-1530 yuan&#x2F;ton).</li><li>Prices for imported titanium ore remain steady. Mozambique titanium ore is priced at approximately $368 per ton, while Kenyan 47%-49% grade ore is priced at about $362 per ton. Despite high domestic ore prices, demand for imported ore is subdued, and the market remains largely in a wait-and-see state.</li><li>The titanium slag market is weak, with 90% low calcium and high titanium slag priced around $935 per ton (converted from 6750 yuan&#x2F;ton). High production costs and weak downstream demand continue to pressure the market.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2180 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $1967-$2022 per ton.</li><li>Due to weak market demand, large inventory pressures, and environmental constraints, some top manufacturers have lowered their prices. The LB Group is one such manufacturer that has adjusted its guiding prices downwards.</li><li>The international market is also challenging due to anti-dumping investigations from the EU, India, and Brazil, leading to increased pressure on exports and causing some enterprises to reduce their export orders.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Downstream demand for titanium dioxide is expected to remain weak, leading to continued pressure on prices.</li><li>The titanium dioxide market is in its off-season, which will likely result in stable to weaker pricing.</li><li>Cost pressures on titanium dioxide production remain high, limiting the potential for significant price reductions.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) is experiencing weakness, with prices of small and medium manufacturers around $283-$288 per ton (converted from 2040-2080 yuan/ton using the exchange rate of 7.21640), and 38% titanium ore (excluding </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2054.01</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/15/2024_11_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2054.01/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/15/2024_11_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2054.01/</id>
    <published>2024-11-15T01:38:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-15T01:42:36.808Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> This month, 90% of northern enterprises have reduced the high titanium slag agreement price to approximately $935.52 per ton. The downstream market is weak, demand support is insufficient, and the recent increase in dry battery prices has added pressure to slag production. Market activity remains, but operational performance is weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide (TiO2):</strong> The market price for titanium dioxide ranges from $831.68 to $887.08 per ton. The cost of raw material procurement is unstable, demand is weak, and market activity is insufficient. Companies face significant cost pressures, and the downstream sponge titanium market is sluggish, leading to a weak performance in the titanium dioxide market.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The main market price for first-grade sponge titanium is about $5,821.17 to $5,947.84 per ton. The prices are very low, and sponge titanium companies are operating at a loss. Market quotations remain firm, but downstream entities are cautiously observing, leading to a stable but weak trend in the sponge titanium market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today, the price index is 2054.01, an increase of $0.14 from yesterday. Overall demand for titanium dioxide pigment is weak, with insufficient sales volume and high market competition pressure. The downstream market is largely in a wait-and-see mode, and the titanium dioxide pigment market remains relatively weak.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: This month, 90% of northern enterprises have reduced the high titanium slag agreement price to app</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2065.07</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/13/2024_11_13-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2065.07/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/13/2024_11_13-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2065.07/</id>
    <published>2024-11-13T01:40:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-13T01:41:07.005Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> In the Panzhihua-Xichang region, some water selection plants remain unable to resume operations in the short term. The supply of intermediate concentrates is tight. With some companies engaging in contract processing, the market for titanium concentrate experiences sluggish flow and weak, stable pricing.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> This month, the bidding price for high titanium slag saw a significant decrease of 640 CNY&#x2F;ton. Northern companies set the bid price for 90% low-calcium magnesium high titanium slag at 6750 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 940.11 USD&#x2F;ton). The rise in electricity prices in Liaoning this month has increased production pressures on slag plants, leading to some production halts. Operations in Inner Mongolia are also insufficient, causing losses for high-slag enterprises and difficult market conditions.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around 42,000 to 43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 5,847.14 to 5,986.18 USD&#x2F;ton). High raw material costs are causing production losses for sponge titanium companies. Market quotes are firm, with downstream buyers cautiously observing, leading to a weak yet temporarily stable market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2065.07, down by 12 from yesterday. Recently, some companies have seen slight improvements in order intake, and with some orders on hand, inventory pressure is not significant. The market is in a low season, with weakened downstream demand and poor stocking sentiment. The overseas paper industry is sluggish, resulting in a significant drop in export orders for companies and a weak titanium dioxide market.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: In the Panzhihua-Xichang region, some water selection plants remain unable to resume operations in the short term. The supply of intermediate concentrates is tight. With some companies engaging in contract processing, the market for titanium concentrate</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2077.3</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/12/2024_11_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2077.3/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/12/2024_11_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2077.3/</id>
    <published>2024-11-12T01:11:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-12T01:12:30.758Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The bidding price for high titanium slag has significantly decreased by 640 CNY&#x2F;ton. Northern companies are bidding at a low price of 6750 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 941 USD&#x2F;ton. This is due to production losses and weak market conditions. The large market and existing inventories have led to unstable prices, with high titanium slag producers facing losses and continued market weakness.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 836-892 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have seen low-price transactions. The recent drop in resource prices has eased raw material costs, but weak downstream demand is leading to continued market price weakness.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream market price for first-grade civilian sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 5853-5994 USD&#x2F;ton. Despite high raw material costs, sponge titanium producers are experiencing production losses, with market prices remaining firm.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2077.3, down by 157.99 from the previous working day. While some companies previously had slightly stronger prices, mainstream companies have lowered their prices. The market remains stable as downstream demand maintains purchases.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The bidding price for high titanium slag has significantly decreased by 640 CNY/ton. Northern companies are bidding at a low price of 6750 CNY/ton, equivalent to approximately 941 USD/ton. This is due to production losses and weak market conditions. Th</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-11-01 to 2024-11-08</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/08/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-11-01-to-2024-11-08/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/08/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-11-01-to-2024-11-08/</id>
    <published>2024-11-08T01:51:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-08T01:52:09.655Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is experiencing a weak phase. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton. The market is in its off-season, and demand remains subdued.</li><li>Top manufacturers, including LB Group, are facing significant pressure from unsold inventory, and export sales are being impacted by anti-dumping duties in some regions.</li><li>Environmental inspections have led to reduced production capacity in areas like Panzhihua, further affecting the titanium dioxide market.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The market continues to show weak demand, with ongoing price reductions of $14-$28 per ton for new orders. This is largely due to the off-season and cautious purchasing behavior from downstream buyers.</li><li>Export markets are experiencing delays due to anti-dumping measures, further increasing the inventory levels at manufacturers.</li><li>Despite a decrease in prices, downstream orders remain cautious, and there is a general market outlook of pessimism.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Demand for titanium dioxide is expected to remain weak, with prices likely to continue their downward trend.</li><li>Environmental regulations and reduced production will keep supply tight, but demand issues will exert downward pressure on prices.</li><li>The market is expected to stay weak, with negotiations on a case-by-case basis for pricing.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is experiencing a weak phase. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton. The market is in its off-season, and demand remains s</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2109.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/08/2024_11_08-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2109.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/08/2024_11_08-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2109.82/</id>
    <published>2024-11-08T01:48:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-08T01:52:09.653Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market remains sluggish with chaotic pricing. Some transactions are below 7000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately $978.15 USD&#x2F;ton). Northern enterprises are starting to tender for low-calcium magnesium high titanium slag with a tender volume of 2000 tons. Due to demand impact, high slag prices are expected to run weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices for titanium tetrachloride are between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately $838.40-$894.13 USD&#x2F;ton). In some regions, transactions occur at lower prices. The raw material chlorine price fluctuates significantly, and although high titanium slag prices have been adjusted downwards, production pressure on enterprises is high. The price of titanium tetrachloride remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for grade one titanium sponge in the civilian market is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 5,926.30-6,067.19  USD&#x2F;ton). Market demand is weak. Although the price of raw material magnesium ingot has declined, enterprises are still under production pressure, leading to weak titanium sponge prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2109.82, a decrease of 21 compared to yesterday. Market order intake remains weak. Although companies have reduced inventory, it remains at a high level, leading to weak titanium dioxide prices.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market remains sluggish with chaotic pricing. Some transactions are below 7000 CNY/ton (approximately $978.15 USD/ton). Northern enterprises are starting to tender for low-calcium magnesium high titanium slag with a tender volume</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2129.12</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/07/2024_11_07-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.12/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/07/2024_11_07-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.12/</id>
    <published>2024-11-07T01:17:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-07T01:17:51.563Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. The current market low price for titanium ore is approximately 2,060 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to about 290.39 USD&#x2F;ton. High-priced sales face significant pressure. Import demand for titanium ore is weak, and there is strong price pressure from the downstream market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market remains sluggish with chaotic pricing. Some transactions are below 7,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is about 986.80 USD&#x2F;ton. Today, a northern company has started bidding for low-calcium magnesium high titanium slag, with a bidding volume of 2,000 tons.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6,000 and 6,400 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 845.77 to 902.03 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have seen lower prices. Recently, chlorine prices have risen, and although high titanium slag prices have decreased, companies face significant production pressure, keeping titanium tetrachloride prices stable for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The sponge titanium market’s main price for Grade 1 sponge titanium for civilian use is around 42,000 to 43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to about 5,920.92 to 6,062.92 USD&#x2F;ton. Downstream demand remains weak, with some companies facing high inventory pressure and insufficient production due to production cost pressures, leading to weak prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2129.12, down by 2 from yesterday. The market is in the off-season, and overall demand is poor. More companies are planning production cuts in November, leading to insufficient production and weak stability in titanium dioxide prices.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. The current market low price for titanium ore is approximately 2,060 CNY/ton, equivalent to about 290.39 USD/ton. High-priced sales face significant pressure. </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.2</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/06/2024_11_06-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.2/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/06/2024_11_06-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.2/</id>
    <published>2024-11-06T00:50:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:51:09.688Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. Current low transaction prices are around 2060 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 290.60 USD&#x2F;ton), while high-priced shipments face significant pressure.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-grade titanium slag market remains sluggish with chaotic pricing. Some transactions are below 7000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 987.43 USD&#x2F;ton). Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and downstream market operations are insufficient, leading to a weak market for high-grade slag.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 846.53-902.95 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have seen lower transaction prices. The market is under operating pressure with insufficient production, resulting in prices that are weak but stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary grade sponge titanium market price for civilian products is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 5,926.30-6,067.19 USD&#x2F;ton). Downstream demand remains weak, with some enterprises facing significant inventory pressure and insufficient production, compounded by production cost pressures. Thus, sponge titanium prices are weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2131.2, an increase of 10 from yesterday. The market is in a slow season, with overall demand being poor. Titanium dioxide enterprises face increased shipment pressure due to high competition, resulting in prices remaining low.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. Current low transaction prices are around 2060 CNY/ton (approx. 290.60 USD/ton), while high-priced shipments face significant pressure.

Titanium Slag: The</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2129.95</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/31/2024_10_31-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.95/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/31/2024_10_31-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.95/</id>
    <published>2024-10-31T09:20:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:51:09.675Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The downstream market remains weak, providing insufficient support for the titanium ore market. Due to supply issues, domestic titanium ore prices are also quite chaotic.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-grade slag market remains sluggish, with chaotic pricing. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the market continues to operate weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Titanium tetrachloride market prices are quoted at 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 843.24-899.58 USD&#x2F;ton. In some regions, there are lower-priced transactions. Despite high costs and production pressure, the downstream market’s sluggishness drags down the titanium tetrachloride market, with prices temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around 4.2-4.3 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 590.19-604.22 USD&#x2F;ton. Production remains stable, but demand is still weak, making it difficult to balance production and sales, with prices remaining weakly stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2129.95, down by 1 from yesterday. Environmental inspection teams have been patrolling factories in the Panzhihua area, affecting production at titanium dioxide plants within the park, leading to a decline in operations. Recently, the market has been weak and stable, with chaotic execution prices. Market sentiment is largely pessimistic, and downstream purchasing remains cautious, with titanium dioxide prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The downstream market remains weak, providing insufficient support for the titanium ore market. Due to supply issues, domestic titanium ore prices are also quite chaotic.

Titanium Slag: The high-grade slag market remains sluggish, with chaotic pricing.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.45</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/30/2024_10_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.45/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/30/2024_10_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.45/</id>
    <published>2024-10-30T07:39:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-30T07:40:15.667Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The downstream titanium dioxide market is sluggish, with resistance to titanium ore prices and a strong sentiment for price-cutting. Environmental inspections in the Panxi and Shandong areas have tightened titanium ore supply, leading prices to temporarily stabilize. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The cost pressure for high titanium slag is significant, with many companies operating at a loss and low market activity. Northern enterprises have not tendered this month. The high slag market has low production, and there is an oversupply, leading to continuous market weakness. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,437 and $9,000 per ton, with lower prices in some regions. High production costs and downstream market sluggishness are creating pressure, keeping market prices temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around $5,961 to $6,043 per ton. After a decline, magnesium ingot prices have stabilized, slightly alleviating costs, but companies are still operating at a loss, leading to weak price stability. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2131.45, unchanged from yesterday. This month, major enterprises offer a discount of $28 per ton to distributors fulfilling task volumes, with only a few companies making minor price adjustments, while others maintain stable prices. This week, environmental groups inspected factories in the Panzhihua area, limiting production and reducing titanium dioxide output. Due to weak demand and low market purchasing sentiment, there is a strong wait-and-see attitude among enterprises, resulting in chaotic market prices, maintained on a case-by-case basis. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The downstream titanium dioxide market is sluggish, with resistance to titanium ore prices and a strong sentiment for price-cutting. Environmental inspections in the Panxi and Shandong areas have tightened titanium ore supply, leading prices to temporar</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.15</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/29/2024_10_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.15/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/29/2024_10_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.15/</id>
    <published>2024-10-29T01:22:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-29T01:23:07.991Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains tight in supply, while the downstream market is overall sluggish. There is significant cost pressure, and market prices are rather chaotic. High-quality imported titanium ore has decreased this year, putting pressure on prices, which remain temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The cost pressure for high titanium slag is substantial, leading to losses for many companies. The market has low operating rates, with northern companies not tendering this month. The high-slag market has low production levels, resulting in an oversupply and continued weak market conditions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,437 and $8,997 per ton. In some regions, transactions occur at lower prices. The market remains stable but has a subdued trading atmosphere, with some companies maintaining production cuts. Prices are temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is approximately $5,963 to $6,046 per ton. After a decline, magnesium ingot prices are stable, slightly easing sponge titanium costs. However, companies are still operating at a loss, and prices are weakly stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2131.15, down by 1 from the previous working day. Demand is sluggish, and companies face significant pressure to sell. Some companies have slightly reduced prices for new orders, keeping the titanium dioxide market in a weak state.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains tight in supply, while the downstream market is overall sluggish. There is significant cost pressure, and market prices are rather chaotic. High-quality imported titanium ore has decreased this year, putting pressure on p</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2132.27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/26/2024_10_26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/26/2024_10_26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/</id>
    <published>2024-10-26T05:22:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-29T01:23:07.991Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises suffering losses and low production activity. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, resulting in a chaotic market and unstable high-titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $843.49 and $899.47 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, with significant fluctuations recently. Enterprises are cautious in raw material procurement, and the downstream market is experiencing reduced production, causing pressure on the market and stabilizing prices for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium products is around $5,902.39 to $6,042.20 USD per ton. Sponge titanium enterprises are still under inventory pressure, and overall downstream demand remains weak, leading to a temporarily weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2132.27, down by 2 from yesterday. Market demand continues to be weak, and competition is intense, with many waiting for price updates from leading enterprises. The titanium dioxide price is maintained on a per-order negotiation basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.

Titanium Slag: The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises su</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-18 to 2024-10-25</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-18-to-2024-10-25/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-18-to-2024-10-25/</id>
    <published>2024-10-25T03:47:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-25T03:47:43.349Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is relatively stable, with prices for current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Domestic downstream markets are weak, leading to increased pressure on enterprises to sell their stock. Additionally, environmental inspections and mining permit issues have tightened the supply of titanium ore, contributing to high raw material costs.</li><li>Exports of titanium dioxide remain strong, supporting high production levels despite domestic market challenges.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak. Enterprises face significant inventory pressure due to sluggish domestic demand, and there is cautious purchasing behavior among buyers.</li><li>Despite high production costs, export markets are providing some support, allowing for high operational rates among manufacturers.</li><li>Some top manufacturers may offer discounts to distributors to stimulate demand, and there may be price adjustments by other producers in the future.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Due to weak downstream demand, titanium dioxide prices are expected to remain stable with a slight weakness.</li><li>The market for titanium dioxide pigments will likely continue to be weak due to ongoing demand softness.</li><li>The imbalance in the supply and demand of sponge titanium will keep prices weak.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is relatively stable, with prices for current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.
 * Domestic downstream markets </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2132.27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/2024_10_25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/2024_10_25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/</id>
    <published>2024-10-25T03:44:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-25T03:47:43.345Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises suffering losses and low production activity. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, resulting in a chaotic market and unstable high-titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $843.49 and $899.47 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, with significant fluctuations recently. Enterprises are cautious in raw material procurement, and the downstream market is experiencing reduced production, causing pressure on the market and stabilizing prices for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium products is around $5,902.39 to $6,042.20 USD per ton. Sponge titanium enterprises are still under inventory pressure, and overall downstream demand remains weak, leading to a temporarily weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2132.27, down by 2 from yesterday. Market demand continues to be weak, and competition is intense, with many waiting for price updates from leading enterprises. The titanium dioxide price is maintained on a per-order negotiation basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.

Titanium Slag: The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises su</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2133.77</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/</id>
    <published>2024-10-24T09:06:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-24T09:06:36.498Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,436 and $8,998 per ton, with some low-price transactions in certain regions. The price of liquid chlorine has fluctuated significantly today, causing enterprises to be cautious with raw material procurement. The downstream market is also experiencing a decline in activity, putting pressure on the titanium tetrachloride market, though prices remain stable for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The market price for grade one sponge titanium is approximately $5,962 to $6,043 per ton. Inventory pressure remains high, and competition in the market is intense, putting pressure on enterprises to sell their products.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2133.77, which is a slight decrease of 1 from yesterday. Market demand is weak, leading to significant sales pressure and inventory challenges for manufacturers. According to market sources, leading companies might implement discount policies, and there have been minor price reductions for some new orders recently, indicating a weak titanium dioxide market.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable hi</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.67</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/</id>
    <published>2024-10-23T06:52:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-23T06:53:03.742Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $844.31-$900.36 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have seen lower prices, but the market has low operating rates. High costs of raw materials exert pressure on companies, and the market price remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $5,909.92-$6,051.40 USD&#x2F;ton. The inventory pressure remains high, and market competition is intense, creating pressure on companies to sell.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current titanium dioxide price index is 2134.67, a decrease of 4 from the previous day. New orders are not performing well, leading to increased inventory for some manufacturers. With high raw material costs, small and medium-sized manufacturers face significant production pressure. The market remains cautious, with prices weakly stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-11 to 2024-10-18</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/</id>
    <published>2024-10-18T02:11:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T02:16:50.899Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Demand remains lackluster, resulting in large inventory pressures on manufacturers. Environmental regulations and equipment maintenance have led to reduced production in several regions, including Southwest China, East China, and Shandong.</li><li>Despite high raw material costs, manufacturers face significant cost pressures. However, due to the weak domestic demand and the imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil on Chinese titanium dioxide, there is considerable pressure on export prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium dioxide pigments is also under pressure, with several companies reducing prices to stimulate demand. The market remains subdued, with transactions being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li><li>The imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil has added to the challenges faced by Chinese manufacturers. Duties include $578 per ton for LB Group and $654 per ton for Anhui Jin Xing, among others.</li><li>Domestic trade continues to be sluggish, and manufacturers are struggling to balance production and sales, with operating rates hovering around 80%.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Downstream demand is expected to remain weak, leading to continued pressure on titanium dioxide prices.</li><li>Manufacturers are likely to maintain reduced production levels due to environmental and market pressures.</li><li>Export challenges, due to international trade measures, will continue to impact the market, requiring strategic adjustments by manufacturers.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.
 * Demand remains lackluster, resulti</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
