<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2021-09-09T07:31:35.823Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chlorine supply and logistics affect Tronox production</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/09/09/Chlorine-supply-and-logistics-affect-Tronox-production/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/09/09/Chlorine-supply-and-logistics-affect-Tronox-production/</id>
    <published>2021-09-09T07:19:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-09T07:31:35.823Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tronox co-CEOs John Romano and Jean François Turgeon told analysts on the Tronox second quarter earnings conference call that in the second quarter, Tronox encountered chlorine availability restrictions and these issues are expected to also affect the company’s current third quarter titanium White powder business.<br>In addition to the chlorine issue, continued global supply and logistics restrictions that limit the availability of ships and containers will affect Tronox’s TiO2 business in the third quarter. The company’s executives said that due to tight logistics, sales in the third quarter are currently expected to drop by 5-10% from the record level in the second quarter. They said that although Tronox had expected improvements earlier in 2021, it now believes that the problem will continue until the end of the year.<br>In addition, in South Africa, the recent social unrest and riots may cause port disruptions, thereby delaying the transportation of Tronox’s raw materials.<br>At the same time, Tronox said that demand for its titanium dioxide remains strong. These executives said that despite the slowdown in demand growth in China, “we have not seen a weakening in demand at all.”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Tronox co-CEOs John Romano and Jean François Turgeon told analysts on the Tronox second quarter earnings conference call that in the second quarter, Tronox encountered chlorine availability restrictions and these issues are expected to also affect the company’s current third quarter titanium White powder business.&lt;br&gt;In addition to the chlorine issue, continued global supply and logistics restrictions that limit the availability of ships and containers will affect Tronox’s TiO2 business in the third quarter. The company’s executives said that due to tight logistics, sales in the third quarter are currently expected to drop by 5-10% from the record level in the second quarter. They said that although Tronox had expected improvements earlier in 2021, it now believes that the problem will continue until the end of the year.&lt;br&gt;In addition, in South Africa, the recent social unrest and riots may cause port disruptions, thereby delaying the transportation of Tronox’s raw materials.&lt;br&gt;At the same time, Tronox said that demand for its titanium dioxide remains strong. These executives said that despite the slowdown in demand growth in China, “we have not seen a weakening in demand at all.”&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="Tronox" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Tronox/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 pigment dispersions for dip coating applications by means of electrokinetic sonic amplitude</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/09/03/TiO2-pigment-dispersions-for-dip-coating-applications-by-means-of-electrokinetic-sonic-amplitude/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/09/03/TiO2-pigment-dispersions-for-dip-coating-applications-by-means-of-electrokinetic-sonic-amplitude/</id>
    <published>2021-09-03T02:03:46.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-09-06T07:52:23.926Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Daniel Moog</strong></p><p>The high-quality white pigment titanium dioxide has many applications. Coagulation or agglomeration of a TiO2 dispersion must be avoided at all costs, both in the manufacturing process and in the processing, e.g. by manufacturers of paints and coatings. This applies in particular to highly filled systems, such as pigment preparations and pigment pastes, where a high degree of particle stabilization is indispensable.</p><p>Purely electrostatic stabilization is not sufficient to stabilize highly concentrated pigment preparations and pigment pastes in such a way that they do not exhibit flocculation and segregation states during storage and processing.</p><p>For this reason, highly filled systems are stabilized either purely sterically or in a certain ratio of electrostatic and steric stabilization. Stabilization with electrostatic and steric components is referred to as electro-steric stabilization.</p><p>Illustration of the measurement setup<br><img src="https://analytik.news/en/grafik/papers/1131_1.jpg" alt="Fig.1: Illustration of the measurement setup"><br>Fig.1: Illustration of the measurement setup<br>(a) ESA probe, (b) measurement chamber,<br>(c) mechanical stirrer, (d) pipette,<br>(e) dispersion, (f) pH probe and<br>(g) conductivity probe. [Source:<br>“Electroacoustic Quantification of Surface<br>Bound Ligands in Functionalized Silica and<br>Iron Oxide Nanoparticles”, Whiley Publishers]<br>By adjusting the ratio of electrostatic to steric stabilization, it may be possible to adjust the viscosity properties of the products. To maintain structural viscosity properties, as is often required in the field of paints and coatings, electrostatic stabilization is often necessary. For viscosities that should be independent of the shear rate (Newtonian viscosity behavior), purely steric stabilization may be useful.</p><p>The electroacoustic ESA measuring technique used is used to record the stabilization process during the addition of additives to an aqueous TiO2 pigment preparation (Figure 1). The measured data show the level and type of stabilization as a function of the added additive concentration. By using the ESA method, additive concentrations can be determined which lead to defined electro-steric or steric stabilization ratios. These dispersion states, which are now known, can then be transferred to the formulation development or formulation optimization of a pigment preparation.</p><p>In summary, the following advantages result from the use of the ESA measuring technique for recording a stabilization process through the addition of additives:</p><ul><li>Assignment of quantitative stability states to the added additive quantities.</li><li>Exact adjustment of electro-steric or pure steric stabilization states.</li><li>Avoidance of additive excess by detection of the complete surface coverage with the surface affine additive groups.</li><li>Estimation of the polymer layer thickness applied to the particles by the electrical double layer.</li><li>Control of dispersion products after storage or in production.</li><li>Evaluation of the ESA raw data signal enables measurement and evaluation without knowledge of the physical substance data. With knowledge of physical substance data, an exact derivation of the zeta potential from the ESA raw data signal is possible.</li></ul><h2 id="Materials-measurement-technology-and-devices"><a href="#Materials-measurement-technology-and-devices" class="headerlink" title="Materials, measurement technology and devices"></a>Materials, measurement technology and devices</h2><p>The materials used for the measurements and the measuring technique are listed below. The measurements were carried out by the company Pulveranalyse Dipl.-Ing. Daniel Moog, a contract laboratory specializing in dispersion analysis. Two titanium dioxide pigment grades were tested which are to be used in highly concentrated pigment preparations as a pre- product in the sector of water-based dip coating products.</p><h2 id="Materials"><a href="#Materials" class="headerlink" title="Materials:"></a>Materials:</h2><p>Aqueous TiO2 dispersion 10 % wt solids.<br>Solvent-free wetting and dispersing additive for waterborne coating applications, consisting of a copolymer with pigment affinity groups.</p><ul><li>TiO2-Pigment SP-Rutile for paints and coatings <a href="https://tinoxchem.com/product/tinox-titanium-dioxide-rutile-r-2160/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TINOX R-2160</a></li><li>TiO2-Pigment SP Rutile for paints and coatings <a href="https://tinoxchem.com/product/tinox-titanium-dioxide-rutile-r-2140/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TINOX R-2140</a><h2 id="Measurement"><a href="#Measurement" class="headerlink" title="Measurement:"></a>Measurement:</h2>ESA measuring system with high sensitive probe with 500 kHz measuring frequency.<br>50 ml Teflon measuring cell, pH sensor, conductivity and temperature sensor, adjustable stirring system to prevent sedimentation during measurement.<br>Software for data recording.<h2 id="Devices"><a href="#Devices" class="headerlink" title="Devices:"></a>Devices:</h2>Ultraturrax T18 for dispersion with tool S18 N-19G</li></ul><h2 id="Results-and-discussion"><a href="#Results-and-discussion" class="headerlink" title="Results and discussion"></a>Results and discussion</h2><p>By measuring the electrokinetic sonic amplitude, the processes during the stabilization of the TiO2 grades in aqueous dispersion can be accurately recorded.</p><p>The results show that the additive used in the concentration of (4-7) % recommended by the additive manufacturer leads to electro-steric mixing stabilization for both TiO2 pigments (Figure 2 and 3). The wetting and coating of the TiO2 pigment surfaces with the additive polymer leads to a decrease in the zeta potential, which is also a measure of the thickness of the applied polymer layer. The ratio of electrostatic to steric stabilization can be detected and thus precisely adjusted.</p><p>zeta potential of TINOX R-2160 TiO2 pigment<br>Fig.2: Recording of the decrease of the zeta potential of TINOX R-2160 TiO2 pigment during additive addition. The measurement<br>was carried out under strong stirring, which prevents sedimentation and ensures homogeneous mixing.<br><img src="https://analytik.news/en/grafik/papers/1131_2.jpg" alt="Recording of the decrease of the zeta potential of TINOX R-2160 TiO2 pigment during additive addition"></p><p>zeta potential of TINOX R-2140 TiO2 pigment<br>Fig.3: Recording of the decrease of the zeta potential of TINOX R-2140 TiO2 pigment during additive addition. The measurement<br>was carried out under strong stirring, which prevents sedimentation and ensures homogeneous mixing.<br><img src="https://analytik.news/en/grafik/papers/1131_3.jpg" alt="Recording of the decrease of the zeta potential of TINOX R-2140 TiO2 pigment during additive addition."></p><p>In the concentrations of (4-7)% on TiO2 recommended by the additive manufacturer, electrostatic mixing stabilization occurs for both pigment grades, with higher electrostatic contents remaining for TINOX R-2140 at the same additive concentration. The results show that the recommended additive concentrations of the additive manufacturers are good guidelines, but that the surface chemistry of the titanium dioxide pigments can vary so much due to post-treatment processes and manufacturing methods that for many TiO2-pigment grades a precise adjustment of the formulation is necessary. This is especially true when highly filled systems are manufactured at the maximum possible concentration, as is the case with pigment formulations and pigment pastes.<br>Conclusion<br>The ESA technique used in the present experiments has been elaborated in a particular way for different applications.</p><p>In the technical production process, dispersions are usually highly concentrated, turbid, colored or tempered. They are often electrostatically influenced by added additive formulations. Often the sedimentation of the mixture in the reactor must be prevented by powerful agitators. Stability analysis by means of electrokinetic sonic amplitude includes all parameters. Thus, the data of the samples analyzed in highly concentrated form can be directly transferred to the electrokinetic properties of the dispersed particles in the raw material or in the finished product.</p><p>By controlled recording of the stabilization process, it was possible to develop a stable semi-finished product with TINOX R-2140 as a pigment preparation with 78% TiO2 for aqueous dip coating applications, which showed no tendency to agglomeration even during subsequent strong dilution processes. The stabilization process could be deciphered a bit further and the dispersion states can be checked by means of ESA technology for process and quality control (see illustration Figure 4).</p><p>metrological recording of stabilization prozess<br>Fig.4: Illustration of the metrological recording of the stabilization process.<br><img src="https://analytik.news/en/grafik/papers/1131_4.jpg" alt="Illustration of the metrological recording of the stabilization process."></p><p>Information on the measurement method used<br>From a scientific point of view, the use of the ESA measurement technique is a method for direct quantification of accessible hydroxide groups on the surface of particles and a profound way for surface quantification of different ligands. While electrophoretic methods for zeta potential surface characterization for technical applications are limited by too high dilutions, sedimentation processes, irregular particle shape or inaccessible physical substance data, the ESA method is a complementary measurement technique for analysis in technical applications.</p><p>The ESA method for characterizing the charge stability of particles in a dispersion is an electroacoustic measurement technique.</p><p>An oscillating voltage is applied to a suspension, dispersion or emulsion, which is generated by an alternating current source. Charged particles in the dispersion oscillate at the frequency of the externally applied electric field. One or more frequencies can be applied. The oscillation of the particles at these frequencies generates sonic waves. The amplitudes of these sonic waves are measured as electrokinetic sonic amplitude (ESA). This ESA signal is proportional to the dynamic mobility of the particles and this in turn is proportional to the zeta potential of the particles present in the dispersion. A prerequisite for the use of this effect is a certain density difference between dispersion medium and particle. To generate evaluable signals, this density difference must be at least 0.2 g/cm3.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel Moog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high-quality white pigment titanium dioxide has many applications. Coagulation or agglomeration of a TiO2 dispersion must be avoided at all costs, both in the manufacturing process and in the processing, e.g. by manufacturers of paints and coatings. This applies in particular to highly filled systems, such as pigment preparations and pigment pastes, where a high degree of particle stabilization is indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Technical" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Technical/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tinox TiO2 r-2140" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tinox-TiO2-r-2140/"/>
    
      <category term="tinox Tio2 r-2160" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tinox-Tio2-r-2160/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The global supply of tio2 is getting worse.</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/08/10/The-global-supply-of-tio2-is-getting-worse/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/08/10/The-global-supply-of-tio2-is-getting-worse/</id>
    <published>2021-08-10T09:24:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T08:27:11.070Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the force majeure announcement of RBM, the market of CP grades TiO2 was expected to raise in 3rd and 4th quarter. But after the mid of July, the Wait-and-see sentiment in the market since May finally leads to a price fallback in Asia, and some Chinese manufacturers had to reduce their price to continues their production.</p><p>Was the uptrend turning around? We all asked the same question.</p><p>In the late of July, the power supply limitation in south China caused a sudden rasie of the sulphate acid price, which was totally unexpected.<br>Usually, in the wet season, the power supply is abundant, and the power cost is the lowest of whole year.<br>But this year, the price of sulphate acid raised more than 20% in ten days, till now, the price is still going up without any signs of stop.<br>Even the sulphate acid price cost only takes 15% of total cost of SP tio2, but this sudden rise of the acid definitely is adding fuel to the fire.  </p><p><strong>After several days of wondering, today, the SP grades gaint LomonBillions finally announced the new price increase of 200USD/MT.</strong></p><p>But as to the SP tio2 is not the mainstream of the global market yet, it is hard to say worse if we only take the acid price increase into account. Followings are the real things causing a headque to some users.</p><p><a href="https://www.dailysabah.com/world/africa/south-african-power-plant-explodes-only-a-week-after-launch?gallery_image=undefined#big" target="_blank" rel="noopener">South African power plant explodes only a week after launch</a></p><p><a href="https://www.icis.com/explore/resources/news/2021/07/29/10668554/tronox-mulls-chlorine-projects-expects-logistics-issues-to-last-through-h2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tronox mulls chlorine projects, expects logistics issues to last through H2</a></p><p><a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/business/india-business/trade-hit-as-cost-of-freight-from-china-surges-200/articleshow/85083086.cms" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Trade hit as cost of freight from China surges 200%</a></p><p>Overall, the main aspects making things worse.</p><ol><li>The raw material supply. The power, the acid, the slag, the chlorine.</li><li>The shipment. The shortage of containers and the prejudice against heavy goods from shipping company also makes the chemical suppliers even harder to get their material loaded on board. Which is extending the supplying period, and strength the tight supply sistuation.</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;After the force majeure announcement of RBM, the market of CP grades TiO2 was expected to raise in 3rd and 4th quarter. But after the mid of July, the Wait-and-see sentiment in the market since May finally leads to a price fallback in Asia, and some Chinese manufacturers had to reduce their price to continues their production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was the uptrend turning around? We all asked the same question.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="Tronox" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Tronox/"/>
    
      <category term="Richards Bay Minerals" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Richards-Bay-Minerals/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market analysis weekly updates 1st week July 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/07/02/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-1st-week-July-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/07/02/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-1st-week-July-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-07-02T09:52:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T11:03:32.875Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Keyword-RBM"><a href="#Keyword-RBM" class="headerlink" title="Keyword: RBM"></a>Keyword: RBM</h2><p>This week, RBM certainly got every attention in tio2 market, like throwing a stone into a calm lake.</p><p><a href="https://www.riotinto.com/news/releases/2021/Rio-Tinto-declares-force-majeure-at-Richards-Bay-Minerals" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rio Tinto declares force majeure at Richards Bay Minerals</a>.</p><h2 id="Why-RBM-is-so-important-to-TiO2-industry"><a href="#Why-RBM-is-so-important-to-TiO2-industry" class="headerlink" title="Why RBM is so important to TiO2 industry?"></a>Why RBM is so important to TiO2 industry?</h2><p>Located on the eastern shores of South Africa, 180 km north of Durban, Richards Bay Minerals (RBM) produces approximately 2.0 million metric tonnes of product annually making RBM a leading producer of titania slag, high purity pig iron, rutile and zircon.<br>Heavy minerals are extracted from the nearby dunes by dredging and concentration on a floating gravity separation plant, followed by separation of the ilmenite, rutile and zircon at the mineral separation plant located at the smelter site. The ilmenite is processed through an oxidizing roast followed by magnetic separation and is then partially reduced to an 85 per cent TiO2 slag in one of four six-in-line a.c. electric arc furnaces. The slag is milled and then classified into two<br>product sizes suitable as a raw material for both the sulphate and chloride pigment processes. The high quality iron produced during the reduction process is further processed to produce various grades of low-manganese iron.<br>Around 95 per cent of the products are exported, yielding a world market share of about 25 per cent of titania slag, rutile, high quality pig iron, and zircon.<br>See more details at <a href="https://www.saimm.co.za/Conferences/Pyro2006/181_RBM.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Heavy Mineral Processing at Richards Bay Minerals</a>.</p><h2 id="The-price-of-tio2-will-surge-again"><a href="#The-price-of-tio2-will-surge-again" class="headerlink" title="The price of tio2 will surge again?"></a>The price of tio2 will surge again?</h2><p>Even now, the RBM throwed a huge stone into the calm lake. But still we are conservative to the price trend.</p><h3 id="Firstly-the-market-continues-to-wait-and-see"><a href="#Firstly-the-market-continues-to-wait-and-see" class="headerlink" title="Firstly, the market continues to wait and see."></a>Firstly, the market continues to wait and see.</h3><p>Now, the price is at a historial high level. After the stock cleaning, the distributors are not yet planing to make new stocks. And to the tio2 manufactures, after the fulfilling of first half orders, now only few obtained orders at hand. Some tio2 manufactures even got into panic and start to lower the price for orders. But their cost is not low, so they choose to make special offers to certain buyers. Some analysists refers that it is a centralized-cleaning of inferior products produced in the previous production.</p><h3 id="Secondly-RBM’s-issue-needs-time-to-pass-the-wave"><a href="#Secondly-RBM’s-issue-needs-time-to-pass-the-wave" class="headerlink" title="Secondly, RBM’s issue needs time to pass the wave."></a>Secondly, RBM’s issue needs time to pass the wave.</h3><p>Most of RBM raw is in high grade supplied to chloride production. And firstly, the impact will on the international CP grade producers. According to reliable source, the Kronos’ long term supply contract is one of the first contracts to be suspended.</p><h3 id="Last-by-not-least-the-trend-may-shows-two-level-differentiation-in-shorterm"><a href="#Last-by-not-least-the-trend-may-shows-two-level-differentiation-in-shorterm" class="headerlink" title="Last by not least, the trend may shows two-level differentiation in shorterm."></a>Last by not least, the trend may shows two-level differentiation in shorterm.</h3><p>To the SP suppliers from China, the shortage of oredrs is still the fact to small and medium tio2 manufacturers. Those who can not take the pressure may turned to adjust their price strategy.<br>But under the impact of RBM, the CP grade tio2 manufactures has no doubt will increase their price to cease the impacts in fourth quarter. And gradually, this impact will be passed to SP tio2 manufactures also.</p><h2 id="Any-forecasts-or-suggests"><a href="#Any-forecasts-or-suggests" class="headerlink" title="Any forecasts or suggests?"></a>Any forecasts or suggests?</h2><p>To our estimation, the general price of SP grades may slightly drop in shorterm, but not much, and the second half of 2021, it is still on a solid strong ground.<br>To CP grades, the big players may announce a new round of price increase in the middle of August 2021.<br>Suggestion? Purchase in needs, make no stocks.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Keyword-RBM&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Keyword-RBM&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Keyword: RBM&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Keyword: RBM&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week, RBM certainly got every attention in tio2 market, like throwing a stone into a calm lake.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="weekly updates" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/"/>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="Richards Bay Minerals" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Richards-Bay-Minerals/"/>
    
      <category term="RBM" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/RBM/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Rio Tinto declares force majeure at Richards Bay Minerals</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/07/01/Rio-Tinto-declares-force-majeure-at-Richards-Bay-Minerals/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/07/01/Rio-Tinto-declares-force-majeure-at-Richards-Bay-Minerals/</id>
    <published>2021-07-01T01:11:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-07-01T07:01:26.076Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>According to Businesswire in London, Rio Tinto has declared force majeure on customer contracts at Richards Bay Minerals (RBM) in South Africa due to an escalation in the security situation at the operations. This has led to the decision to cease operations until the safety and security position improves.</p><p>Rio Tinto chief executive Minerals, Sinead Kaufman, said: “The safety of our people is our top priority.We continue to offer our full support to the investigating authorities and I would like to acknowledge the ongoing support of the regional and national governments and South African Police Service as we work together to ensure that we can safely resume operations.”</p><p>All mining and smelting operations at RBM have been halted until further notice. The Zulti South project has remained on full suspension since the security and community issues in 2019.</p><p>This announcement is authorised for release to the market by Steve Allen, Rio Tinto’s Group Company Secretary.<br><a href="https://www.news24.com/fin24/companies/its-impossible-to-run-our-business-rio-tinto-shuts-kzn-operation-amid-bloodshed-20210630" target="_blank" rel="noopener">‘It’s impossible to run our business’: Rio Tinto shuts KZN operation amid bloodshed</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;According to Businesswire in London, Rio Tinto has declared force majeure on customer contracts at Richards Bay Minerals (RBM) in South Africa due to an escalation in the security situation at the operations. This has led to the decision to cease operations until the safety and security position improves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rio Tinto chief executive Minerals, Sinead Kaufman, said: “The safety of our people is our top priority.We continue to offer our full support to the investigating authorities and I would like to acknowledge the ongoing support of the regional and national governments and South African Police Service as we work together to ensure that we can safely resume operations.”&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Global titanium dioxide market outlook for the better</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/23/Global-titanium-dioxide-market-outlook-for-the-better/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/23/Global-titanium-dioxide-market-outlook-for-the-better/</id>
    <published>2021-06-23T06:28:38.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-23T06:55:45.809Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, a number of titanium dioxide manufacturers said that the global demand for titanium dioxide is strong and the supply is tight, and the market price may continue to rise. Major producers Chemours, Venator, Tronox and Kronos reported positive results in the first quarter and expect their performance to continue to grow for the rest of this year.</p><h3 id="Increase-in-sales-and-decrease-in-inventory"><a href="#Increase-in-sales-and-decrease-in-inventory" class="headerlink" title="Increase in sales and decrease in inventory"></a>Increase in sales and decrease in inventory</h3><p>“Chemours’ sales in the first quarter increased by 2% compared to the fourth quarter of last year. The demand for coatings, plastics and laminates in Chemours’ titanium technology business continued to increase in the second quarter.” Chemours President and CEO Mark P. Vergnano stated on the May 4 earnings conference call, “In the first half of this year, new houses and renovations in various countries are driving the rapid growth of demand for architectural coatings. Since 2020, the demand for DIY products has maintained a strong momentum.”<br>John D. Romano from Tronox said that the sales volume of titanium dioxide in the first quarter increased by 15% compared with the fourth quarter of last year. Demand in various regions was strong, but the largest growth was in Europe and the Asia-Pacific region. Simon Turner, chief executive officer of Venator, also said that market demand has unexpectedly grown strongly. All industries and regions have strong demand for functional titanium dioxide. The demand for specialty titanium dioxide products has shown a good momentum of recovery, mainly in the textile and automotive industries. Venator’s titanium dioxide sales volume has continuously increased by 14%. Compared with the fourth quarter of 2020, the device utilization rate has increased, and the inventory remains tight throughout the first quarter.</p><h3 id="Demand-is-back-on-track"><a href="#Demand-is-back-on-track" class="headerlink" title="Demand is back on track"></a>Demand is back on track</h3><p>The overall demand for titanium dioxide has basically returned to the level before the epidemic. The Kronos report shows that sales in the first quarter of this year were 141,000 tons, an increase of 4% from 136,000 tons in the same period last year, and an increase of 14% from 124,000 tons in the second quarter of 2020. The total sales volume in the third quarter of last year was 136,000 tons and the fourth quarter was 135,000 tons. Other manufacturers did not report sales, but their year-on-year sales growth data showed the same trend. Chemours’ titanium dioxide sales in the first quarter of this year increased by 16% year-on-year, while the first quarter of 2020 increased by 19% year-on-year, and the second quarter of 2020 decreased by 9% year-on-year. Tronox’s sales in the first quarter of this year increased by 16% year-on-year, the first quarter of last year sales increased by 6% year-on-year, and the second quarter fell by 27% year-on-year. Venators’ sales volume of Titanium Dioxide in the first quarter of this year was down 1% year-on-year, and in the second quarter of 2020, it was down 21% year-on-year.<br>Chemours Chief Operating Officer Mark Newman said: “The recovery in demand for titanium dioxide started when DIY products were launched in the second quarter of last year. Architectural coatings accounted for most of the company’s titanium dioxide business, and the rest was laminate and plastics business. Then there is the construction industry demand, especially the demand for new housing, which is growing rapidly. Based on the current development trend, sales are expected to increase in the next three quarters.”</p><h3 id="Supply-tends-to-be-tight"><a href="#Supply-tends-to-be-tight" class="headerlink" title="Supply tends to be tight"></a>Supply tends to be tight</h3><p>After the collapse of demand in the second quarter of last year, titanium dioxide producers around the world have drastically reduced their production, and then the slow recovery of production has resulted in a tight supply situation. Newman said: “Judging from the operation of our factory in March and April, our production in the second quarter will be higher than that in the first quarter. In addition, in terms of the supply of each factory, the supply of raw materials is restricted, but these are all It’s only a temporary impact.”  Venator also expressed a similar view.<br>Although the price of titanium dioxide is rising in the first quarter of this year, it has not fully recovered. At the same time, production costs are also increasing. Hassan Ahmed, an analyst at Alembic Global Advisors, an American investment research company, predicts that the price of titanium dioxide will continue to push up this year. He pointed out in a recent research report: “The current titanium dioxide price is only slightly higher than the 16-year average level and the 2008-2009 crisis period, so the upward potential is greater.” The price of ilmentile continues to rise, which may further push the price of titanium dioxide increasing.<br>Turner pointed out that China’s exports remained stable in the first quarter of this year, and the main export markets were other Asian countries and emerging markets. He said: “Due to the strong local demand for titanium dioxide in China, coupled with transportation restrictions, China’s exports to Europe and North America will fall, which will make customers more hope that we can provide reliable supplies.” Due to rising raw material and transportation costs, Chinese titanium dioxide producers are also continuously increasing their sales prices, thereby continuing to narrow the arbitrage space.<br>According to relevant data, Chemours, Venator, Tronox and Kronox together account for 40% of the global titanium dioxide production capacity, with a total global production capacity of 8.4 million tons/year in 2020. Chemours has the largest production capacity, about 1.2 million tons/year; followed by Tronox with 1 million tons/year;  Venator and Kronox both have 500,000 tons/year. In the past 10 years, China’s titanium dioxide production capacity has surged, from 2.1 million tons/year in 2011 to 3.7 million tons/year in 2020, accounting for 44% of the world’s total production capacity. During the same period, China’s annual net exports increased from 41,000 tons to 69,000 tons.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Recently, a number of titanium dioxide manufacturers said that the global demand for titanium dioxide is strong and the supply is tight, and the market price may continue to rise. Major producers Chemours, Venator, Tronox and Kronos reported positive results in the first quarter and expect their performance to continue to grow for the rest of this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;Increase-in-sales-and-decrease-in-inventory&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Increase-in-sales-and-decrease-in-inventory&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Increase in sales and decrease in inventory&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Increase in sales and decrease in inventory&lt;/h3&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>China Containerized Freight Index reached a new record high</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/15/China-Containerized-Freight-Index-reached-a-new-record-high/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/15/China-Containerized-Freight-Index-reached-a-new-record-high/</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T07:54:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T08:24:47.352Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>China Containerized Freight Index knowns as CCFI, is an important index reflecting the shipping price.<br>On 11th June, the CCFI reached a new high to 2442.57 from 2373.77 in a 2.9% rise comparing with last period dated 4th June.</p><p>In which, the Europe serivces increased 4.6% ranked the first on the list. The top ten as following:</p><ol><li>Europe services, increased 4.6% to 4013.86.</li><li>Mediterranean services, increased 4.3% to 4797.74.</li><li>West East Africa services, increased 3.4% to 1620.66.</li><li>South Africa services &amp; South America services, increased 3.3% to 2104.9 &amp; 1984.9.</li><li>E/C America serivces, increased 1.8% to 1977.92.</li><li>W/C America services, increased 1.5% to 1643.48.</li><li>Japan serivces, increased 1.3% to 929.84.</li><li>Southeast Asia services, increased 1.1% to 1340.88.</li><li>Persian Gul/Red sea services, increased 0.7% to 2865.45.</li></ol><p>In the meanwhile, the the Shanghai Containerized Freight Index, known as SCFI, also reached a historical high to 3703.93, it was doubled since Dec.2020, in 6 monthes.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;China Containerized Freight Index knowns as CCFI, is an important index reflecting the shipping price.&lt;br&gt;On 11th June, the CCFI reached a new high to 2442.57 from 2373.77 in a 2.9% rise comparing with last period dated 4th June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In which, the Europe serivces increased 4.6% ranked the first on the list. The top ten as following:&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Freight" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Freight/"/>
    
      <category term="Shipment tight" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Shipment-tight/"/>
    
      <category term="CCFI" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/CCFI/"/>
    
      <category term="SCFI" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/SCFI/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>International rutile prices rose in the third quarter</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/11/International-rutile-prices-rose-in-the-third-quarter/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/11/International-rutile-prices-rose-in-the-third-quarter/</id>
    <published>2021-06-11T03:18:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T03:33:45.823Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the recovery in Europe and America, the demand for titanium raw materials by European and American companies is also recovering. It is understood that driven by the growth of demand in Europe and the United States, ILUKA’s rutile quotation in the third quarter rose from the previous US$1,495/ton to US$1,640/ton. In addition to ILUKA, some foreign companies have also raised the price of 95 rutile. At present, the international quotations of 95 rutiles are all above US$1,600/ton, and the supply exceeds demand. According to several rutile manufacturers, the current western downstream users are more active in purchasing rutile raw materials, and the spot supply of rutile is tight.</p><p>In May, ILUKA announced that it would suspend the production of rutile mines in Sierra Leone after November this year, which will cause the global supply of rutile to drop by more than 140,000 tons per year. At the same time, the safety accident at Rio Tinto’s South Africa plant has made the plant’s future stability of high-titanium slag supply uncertain. If the output of ILUKA rutile is reduced while Rio Tinto’s South Africa titanium slag plant also sees a decline in output, then the global supply of high-grade titanium-rich materials at the end of this year will not be optimistic.</p><p>Judging from the current situation, the market prices of high-titanium slag and rutile have been determined to rise slightly in the third quarter. If the supply situation of Rio Tinto’s South Africa plant does fluctuate at the end of this year, the global price of rutile and titanium slag may rise sharply again in the fourth quarter. Some industry insiders believe that the price of 95 rutile may exceed US$1,800/ton by then. According to relevant analysis, customers in the welding consumables industry may be the most affected in the short term. Because other industries such as the chloride process titanium dioxide plant can choose the raw materials of high-titanium slag, artificial rutile, and natural rutile, while the welding material industry relies heavily on natural rutile and is more difficult to replace with other products.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;With the recovery in Europe and America, the demand for titanium raw materials by European and American companies is also recovering. It is understood that driven by the growth of demand in Europe and the United States, ILUKA’s rutile quotation in the third quarter rose from the previous US$1,495/ton to US$1,640/ton. In addition to ILUKA, some foreign companies have also raised the price of 95 rutile. At present, the international quotations of 95 rutiles are all above US$1,600/ton, and the supply exceeds demand. According to several rutile manufacturers, the current western downstream users are more active in purchasing rutile raw materials, and the spot supply of rutile is tight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, ILUKA announced that it would suspend the production of rutile mines in Sierra Leone after November this year, which will cause the global supply of rutile to drop by more than 140,000 tons per year. At the same time, the safety accident at Rio Tinto’s South Africa plant has made the plant’s future stability of high-titanium slag supply uncertain. If the output of ILUKA rutile is reduced while Rio Tinto’s South Africa titanium slag plant also sees a decline in output, then the global supply of high-grade titanium-rich materials at the end of this year will not be optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="rutile tio2 prices" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/rutile-tio2-prices/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>LomonBillions announced price increase since 1st July 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/11/LomonBillions-announced-price-increase-since-1st-July-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/11/LomonBillions-announced-price-increase-since-1st-July-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-06-11T03:09:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T03:14:33.233Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LomonBillions announced price increase, since 1st July 2021, all grades of titanium dioxide(Sulfate process tio2, Chloride process tio2) price will increase 500yuan/mt based on last price offer.<br><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1702145804279699775&wfr=spider&for=pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lomon Baili raised prices for 6 consecutive times during the year</a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;LomonBillions announced price increase, since 1st July 2021, all grades of titanium dioxide(Sulfate process tio2, Chloride process tio2) price will increase 500yuan/mt based on last price offer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1702145804279699775&amp;wfr=spider&amp;for=pc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Lomon Baili raised prices for 6 consecutive times during the year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="LomonBillions" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/LomonBillions/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The high-titanium slag market enters a short period of stability</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/09/The-high-titanium-slag-market-enters-a-short-period-of-stability/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/09/The-high-titanium-slag-market-enters-a-short-period-of-stability/</id>
    <published>2021-06-09T05:59:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T06:26:57.975Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This month, the northern 90 titanium slag bidding price was 7,600 yuan/ton, an increase of 100 yuan/ton from last month. Since March, the price of 90 titanium slag has risen at a relatively large pace, mostly around 400 yuan/ton. The slowdown in the price increase this time indicates that the high-titanium slag market will enter a period of relatively stable prices in the future.</p><p>The reason why the price of high-titanium slag rose sharply in March and April was mainly due to the rapid increase in the price of ilmenite leading to rising costs. Recently, the northern high-titanium slag enterprises have gradually completed the establishment of ilmenite inventory, and the average ilmenite inventory is about 2-3 months. Therefore, the production cost of high-titanium slag in the north will be relatively stable in the future, and a single increase of 400 yuan/ton will temporarily bid farewell to the market. From a long-term trend, with the gradual resumption of production of western titanium dioxide companies, the demand for ilmenite in the West will also gradually increase, and the corresponding supply to the Chinese market will decrease. The recent discovery of a mutated new coronavirus in Vietnam has brought certain uncertainty to the future market trend. The Vietnamese market is my country’s main source of titanium slag raw materials. Although the supply has declined in recent years, it has maintained a relatively stable supply. In contrast, although ilmenite from Ukraine, Sri Lanka, Falkland Islands, and Norway appeared on the market some time ago, they cannot become a stable source. If the spread of the new coronavirus in Vietnam affects its export of ilmenite to my country, it may push up the price of domestic titanium chloride ore in the future. After the current inventory of ilmenite in the titanium slag plant is exhausted, the price of titanium slag may change again due to the cost of ilmenite.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This month, the northern 90 titanium slag bidding price was 7,600 yuan/ton, an increase of 100 yuan/ton from last month. Since March, the price of 90 titanium slag has risen at a relatively large pace, mostly around 400 yuan/ton. The slowdown in the price increase this time indicates that the high-titanium slag market will enter a period of relatively stable prices in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why the price of high-titanium slag rose sharply in March and April was mainly due to the rapid increase in the price of ilmenite leading to rising costs. Recently, the northern high-titanium slag enterprises have gradually completed the establishment of ilmenite inventory, and the average ilmenite inventory is about 2-3 months. Therefore, the production cost of high-titanium slag in the north will be relatively stable in the future, and a single increase of 400 yuan/ton will temporarily bid farewell to the market. From a long-term trend, with the gradual resumption of production of western titanium dioxide companies, the demand for ilmenite in the West will also gradually increase, and the corresponding supply to the Chinese market will decrease. The recent discovery of a mutated new coronavirus in Vietnam has brought certain uncertainty to the future market trend. The Vietnamese market is my country’s main source of titanium slag raw materials. Although the supply has declined in recent years, it has maintained a relatively stable supply. In contrast, although ilmenite from Ukraine, Sri Lanka, Falkland Islands, and Norway appeared on the market some time ago, they cannot become a stable source. If the spread of the new coronavirus in Vietnam affects its export of ilmenite to my country, it may push up the price of domestic titanium chloride ore in the future. After the current inventory of ilmenite in the titanium slag plant is exhausted, the price of titanium slag may change again due to the cost of ilmenite.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="high titanium slag" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/high-titanium-slag/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market analysis weekly updates, 1st week of June, 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/04/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-1st-week-of-June-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/04/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-1st-week-of-June-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-06-04T10:01:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T10:45:04.882Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Keyword-Flat"><a href="#Keyword-Flat" class="headerlink" title="Keyword: Flat"></a>Keyword: Flat</h2><p>Still the market is quiet this week, nobody is making noise at this point of time.</p><p>The demands is still at a low level, but the turning point of the crazy trend still not show up.</p><h2 id="Why"><a href="#Why" class="headerlink" title="Why?"></a>Why?</h2><ol><li><em>The expectation of the price increase in July is strong.</em> In april and last month, Kronos, Venator and Tronox announced their plan to increase the price in July. So will you chooice to decease the price for orders in June, if you are the manfuacture? I beg you will not.<br>If you will, you may choice to do it in May or early June, and increase it back in the late of June or the early July. Apparently, nobody was doing so.</li><li><em>The output is in a temporarily ups and down after a full load running of 6 months</em> Today, <a href="https://pangang-titanium.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pangang group</a>s’ facility in Panzhihua area discontinued production due to accident. Meanwhile, in Guangxi and Guangdong province, the power is limited supply, and meets only half the needs of normal. Surprisingly, the Anatase supply is getting more tight than expected. As we all know, in the past, more and more users are shitfing to the Rutile grades due to its outstanding performance comparing with Anatase. But now, we found that, many users are shifting back to Anatase due the crazy price increase of Rutile, to whom a little compromise in quality is not a serious issue.  But more importantly, most of the producers of Anatase already shift their production line to Rutile and not willing to shit it back yet. Only handful producers in China located in Guangxi, Guizhou and Sichuan. As a result , now the FOB price of anatase grade of tio2, is surpassing 3000USD/MT already.</li><li><em>The futures players is ready to start a new game.</em> Last month, most of the stocks in the market got cleaned, which means the futures player is also reloaded and wait only for a signal, which we believe could appear in late of June, to involve again.</li></ol><p>So in the end, we make bold estimation that there is 60% chance of the price going up, 29% chance of the price keeping still, and only 1% chance to turning down.  This 1% is only for showing some respect to probability.</p><p>So what is your estimated FOB Chian price in July? Please feel free to comment.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Keyword-Flat&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Keyword-Flat&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Keyword: Flat&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Keyword: Flat&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still the market is quiet this week, nobody is making noise at this point of time.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="weekly updates" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/"/>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>LomonBillions may invest 400Million CNY to build new factory in Gansu</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/LomonBillions-may-invest-400Million-CNY-to-build-new-factory-in-Gansu/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/LomonBillions-may-invest-400Million-CNY-to-build-new-factory-in-Gansu/</id>
    <published>2021-06-03T09:42:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-03T09:48:30.258Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, LomonBillions announced, according to the company’s business and strategic development needs, in order to further increase the company’s market share and strengthen the company’s competitiveness, the wholly-owned subsidiary Longbai sichuan titanium limited is planning to invest 400MillionCNY in JinCang City, Gansu Province, China, to build new factory, which will be named Gansu Billions Chemical Co ltd (Subject to the final actual name).</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Recently, LomonBillions announced, according to the company’s business and strategic development needs, in order to further increase the company’s market share and strengthen the company’s competitiveness, the wholly-owned subsidiary Longbai sichuan titanium limited is planning to invest 400MillionCNY in JinCang City, Gansu Province, China, to build new factory, which will be named Gansu Billions Chemical Co ltd (Subject to the final actual name).&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="TiO2" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tronox announced the price increase in asia pacific</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/Tronox-announced-the-price-increase-in-asia-pacific/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/Tronox-announced-the-price-increase-in-asia-pacific/</id>
    <published>2021-06-03T09:34:26.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-03T09:40:19.405Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tronox announced, since 1st July 2021, all TIONA TiO2 products sold to asia pacific price will increase 225USD/MT.<br>Tronox said, now the TiO2 is still in strong demands, and the shipping sistuation is still tight and challenging. The 60days deliverying policy is still live.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Tronox announced, since 1st July 2021, all TIONA TiO2 products sold to asia pacific price will increase 225USD/MT.&lt;br&gt;Tronox said, now the TiO2 is still in strong demands, and the shipping sistuation is still tight and challenging. The 60days deliverying policy is still live.&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="TiO2" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Pangang New CP grade TiO2 production line final test is in progress</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/Pangang-New-CP-grade-line-final-test-is-in-progress/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/06/03/Pangang-New-CP-grade-line-final-test-is-in-progress/</id>
    <published>2021-06-03T09:19:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-03T09:30:54.427Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://pangang-titanium.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pangang Group</a> said recently, now the company is organizing forces for the final test of new production line of CP grade TiO2, which was designed for 15K/Mt annual capacity.<br>After then, the new production line is estimated to come into real production.</p><p>Data shows, Panzhihua area in Sichuan Province China, is one of the four largest iron ore production area, in which the associated resources reserves rank first of the whole world. Low-temperature chlorination process for producing titanium dioxide is the company original technology, using carbonized slag as its raw material. <a href="https://pangang-titanium.com/product/titanium-dioxide-rutile-cr-350/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CR-350</a> grade is in stable mass production.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pangang-titanium.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Pangang Group&lt;/a&gt; said recently, now the company is organizing forces for the final test of new production line of CP grade TiO2, which was designed for 15K/Mt annual capacity.&lt;br&gt;After then, the new production line is estimated to come into real production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data shows, Panzhihua area in Sichuan Province China, is one of the four largest iron ore production area, in which the associated resources reserves rank first of the whole world. Low-temperature chlorination process for producing titanium dioxide is the company original technology, using carbonized slag as its raw material. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pangang-titanium.com/product/titanium-dioxide-rutile-cr-350/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;CR-350&lt;/a&gt; grade is in stable mass production.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="TiO2" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market analysis weekly updates, 4th week May 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/28/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-4th-week-May-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/28/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-4th-week-May-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-05-28T09:46:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T10:23:30.356Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Keyword-Dull"><a href="#Keyword-Dull" class="headerlink" title="Keyword: Dull"></a>Keyword: Dull</h2><p>There aren’t many differences with the last week, except the shippment and exchange rates.<br>Read this:</p><p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/china-yuan-midday-idUSL1N2MM09Z" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Zhou Chengjun, director of the People’s Bank of China’s (PBOC) Finance Research Institute, says the rate has to be determined by global market participants.- China’s yuan near 2-month high as Fed, Biden stimulus drag on dollar</a></p><p><a href="https://www.scmp.com/economy/china-economy/article/3134546/chinas-central-bank-says-it-has-no-plans-ease-exchange-rate" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shenzhen’s Yantian Port suspends acceptance of heavy export containers after COVID-19 cases</a>.</p><ol><li>The Chinese central bank is more likely to free the CNY/USD exchange rates, which means, the under estimated CNY value will gradually exposed to the free international market. Not has to mention that the USD is even getting weaker after the pandemic. The exporters in China now is looking forward to a enter a New era of 5.xx CNY/USD rates.</li><li>The shippment shows no sign of ease. The jam and container shortages keep still. And the rates for far ocean routes is getting crazy. The freight to west africa is reaching 10k USD, to South America it is chasing after.</li></ol><p>To the market of tio2, it is dull, but we can still smell the intentions of turning arround is getting stronger.<br>The difficulty of shipment makes the both the manufacturers and exporters suffering, because the products jam at port, which means the money flow is getting slower and slower. And with the influence of the exchange rates, the pressure may out of our imagination.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Keyword-Dull&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Keyword-Dull&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Keyword: Dull&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Keyword: Dull&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There aren’t many differences with the last week, except the shippment and exchange rates.&lt;br&gt;Read this:&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="weekly updates" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/"/>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market analysis weekly updates, 3rd May 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/21/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-3rd-May-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/21/TiO2-market-analysis-weekly-updates-3rd-May-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-05-21T10:04:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-21T11:12:59.016Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Keyword-Unpredictable"><a href="#Keyword-Unpredictable" class="headerlink" title="Keyword: Unpredictable"></a>Keyword: Unpredictable</h2><p>If we say the first half of 2021 tio2 market was certain to surge, then now it is getting unclear and hard to predict.<br>There were many reasons for the certainty of price increasing in the first half, eg.:</p><ul><li>After pandemic recovery</li><li>Annually peak season</li><li>Centralized release of demand</li><li>Reduced logistics efficiency<br>…<h2 id="Why-now-it-is-becoming-unpredictable"><a href="#Why-now-it-is-becoming-unpredictable" class="headerlink" title="Why now it is becoming unpredictable?"></a>Why now it is becoming unpredictable?</h2>When it came to the certainty in the past months, there were almost no challenging aspects to the uptrends.<br>Now, when we say it is unpredictable, for sure there are challenging aspects, and they are growing.<br>What are they?</li></ul><ul><li>After the fifth round of price increase, now the made in China TiO2 almost lost all price allure in the market when competing with western brands.<br>And the SP price is too much close to the CP grade, which makes distributors and endusers standing by and watch instead of taking immediately action.</li><li>All participators is running out of stocks. Now, the manufactures are finishing the orders placed in March, April, even in Feb. Looks like they are<br>truely busy, and running in full load. But the reality is, after the Fourth round of price in crease in late April and the fifth in Early May, the new<br>orders are dropping.  Especially after the fifth round, and if more buyers choose to wait, it will hard for the manufactues to continuing working in a full load.</li></ul><h2 id="So-why-don’t-they-decrease-the-price"><a href="#So-why-don’t-they-decrease-the-price" class="headerlink" title="So why don’t they decrease the price?"></a>So why don’t they decrease the price?</h2><ol><li>The pressure from the shrinking needs is burable. The last straw is not yet to come.</li><li>From the objective reality aspect. The cost is still increasing.</li></ol><h2 id="The-increasing-is-based-on-a-solid-ground"><a href="#The-increasing-is-based-on-a-solid-ground" class="headerlink" title="The increasing is based on a solid ground."></a>The increasing is based on a solid ground.</h2><ul><li>Raw materials price increasing. From the ilmenite to sulphate, the price is still going up. According to informed sources, the LM is going to raise the price os ilmenite<br>in last week. If it works out, then the 6th round of price increasing of TiO2 will be a high probability event.</li><li>Environmental inspection. Now it is again a hot topic in chemical industry of China, the central government sent groups of inspectors to local for the purpose of Environmental inspection.<br>And they report only to the central government, which makes the local entrepreneurs in high pressure, and from time to time halt the production to avoid the possibility of being figured.</li><li>The potential of new demands releasing. The domestic market of China is cooling down gradually, and most of the big demands were fed up in April. But to June, it is another two months, and most<br>of the endusers stock for less than 3 months. Which means, they are gettting hungry again.</li><li>The logistics is still not fully recovered which makes the whole supply chain looks like a dripping water pipe, instead flushing as in old days. This is a reason of the shortages the market felt,<br>instead of huge demands. The gloabl economical growth in 2020 and 2021 can not nursing great demands as we all know. The demands is not changing, the capacity is not changing, but if the pipe is getting<br>smaller, then you will feel huge gap between demands and supply.</li></ul><h2 id="What-is-the-suggestion"><a href="#What-is-the-suggestion" class="headerlink" title="What is the suggestion?"></a>What is the suggestion?</h2><p>Be cautious.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Keyword-Unpredictable&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Keyword-Unpredictable&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Keyword: Unpredictable&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Keyword: Unpredictable&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If we say the first half of 2021 tio2 market was certain to surge, then now it is getting unclear and hard to predict.&lt;br&gt;There were many reasons for the certainty of price increasing in the first half, eg.:&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="weekly updates" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/"/>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The fifth round of price increases during the year landed, titanium dioxide price rose for 11 consecutive months</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/14/The-fifth-round-of-price-increases-during-the-year-landed-titanium-dioxide-price-rose-for-11-consecutive-months/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/14/The-fifth-round-of-price-increases-during-the-year-landed-titanium-dioxide-price-rose-for-11-consecutive-months/</id>
    <published>2021-05-14T01:15:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-14T03:34:56.188Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>stcn.com, Zhaoliyun</strong> Original content <a href="https://stock.stcn.com/djjd/202105/t20210512_3216342.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">年内第五轮涨价落地 钛白粉连涨11个月</a></p><p>As a product whose price fluctuations have attracted much attention from the market before, the announcement of titanium dioxide’s recent rise has been submerged in the “rising sound” of various commodities one after another. Inadvertently, titanium dioxide has been rising for 11 consecutive months, and the fifth round of price increases this year has also landed one after another, and the record for the longest product price increase is about to be broken.</p><h2 id="The-price-hike-lasted-for-nearly-a-year"><a href="#The-price-hike-lasted-for-nearly-a-year" class="headerlink" title="The price hike lasted for nearly a year"></a>The price hike lasted for nearly a year</h2><p>On May 10, the leader of the titanium dioxide industry, Lomon Baili(Known as LomonBillions), issued an announcement stating that, according to the current domestic and international titanium dioxide market conditions, the company will start from now on all types of titanium dioxide (including sulfuric acid titanium dioxide, chloride titanium dioxide) On the basis of the original price, the sales price will be raised by RMB 1,000/ton for various domestic customers and USD 150/ton for international customers.</p><p>Prior to this, another leading company in the industry, CNNC HUA YUAN Titanium Dioxide Co., Ltd(Known as CHTI), also issued a price adjustment announcement, stating that the overall increase in the sales price of the company’s main products will help further enhance the company’s continued profitability and improve the company’s market position and influence. It is expected to have an impact on the company’s operations. The results will have a positive impact.</p><p>The price adjustments of Lomon Baili and CNNC HUA YUAN Titanium Dioxide Co., Ltd are not alone. After the May 1st holiday, the titanium dioxide price market has remained strong and stable.</p><p>“At present, more than ten manufacturers including Anada, Hengtong Titanium, Longteng Titanium, Jiangsu Zhentai, Shandong Dongjia, Jinpu Titanium, Shandong Dawn, etc. have sent letters announcing an increase of 1,000 yuan/ton, in addition to Southwest etc. Several producers in the region went straight up by 800-1000 yuan/ton without letter, continuing the bullish market sentiment. The price market is already the fifth round of price increases this year.” Yan Ti analyst Yang Xun said.</p><p>Yang Xun introduced that the mainstream prices of most domestic sulfuric acid rutile and anatase titanium dioxides currently range from 19,800 to 21,000 yuan/ton and 18,300 to 19,000 yuan/ton. Domestic and imported chlorinated rutile titanium dioxides differentiate the mainstream prices by use At 21500-23500 yuan / ton and 27000-28500 yuan / ton (the above are all tax-included cash outbound prices). Since July 2020, the titanium dioxide market has been rising for 11 consecutive months, almost equal to the longest continuous rise record of titanium dioxide in 2016. The price market continues to be strong, and the price of holders is relatively hard. For low-price inquiries More resistant, more inclined to cash orders.</p><p>Zhuochuang analyst Tian Xiaoyu also said that the current domestic titanium dioxide market has been rising for 11 months, and the market price will also break through the historical high since 2012. During the period, as the most upstream of the titanium dioxide industry chain, titanium concentrate performed more prominently. In the second half of 2020 alone, the growth rate exceeded 65%, and in some stages it provided strong cost support for the price of titanium dioxide.</p><h2 id="Cost-support-high-price-continuation"><a href="#Cost-support-high-price-continuation" class="headerlink" title="Cost support high price continuation"></a>Cost support high price continuation</h2><p>What are the factors supporting the continued increase in the price of titanium dioxide? Is the price increase sustainable?</p><p>Yang Xun said that the current trading market is still very confrontational, and the price market is in a state of gaming. In terms of demand, industries such as plastic color masterbatches have entered the off-season, and overall demand has declined. At the same time, the downward transmission of costs is difficult, and it is more resistant to high-priced titanium dioxide, and production is simply stopped. In addition, high-priced titanium dioxide forces end customers to try alternatives. However, on the supply side, titanium concentrates are always tight and expensive, and the raw material cost of titanium dioxide remains high.</p><p>At present, the market has a large number of foreign trade orders, and the main manufacturers have received orders until June. The vast majority of manufacturers and distributors are tight in stock, especially some of the main brand products. What needs attention is that environmental inspections and emergencies have also caused some regional producers to suspend production, causing production capacity to shrink.</p><h2 id="Cost-support-is-indeed-one-of-the-main-reasons-why-the-price-of-titanium-dioxide-continues-to-rise"><a href="#Cost-support-is-indeed-one-of-the-main-reasons-why-the-price-of-titanium-dioxide-continues-to-rise" class="headerlink" title="Cost support is indeed one of the main reasons why the price of titanium dioxide continues to rise."></a>Cost support is indeed one of the main reasons why the price of titanium dioxide continues to rise.</h2><p>“Titanium concentrate is the main and important raw material in the production of titanium dioxide. Titanium dioxide accounts for nearly 96% of the downstream consumption of titanium concentrate. Others are mostly used in the manufacture of sponge titanium. Since the bottom of the price in 2020, the price of titanium concentrate has doubled. The current national market average price is 2450 yuan/ton. At the end of April, major Panxi major manufacturers raised their sales guidance prices for May by 80-100 yuan/ton. Supported by the price of titanium concentrates on the main cost surface, the domestic titanium dioxide market after Labor Day A new round of growth has begun.” Tian Xiaoyu said.</p><p>Regarding the market outlook, Yang Xun believes that in the short term, the game between supply and demand is obvious, demand enters the off-season, and the terminal is more resistant to high-level titanium dioxide; supply-side manufacturers have high costs, smooth exports, tight spot prices, and low start-ups. Without the support of demand, the mid- to long-term market trend is still unclear, but the profit in May is as expected, and the current real order price is strong and firm.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stcn.com, Zhaoliyun&lt;/strong&gt; Original content &lt;a href=&quot;https://stock.stcn.com/djjd/202105/t20210512_3216342.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;年内第五轮涨价落地 钛白粉连涨11个月&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a product whose price fluctuations have attracted much attention from the market before, the announcement of titanium dioxide’s recent rise has been submerged in the “rising sound” of various commodities one after another. Inadvertently, titanium dioxide has been rising for 11 consecutive months, and the fifth round of price increases this year has also landed one after another, and the record for the longest product price increase is about to be broken.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-price-trend/"/>
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title> Venator announces global Titanium Dioxide price increases</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/13/Venator-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-price-increases/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/13/Venator-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-price-increases/</id>
    <published>2021-05-13T04:03:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T04:20:01.742Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="VENATOR-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-Price-INCREASES"><a href="#VENATOR-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-Price-INCREASES" class="headerlink" title="VENATOR announces global Titanium Dioxide Price INCREASES"></a>VENATOR announces global Titanium Dioxide Price INCREASES</h2><blockquote><p>WYNYARD, UK – Venator Materials PLC (“Venator”) (NYSE:VNTR) today announced global price increases for all its titanium dioxide pigments for coatings, plastics, inks and paper applications. The increases are effective from July 1, 2021.<br>EMEA (Europe, Middle East and Africa): €180/t or USD USD200/t<br>Asia Pacific / Latin America: USD USD200/t<br>North America: USD $0.08/lb<br>The implementation of the above announced increases will be agreed with individual customers consistent with our customer tailored approach.</p></blockquote><p>The original announcement<a href="https://www.venatorcorp.com/media/news/2021/2021-05-12" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VENATOR announces global Titanium Dioxide Price INCREASES</a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;VENATOR-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-Price-INCREASES&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#VENATOR-announces-global-Titanium-Dioxide-Price-INCREASES&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;VENATOR announces global Titanium Dioxide Price INCREASES&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;VENATOR announces global Titanium Dioxide Price INCREASES&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WYNYARD, UK – Venator Materials PLC (“Venator”) (NYSE:VNTR) today announced global price increases for all its titanium dioxide pigments for coatings, plastics, inks and paper applications. The increases are effective from July 1, 2021.&lt;br&gt;EMEA (Europe, Middle East and Africa): €180/t or USD USD200/t&lt;br&gt;Asia Pacific / Latin America: USD USD200/t&lt;br&gt;North America: USD $0.08/lb&lt;br&gt;The implementation of the above announced increases will be agreed with individual customers consistent with our customer tailored approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
      <category term="Venator" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Venator/"/>
    
      <category term="Venator titanium Dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Venator-titanium-Dioxide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>KRONOS announced price increase from July 1 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/12/KRONOS-announced-price-increase-from-July-1-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/12/KRONOS-announced-price-increase-from-July-1-2021/</id>
    <published>2021-05-12T09:04:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T09:39:17.928Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="KRONOS-ANOUNCED-price-increase-at-April-30th-2021"><a href="#KRONOS-ANOUNCED-price-increase-at-April-30th-2021" class="headerlink" title="KRONOS ANOUNCED price increase at April 30th, 2021."></a>KRONOS ANOUNCED price increase at April 30th, 2021.</h2><p>The full letter as following:</p><blockquote><p>Dear valued partner,<br>Pleqase be advised, that KRONOS will implement a price increase of minimum<br><strong>EUR 250, GBP 220, USD 300</strong><br>for all Titanium Dioxide products in the region MEAA with an effective date of July 1, 2021 or as contractual agreements allow.<br>This increase is in response to continuing strong demand and substantially mltigates rising costs across all areas of our business.<br>We thank you for partnering with KRONOS and allowing us to serve your Titanium dioxide needs, KRONOS continues to be focused on the world-class production and supply of high-quality titanium dioxide along with leading levels of technical support &amp; customer service. We continue to be committed to a long-term future with our partners.<br>If you have any questions or require further assistance, please do not hesitate to contact your KRONOS sales representative.<br>Sincerely,<br>KRONOS INTERNATIONAL, Inc.</p></blockquote><p>The file as :<br><a href="https://tinoxchem.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/20210512172400.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Price increase KRONOS Titanium Dioxide</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;KRONOS-ANOUNCED-price-increase-at-April-30th-2021&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#KRONOS-ANOUNCED-price-increase-at-April-30th-2021&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;KRONOS ANOUNCED price increase at April 30th, 2021.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;KRONOS ANOUNCED price increase at April 30th, 2021.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The full letter as following:&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
      <category term="KRONOS" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/KRONOS/"/>
    
      <category term="KRONOS titanium Dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/KRONOS-titanium-Dioxide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 material shortage has no sign of easing.</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/05/10/TiO2-material-shortage-has-no-sign-of-easing/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/05/10/TiO2-material-shortage-has-no-sign-of-easing/</id>
    <published>2021-05-10T02:06:07.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T08:02:54.249Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>“Several price increases during the year 　 the prosperity of titanium dioxide continues to improve”</strong> -<em>ECONOMIC INFORMATION DAILY,Li Ben, Beijing.</em> <a href="http://www.jjckb.cn/2021-05/10/c_139935122.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">年内多次提价　钛白粉景气度持续提升</a><br><strong>“Titanium dioxide welcomes the “price boom” again, short-term demand still exceeds supply.”</strong> -<em>Sina Financial, ZhangJia Yun, Beijing</em><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699066858562408080&wfr=spider&for=pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">钛白粉再迎“涨价潮” 短期仍供不应求</a><br><strong>The industry has entered the traditional peak season, titanium dioxide staged a new round of price increase cycle</strong><em>Yicai.com</em><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699066858562408080&wfr=spider&for=pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">行业已进入传统旺季，钛白粉上演新一轮涨价周期</a><br><strong>Titanium dioxide business quickly into the fifth round of the year prices surge.</strong><em>163.com</em><a href="https://www.163.com/dy/article/G9K9N5Q105373SK0.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">钛白粉企业迅速投入年内第五轮涨价潮</a><br><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699173959379051963&wfr=spider&for=pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“These price increasing letter showing the unstoppable trends of price increases.</a></p><h2 id="The-current-domestic-titanium-dioxide-market-situation"><a href="#The-current-domestic-titanium-dioxide-market-situation" class="headerlink" title="The current domestic titanium dioxide market situation:"></a>The current domestic titanium dioxide market situation:</h2><p>Now, the domestic price is around 20400CNY/MT, and FOB 3150-3350USD/MT. And in a very tight supply.</p><blockquote><p>“Before Sep. 2021, there could be 2-3 rounds of price increases” by analysts form LMB.<br>“The strong revocery of China domestic ecomony makes the domestic demand surges and the ilmenite supplier reserves a positive expection of the market showing no intends to lower the price”. by PM of Tinox.</p></blockquote><h2 id="Is-there-any-grades-which-is-less-tighter-supply"><a href="#Is-there-any-grades-which-is-less-tighter-supply" class="headerlink" title="Is there any grades which is less tighter supply?"></a>Is there any grades which is less tighter supply?</h2><blockquote><p>“Of course, now, LMB R108 sales not as expected, and in recent days, can be purchased domestically. Traditionally, this season is a off-season for tio2, but this year, only those neighbor markets of China shows the sign of off-season.”<a href="https://pangang-titanium.com/?p=108" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pangang Titanium industry</a></p></blockquote><p><em>Titanium dioxide welcomes the “price boom” again, short-term demand still exceeds supply.</em> <em>Sina Financial, ZhangJia Yun, Beijing, _Translated by Qiaomai Lang</em></p><p>At noon on May 6, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. (002145.SZ) issued a letter for the fifth increase in the price of titanium dioxide in the year.</p><p>In fact, entering May, listed companies such as Jinpu Titanium (000545.SZ) and Anada (002136.SZ) have also begun to raise the sales price of titanium dioxide, and the price increase in this round remains the same. Recently, the share prices of listed titanium dioxide companies have shown an upward trend. Benefiting from the continued rise in the price of titanium dioxide, the first quarter performance of the leading listed companies in the industry hit a new high during the same period.</p><p>An executive of Lomon Baili said in an interview with a reporter from “China Business News” that generally price increases are determined by cost and demand. This year’s consecutive price increases are mainly due to rising raw material costs and strong market demand; especially foreign market demand Further strengthening has made the first quarter performance of domestic titanium dioxide listed companies soar.</p><p><strong>Start a new wave of price increases?</strong></p><p>In the midday of May 6, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. issued an announcement stating that the company’s price committee decided that from now on, on the basis of the current sales price of titanium dioxide, the company’s sales prices for various types of titanium dioxide will be raised. Among them, the sales price for domestic customers is raised by RMB 1,000/ton, and the export price for international customers is raised by USD150/ton.</p><p>The reporter noticed that since the beginning of this year, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. has issued monthly announcements on raising the sales price of titanium dioxide. Looking at the leopard, as the industry’s leading company, the continuous price increase of CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. also represents the titanium dioxide industry.</p><p>In fact, in addition to CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd., the two listed companies of Jinpu Titanium Industry and Anada also raised the sales price of titanium dioxide, and the price increase of the three companies remained the same, which also indicates that titanium dioxide is expected to start a new round of price increases. tide.</p><p>Regarding the reasons for the price increase, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. said that it decided to increase the price “according to the recent market conditions of titanium dioxide and the increase in raw material prices.” Ananda also stated that the company decided to increase prices based on recent domestic and international market demand for titanium dioxide and rising prices of raw materials.</p><p>Earlier, Fu Yijiang, deputy secretary-general of the Titanium Dioxide Branch of the China Coatings Industry Association, said in an interview that after the global new crown pneumonia epidemic, the market is optimistic and demand is the main reason for the strong titanium dioxide market. The coatings, automotive paint and other markets have improved recently. Driven the increase in market demand for titanium dioxide, exports will continue to increase.</p><p>According to Fu Yijiang’s analysis, the upstream raw material of titanium dioxide is titanium concentrate, and its downstream applications are extensive, including coatings, automotive paint, medicine, food and other industries. The price of upstream titanium concentrate rose by 53% from June 2020 to February 2021. Downstream coatings, automotive paints and other fields are the application areas of titanium dioxide. In 2020, the national commercial housing sales area was 1.761 billion square meters, an increase of 2.6% year-on-year; the recent price increase in the coating industry has been soaring, and the price of titanium concentrate has continued to rise.</p><p>According to statistics from Zhuo Chuang Information, as of the end of April, the price of 46% titanium concentrate has been raised by RMB 150/ton from the previous month, with an average price of RMB 2,450/ton; on April 29, Panxi’s mainstream mining companies will guide their new orders for titanium concentrate prices in May. Raise 80 yuan/ton; as of the end of April, the market price of sulfuric acid in Shandong increased by 140 yuan/ton to 570 yuan/ton, and the price in the East China market rose by 60 yuan/ton to 565 yuan/ton. At the beginning of last July, the titanium concentrate was only 1175 yuan per ton.</p><p>The price of ilmenite concentrate has risen, and the price of sulfuric acid in the upstream is superimposed. These two major cost pressures have brought greater impetus to the price of the upstream market of titanium dioxide.</p><p>The Titanium Concentrate Analyst of Business Club believes that the actual price of titanium concentrate in Panxi is relatively strong, and the spot of titanium concentrate continues to be tight, and some miners are reluctant to sell it. The new price of titanium concentrate may rise steadily, and it is actually single. Discussion.</p><p>According to data from Baichuan, on April 23, the mainstream price of sulfuric acid rutile titanium dioxide market was 20000 to 21000 yuan/ton, the mainstream price of anatase titanium dioxide market was 17300~18000 yuan/ton, and the mainstream price of chloride titanium dioxide market was It is 22000 to 24000 yuan/ton.</p><p>Fu Yijiang told reporters that with the gradual improvement of the global epidemic, the climax of global resumption of production and work, coupled with the implementation of a new round of stimulus of 1.9 trillion USD by the Biden administration, has hindered the US industrial chain caused by the epidemic. In the context of a rapid rebound in U.S. demand driven by scale stimulus, U.S. imports from China have surged. From January to February this year, Chinese exports soared by 60.6% in U.S. dollars, of which exports to the United States increased by 87.3%. In December 2020, the United States passed a 900 billion USD stimulus package to promote a 10.8% year-on-year growth in US retail sales in January 2021, the highest increase in history since March 1994. It is expected that the 1.9 trillion USD stimulus will further drive the high increase in US imports from China, especially the demand for consumer goods and real estate-related commodities.</p><p>At the same time, he said that the U.S., Europe and the “Belt and Road” markets are gradually recovering, and the domestic and international dual cycles are oriented towards mutual promotion, which has become the new strategic direction of the Chinese economy after the epidemic. The demand for domestic and foreign consumer goods and real estate-related commodities will greatly stimulate China’s production output is increasing, and titanium dioxide is a rigid demand product in many fields. From the current global market, titanium dioxide will still be in a situation of “supply exceeds demand” in the short term.</p><p>According to the analysis of Zhuo Chuang Information, after the holiday, as expected, the logic of the market price increase in May will be clearer, including direct support from the cost-side raw material price increase and continued tight spot supply support. At present, downstream users on the demand side have also begun. In the face of continuous consumption of inventory, regular purchase plans need to be put on the agenda at the same time. Under high prices, the market outlook may show rigidity, so that in the process of price increases, the game advantages of buyers and sellers will still be biased towards the sellers, and ultimately promote the upward market price. .</p><p>CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. also stated that the company will closely follow the price trend of titanium dioxide and changes in supply and demand, and do a good job in adjusting the price of titanium dioxide products in a timely manner. The overall increase in the sales price of the company’s main products will help further enhance the company’s continued profitability, and will help improve the company’s market position and influence. It is expected to have a positive impact on the company’s operating results.</p><p><strong>Corporate performance rises</strong></p><p>Benefiting from the improvement of the industry’s prosperity, leading titanium dioxide companies performed well in the first quarter.</p><p>The reporter sorted out the financial report and noticed that recently, the first quarter of 2021 financial reports released by leading companies such as Jinpu Titanium Industry, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd., Anada, Lubei Chemical and other listed companies in the titanium dioxide industry showed that their performance has achieved substantial growth.</p><p>The financial report shows that on May 6, Jinpu Titanium released its first quarter report of 2021. During the reporting period, the company achieved operating income of 574 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 46.98%; net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was 35 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 1308.05 %. On April 30, Lubei Chemical (600727.SH) released the report for the first quarter of 2021. The company achieved total operating income of 928 million yuan, an increase of 38.73% year-on-year; net profit attributable to the parent company was 107 million yuan, an increase of 136.8% year-on-year.</p><p>In addition, on April 26, CNNC Hua Yuan Titanium Dioxide Company Ltd. released its report for the first quarter of 2021. The company’s revenue was 1.236 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 49.53%; net profit was about 287 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 77.29%. Huiyun Titanium Industry (300891.SZ) released its first quarterly report for 2021. In the first quarter of 2021, the company achieved operating income of 319 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 51.99%. The net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was 45 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 81.25%. . On April 24, Anadar issued a report for the first quarter of 2021. During the reporting period, the company achieved operating income of 406 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 58.50%; net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was 31 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 28.54%.</p><p>Regarding the substantial increase in performance, Jinpu Titanium Industry stated that during the reporting period, the increase in operating income and profit was mainly due to the increase in sales volume, sales price and increase in the sales price of titanium dioxide, the main product during the reporting period, and the increase in gross profit.</p><p>Economist Song Qinghui analyzed to reporters that the sharp rise in profits of listed companies is also a manifestation of the industry’s further elimination of backward production capacity in the market in recent years, the continuous increase of industry concentration, and the manifestation of intensive benefits.</p><p>It can be seen that in recent years, leading titanium dioxide companies have expanded their layout and occupied market share.</p><p>At the end of February 2020, China Nuclear Power Titanium Dioxide released a 1.6 billion yuan fixed increase plan, and plans to raise funds for the 200,000 tons/year titanium dioxide post-processing project. Subsequently, on April 23, Lomon Baili issued an announcement stating that the number of non-public offerings would not exceed 368 million shares, and the total amount of raised funds would not exceed 4.387 billion yuan for use in titanium chloride slag and chlorinated titanium dioxide. Production and construction and supplementary working capital.</p><p>At the same time, in 2020, after Lubei Chemical acquired Jinhai Titanium Industry and Xianghai Titanium Industry, the titanium dioxide business became the company’s largest business. Lubei Chemical currently has an annual production capacity of over 100,000 tons of sulfuric acid titanium dioxide, and is proceeding in an orderly manner with the construction of a production line of 100,000 tons of sulfuric acid titanium dioxide and a production line of 60,000 tons of chloride titanium dioxide. After the project is completed, its titanium dioxide production capacity will reach 26 Million tons.</p><p>Qin Chong, a researcher at China Research and Puhua, told reporters that in 2019, the top 5 companies in the world’s titanium dioxide production capacity accounted for 90% of the industry’s production capacity, while the top ten concentration of my country’s titanium dioxide industry was about 68%, referring to the global situation It can be seen that there will still be acquisitions in the titanium dioxide industry in my country in the future to cater to the development trend of the industry. At the same time, with the help of listed companies, funding channels have been increased, and risk resistance has been increased for the development of enterprises. In addition, due to the implementation of environmental protection policies, the policy-oriented chlorination process will become the mainstream, and the new production capacity will basically be chlorination, which is also a manifestation of the company’s catering to the market.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Several price increases during the year 　 the prosperity of titanium dioxide continues to improve”&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;em&gt;ECONOMIC INFORMATION DAILY,Li Ben, Beijing.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jjckb.cn/2021-05/10/c_139935122.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;年内多次提价　钛白粉景气度持续提升&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Titanium dioxide welcomes the “price boom” again, short-term demand still exceeds supply.”&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;em&gt;Sina Financial, ZhangJia Yun, Beijing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699066858562408080&amp;wfr=spider&amp;for=pc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;钛白粉再迎“涨价潮” 短期仍供不应求&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The industry has entered the traditional peak season, titanium dioxide staged a new round of price increase cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yicai.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699066858562408080&amp;wfr=spider&amp;for=pc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;行业已进入传统旺季，钛白粉上演新一轮涨价周期&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Titanium dioxide business quickly into the fifth round of the year prices surge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;163.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.163.com/dy/article/G9K9N5Q105373SK0.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;钛白粉企业迅速投入年内第五轮涨价潮&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1699173959379051963&amp;wfr=spider&amp;for=pc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;“These price increasing letter showing the unstoppable trends of price increases.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;The-current-domestic-titanium-dioxide-market-situation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#The-current-domestic-titanium-dioxide-market-situation&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;The current domestic titanium dioxide market situation:&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The current domestic titanium dioxide market situation:&lt;/h2&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
      <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
      <category term="titanium dioxide market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
