<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tio2.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2024-09-27T02:33:23.020Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-09-20 to 2024-09-27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-09-20-to-2024-09-27/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:33:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:33:23.020Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices remain steady, with Mozambique titanium ore priced at around $368 per ton and Kenyan 47%-49% grade ore priced at around $362 per ton. The supply of imported titanium ore remains tight, and domestic signing is cautious.</li><li>The high titanium slag market is weak, with prices around $831-$839 per ton. Production costs are high, and enterprises are running at a loss, leading to reduced production and weak market conditions.</li><li>Titanium tetrachloride prices are stable at around $857-$914 per ton. The price of liquid chlorine is fluctuating, and high raw material prices are putting production pressure on titanium tetrachloride manufacturers.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak and stable. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2162-$2302 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2049-$2104 per ton.</li><li>With order volumes decreasing, some enterprises are experiencing inventory increases. As the holiday approaches, there is slight stocking in the downstream market, but overall demand remains weak. Some enterprises have temporarily halted production due to environmental and maintenance reasons, leading to a slight decrease in titanium dioxide production.</li><li>The market remains competitive, and downstream procurement is cautious due to high costs. The mainstream prices of titanium dioxide are stable, with some prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>After a brief period of market activity in the first half of this month, the market has returned to silence. Demand has been below expectations, the supply side is under significant cost pressure, and inventory has not yet bottomed out, indicating that weakness may persist. However, on the capital side, the purchasing power of the US dollar continues to decline, while the Chinese yuan has rebounded strongly. In summary, transaction prices denominated in US dollars will continue to rise slightly due to exchange rate fluctuations.</li><li>As the US dollar continues to weaken, the purchasing power of the global southern markets will continue to strengthen. With the peak demand season gradually approaching, the overall market price is likely to continue its slow upward trend.</li><li>There is an imbalance in the supply and demand of sponge titanium, and prices are expected to remain weak.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The market for titanium ore (ilmenite) has been weak, with prices for small and medium manufacturers around $311-$314 per ton, and 38-grade titanium ore (excluding tax) around $224-$231 per ton.
 * Imported titanium ore prices remain steady</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium_dioxide_price_index_2199.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/27/2024-09-27-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.16/</id>
    <published>2024-09-27T02:05:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-27T02:06:31.412Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6,124.23 to $6,410.11 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.16, unchanged from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.

Titanium Tetrachloride: Market prices range from approximately $854.62 to $911.45 per ton. S</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium_dioxide_price_index_2199.47</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/26/2024-09-26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2199.47/</id>
    <published>2024-09-26T02:28:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-26T02:43:03.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide (TiO2):</strong> Market prices range from approximately $854.74 to $911.65 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, prices remain firm. The downstream market continues to be sluggish, maintaining a weak but stable trend.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $6125.01 to $6410.57 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2199.47, a slight increase of 5 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium_dioxide_price_index_2194</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/09/25/2024-09-25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2194/</id>
    <published>2024-09-25T03:12:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-26T03:37:32.359Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p>Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions remain weak.</p><p>Titanium Slag The high-temperature market has low production activity, with market prices remaining low. The high cost of raw titanium ore puts immense pressure on enterprises, and the market remains sluggish.</p><p>Titanium Tetrachloride The market price for Titanium Tetrachloride is 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 852.47-909.24 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have lower transaction prices. Enterprises face significant cost pressures, and downstream cost pressures are also high. The price of Titanium Tetrachloride remains stable.</p><p>Titanium Sponge The mainstream price for first-grade Titanium Sponge in the market is about 4.3-4.5 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 611.08-639.90 USD&#x2F;ton). The demand for Titanium Sponge is weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices at a low level.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide Today’s Titanium Dioxide price index is 2193.57, unchanged from the previous working day. The market demand for Titanium Dioxide is weak, with enterprise orders gradually decreasing, and export pressures increasing. Some enterprises are gradually adjusting new order prices, and the market sentiment is cautious.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Market Summary Due to further tightening of raw material supply by Panzhihua Iron and Steel, and a reduction in processing factories, raw material shortages have stabilized prices. Small and medium-sized miners continue to hold firm quotes, but market transactions re</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 price index hits a new low of the last year</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/08/18/TiO2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</id>
    <published>2022-08-18T06:58:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-18T07:14:44.613Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.<br><img src="https://tio2.pro/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/%E4%B8%8B%E8%BD%BD-1536x647.png" alt="TiO2 price index trend"><br>It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off seasonal, but the truth is far more than this.</p><p>After a strong period of growth since the late of 2020, the whole industry is getting to chill, party is over. And everything will final back to real life. And the value is getting back to its reality.<br>The global inflation. Food, energy, and very thing price is increasing. People is consuming on the things really matters, as to the pigments, is that really matter? The paints manufacturers are reporting of high stocks after the shortage of the first half of the year, and less willing to making new.<br>But long this could continues?</p><p>Based on our experience, this time price withdraw is basically a good sign to show that the global inflation is haling. And it will finally go back into the real track. To our estimation, without any blackswan inccidents, the index will finally wave at 1800~2100 level. And it could take 2 years to arrive at the postition where it belongs.<br>The original article:<a href="https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/"> https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/08/18/tio2-price-index-hits-a-new-low-of-the-last-year/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">The latest TiO2 price index is 2439, 21% lower than the same period last year, a harsh drop of 15% than the first day of July.

It is not difficult to find out that the maket is in very low demands after the earlier summer. Industrial watchers are firmly agree that this is mainly caused by the off s</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide market analysis July 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/07/26/Titanium-dioxide-market-analysis-July-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/07/26/Titanium-dioxide-market-analysis-July-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-07-26T09:12:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-26T09:21:24.102Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-ore"><a href="#Titanium-ore" class="headerlink" title="Titanium ore"></a>Titanium ore</h2><p>As of now, the transaction price of 46.10 titanium ore from small and medium-sized manufacturers is 2150-2180 yuan &#x2F; ton, 47&#x2F;20 ore is quoted at 2400-2450 yuan &#x2F; ton, 38&#x2F;42 titanium ore is not The quotation including tax is 1530-1580 yuan &#x2F; ton; the iron ore construction has declined, the supply of medium-sized mines continues to be tight, the price is high and strong, and the cost of concentrate is under great pressure; the downstream titanium dioxide market continues to weaken, and the small and medium-sized miners of 10 mines are under relatively high pressure on shipments. The high-level price has also been adjusted back compared with the previous period, the high-low price difference has gradually narrowed, and the titanium ore market continues to run strongly.<br>The price of imported titanium ore has remained stable. As of now, the Australian titanium ore market is priced at US$460&#x2F;ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore market is priced at 480 US dollars&#x2F;ton, and Kenya’s 47-49 mines are temporarily unavailable. The international market for titanium raw materials is tight, and in the first half of the year The amount of imported ore returned to China decreased by 12.27% compared with the same period of last year; however, the downstream market remained weak, some prices were at a loss, and the price of non-mainstream imported ore was slightly adjusted, while the output of chlorinated titanium dioxide increased by 26% compared with the same period last year, and the demand for imported ore It is also increasing steadily, coupled with the release of new production capacity in the market in the third quarter, the price of titanium raw materials for the chloride process will continue to run at a high level. </p><h2 id="Titanium-slag"><a href="#Titanium-slag" class="headerlink" title="Titanium slag"></a>Titanium slag</h2><p>The high-titanium slag market continues to operate weakly. This month, the new bidding price of the northern 90 general slag high-titanium slag is 10,200 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the bidding price of low-calcium-magnesium high-titanium slag is 10,650 yuan&#x2F;ton. New production capacity is released, while the downstream market is under great pressure, some prices have already lost money, the market is oversupplied, and the high-titanium slag is running weakly.<br>This week, the acid residue market continued to run steadily and weakly. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 5,600 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price including tax in Yunnan is 5,000-5,550 yuan&#x2F;ton. Recently, the downstream titanium dioxide market has declined, and the acid residue market has shipped The pressure is high, the inventory of some manufacturers is high, the pressure of enterprises continues to increase, and the market transaction price is also weak.</p><h2 id="Titanium-tetrachloride"><a href="#Titanium-tetrachloride" class="headerlink" title="Titanium tetrachloride"></a>Titanium tetrachloride</h2><p>The market price of titanium chloride continued to decline this Thursday. The prices in Sichuan, Henan, Yunnan and other regions were reduced by 300 yuan&#x2F;ton. The current market price of titanium tetrachloride is 8500-8700 yuan&#x2F;ton; Although the price of titanium tetrachloride has been lowered, the profit of the enterprise is still good, but the downstream chlorination method titanium dioxide market is weak, and the titanium tetrachloride enterprises are also under certain pressure on the shipment, and the price of titanium tetrachloride will be adjusted in the later stage.</p><h2 id="Titanium-dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium dioxide"></a>Titanium dioxide</h2><p>This week, the market price of titanium dioxide is stable and weak. As of now, the ex-factory price of China’s rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 17300-18700 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 16300-17000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The market is in the off-season, the downstream market is under-operated, the demand for titanium dioxide is reduced, and enterprises are under great pressure, and some prices continue to fall; The price is in a state of loss; at present, the market price is relatively chaotic, the supply of low-priced goods continues to increase, and the competition pressure of enterprises is relatively large, and under the multiple negative factors, the titanium dioxide market will continue to be weak.</p><h2 id="sulfuric-acid"><a href="#sulfuric-acid" class="headerlink" title="sulfuric acid"></a>sulfuric acid</h2><p>This week, the domestic sulfuric acid market continued to decline sharply, with a decline of 50-300 yuan&#x2F;ton. As of now, the ex-factory price of 98% smelting acid in Anhui is 540-580 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price of 98% smelting acid in Yunnan is 370-470 yuan. &#x2F; ton, the price of 98% smelting acid in Shandong area is 330-350 yuan &#x2F; ton; the price of raw material sulfur continues to weaken, and the cost of sulfuric acid is reduced; the downstream market demand continues to be weak, the market demand for chemical fertilizers and phosphate fertilizers is weak, and the cost pressure of enterprises is great. The price continued to fall; and the sulfuric acid market started relatively high, the market was oversupplied, and the supply of low-priced goods in the market increased significantly, and the sulfuric acid market continued to operate weakly in the short term. Sponge titanium<br>The titanium sponge market remained stable this week. At present, the transaction price of grade 1 titanium sponge in the market is 74,000-85,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. In June, the export market of titanium sponge remained relatively good, and the downstream domestic and foreign demand was good. The inventory of titanium sponge enterprises was still low. The cost of raw materials is high, and the price of sponge titanium will continue to run high.</p><h2 id="Market-outlook-forecast"><a href="#Market-outlook-forecast" class="headerlink" title="Market outlook forecast:"></a>Market outlook forecast:</h2><ol><li>The price of medium and small mines is high, and the quotations of small and medium-sized mines continue to be firm;</li><li>The titanium dioxide market is off-season, the market demand is weak, and the price continues to run weakly;</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium ore
As of now, the transaction price of 46.10 titanium ore from small and medium-sized manufacturers is 2150-2180 yuan / ton, 47/20 ore is quoted at 2400-2450 yuan / ton, 38/42 titanium ore is not The quotation including tax is 1530-1580 yuan / ton; the iron ore construction has declined, t</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="titanium dioxide market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide-market-analysis/"/>
    
    <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
    <category term="titanium dioxide" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-dioxide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market review of June 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/29/TiO2-market-review-of-June-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/29/TiO2-market-review-of-June-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-06-29T07:33:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-29T07:45:43.447Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="1-Titanium-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1 Titanium Market Analysis"></a>1 Titanium Market Analysis</h1><h2 id="1-1-Market-price-analysis-of-titanium-series"><a href="#1-1-Market-price-analysis-of-titanium-series" class="headerlink" title="1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series"></a>1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series</h2><p>In June, the transaction price of Panxi Titanium Mine rose steadily. The cumulative increase of 46,10 mines was 30-50 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38,42 mines rose by 30 yuan&#x2F;ton at the end of the month. The prices of major manufacturers remained stable. So far ,<br>The price of Panxi Dachang 47,20 titanium ore is 2400-2450 yuan&#x2F;ton, the transaction price of small and medium 46,10 titanium ore is about 2160-2200 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38,42 ore excluding tax is 1530-1580 yuan&#x2F;ton. There are three main reasons for the increase in market prices: 1. The cost of raw ore is high, and the cost pressure of small and medium-sized factories is relatively large, and the enterprises are not operating enough; 2. The iron ore market is sluggish, and the supply of medium-sized mines is tight; The market has seen a lot of destocking of 10 mines, and the transaction price has risen slightly. At present, the overall demand for titanium ore is relatively stable, and some enterprises are still under-operated, and the supply of large enterprises in Xichang is still tight. As the titanium dioxide market enters the off-season, the cost pressure of enterprises Large, coupled with weak terminal demand, titanium ore prices are not expected to rise significantly.</p><p>Imported titanium ore prices remained stable, and market quotations remained firm. Up to now, the price of Australia 50 titanium ore is 460 US dollars &#x2F; ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore price is 480 US dollars &#x2F; ton, Kenya 47-49 ore is temporarily not quoting, and Vietnam imported ore is not temporarily quoting; downstream titanium dioxide and titanium slag market capacity Continued release, stable market demand, but the price of imported ore is high, the cost pressure of enterprises is relatively large, and the high-priced orders are under pressure; according to customs statistics, imported titanium ore in May was 205,400 tons, a year-on-year decrease of 9.41%. In May, China imported about 1.4676 million tons of titanium ore, a year-on-year decrease of 9.46%. This year, the mainstream importing countries have declined severely, and domestic supply is still tight. In addition, in the second half of the year, there will be new production capacity released by the chlorination method, and the price of imported titanium ore will also continue. run high.</p><p>The price of titanium slag<br>in the acid slag market fell sharply in June. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 5,600 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price in Yunnan is 5,000-5,550 yuan&#x2F;ton. The downstream titanium dioxide market continues to be weak, and is affected by the Panxi part Influenced by the conversion of slag from manufacturers to mines, the demand for acid slag has decreased, enterprises are under great pressure on shipments, and prices have fallen; manufacturers’ inventories have increased, and companies have been under great pressure.</p><p>The high-slag market remains stable. 6 The bidding price of ordinary high-slag in the north is 10,400 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the bidding price of low-calcium-magnesium high-slag is 11,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The bidding in July will start soon, and the price is expected to be the same as last month. The market is running well, companies in the north are actively working, and some companies in the south are converting acid residues to high-slag production, and the market supply has increased; the downstream market demand is stable. Multi-dimensional stable operation.</p><p>The price of titanium tetrachloride<br>maintained stable operation this month. The market quotation of titanium tetrachloride was 8700-9100 yuan&#x2F;ton; the price of raw materials was high, the cost of titanium tetrachloride increased, and the market demand was relatively stable. The overall titanium tetrachloride market Relatively stable; while the downstream titanium sponge market is running well, and the price remains stable, the price of titanium tetrachloride is expected to continue to run steadily.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide<br>The titanium dioxide market in June was relatively chaotic, and the quotations of manufacturers were reduced by different degrees, and the price was reduced to 800-1200 yuan&#x2F;ton. The ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide including tax is 17500-18500 yuan &#x2F; ton; in June, the price of dragon enterprises remained stable, and the rebate discount did not change compared with the previous period. Influenced by other factors, the market economy is not good, the demand in East China and other regions has been greatly reduced, and enterprises are under great pressure to ship goods; the export market has remained stable in the past two months, but the domestic sales market is still weak, the competition pressure of enterprises is large, and market prices are running chaotically; raw material prices High, some low prices are on the verge of loss, and market competition is under great pressure. At the end of the month, the prices of individual companies have been lowered again, and the market has entered a traditional off-season. In July, market prices will continue to run weakly.</p><p>Sponge titanium<br>The sponge titanium market performed well in June. At present, the first-grade sponge titanium market price is 74,000-85,000 yuan &#x2F; ton. The price of raw magnesium ingots continues to fall. The pressure on semi-process enterprises has eased, and enterprises have gradually resumed construction; domestic and foreign market demand Continued to be strong, the export market for civilian products has increased significantly, the inventory of sponge titanium manufacturers will remain low, the new production capacity in the market will continue to be released, the market supply will increase, and the price of sponge titanium will continue to be high.</p><p>July market forecast:</p><ol><li>The demand for titanium ore is stable, the market supply is tight, and the price may rise slightly;</li><li>The titanium dioxide market has entered the off-season, the demand is still weak, and the market will continue to operate weakly;</li><li>The market demand for sponge titanium increases, the market supply is stable, and the market price runs smoothly.</li></ol><h2 id="1-2-Import-and-Export"><a href="#1-2-Import-and-Export" class="headerlink" title="1.2 Import and Export"></a>1.2 Import and Export</h2><p>Titanium ore<br>China imported 205,400 tons of titanium ore in May 2022, with a monthly average price of US$422&#x2F;ton, a year-on-year decrease of 9.41% and a month-on-month decrease of 56.06%; the top three countries in terms of import volume in May are: Mozambique, Norway, Vietnam; 2022 From January to May of this year, China imported about 1.4676 million tons of titanium ore, a year-on-year decrease of 9.46%, and the import volume decreased by about 153,400 tons.</p><p>Titanium Dioxide<br>China imported about 15,000 tons of titanium dioxide in May 2022, a year-on-year decrease of 5.06% and a month-on-month decrease of 2.57%; the top three imported regions in May were Taiwan, Mexico, and Australia; the cumulative import volume of titanium dioxide from January to May 2022 About 67,100 tons, a decrease of 17.17% compared with the same period last year, and the import volume decreased by about 13,900 tons.</p><p>According to customs data, China’s titanium dioxide exports in May 2022 will be about 115,700 tons, a year-on-year increase of 10.31% and a month-on-month decrease of 2.48%; the top three countries in terms of titanium dioxide exports in May are: India, Vietnam, and South Korea; January-May 2022 The cumulative export volume of titanium dioxide in the month was about 622,300 tons, a year-on-year increase of 15.24%, and the export volume increased by about 82,300 tons.</p><p>Titanium sponge<br>In May 2022, the import of titanium sponge was about 1357.4 tons, an increase of 55.56% year-on-year and a month-on-month increase of 23.26%; from January to May 2022, the cumulative import volume of titanium sponge in China was about 6548.9 tons, an increase of 66.37% year-on-year, and the import volume increased by about 2612.6 Ton.</p><p>In May 2022, China’s export of titanium sponge was about 256.8 tons, a year-on-year increase of 98.87% and a month-on-month decrease of 25.40 %; the cumulative export from January to May 2022 was about 748.2 tons, an increase of 45.71% year-on-year, and the import volume increased by about 234.72 tons.</p><h1 id="2-Production-of-titanium-dioxide-and-titanium-sponge-in-May"><a href="#2-Production-of-titanium-dioxide-and-titanium-sponge-in-May" class="headerlink" title="2 Production of titanium dioxide and titanium sponge in May"></a>2 Production of titanium dioxide and titanium sponge in May</h1><p>2.1 Yield Analysis:<br>According to Tu Duoduo’s statistics, in May 2022, China’s titanium dioxide output was 344,100 tons, a month-on-month increase of 2.28% and a year-on-year increase of 4.49%; Production increased by about 135,800 tons. In May, the regional output increased and decreased. Due to the overhaul of some devices and the influence of inventory pressure, the production of enterprises decreased. In May, some enterprises completed the maintenance, the output increased, and the overall output increased slightly.</p><p>The top three regions in May output were Sichuan, Henan, and Shandong, accounting for 21%, 15%, and 14% of the total output.</p><p>According to Tu Duoduo’s statistics, China’s titanium sponge output in May 2022 was 12,500 tons, a year-on-year increase of 0.24%. The output of titanium sponge in April 2022 increased by 9.65%. In May, China’s titanium sponge production maintained a steady and moderate growth trend. In June, semi-process titanium sponge enterprises Shengfeng Titanium Industry and Anshan Massive Plant will resume production. The production capacity of each enterprise will gradually be released, and the output of sponge titanium will reach a new record high.</p><p>In May, Liaoning, Xinjiang, and Henan, the top three domestic production areas of titanium sponge in China, accounted for 23%, 19% and 15% of the total domestic output respectively.</p><h1 id="3-Industry-News-of-the-Month"><a href="#3-Industry-News-of-the-Month" class="headerlink" title="3 Industry News of the Month"></a>3 Industry News of the Month</h1><p>“Invest 1 billion! The 500,000-ton paint project was officially put into production! 》<br>The first phase of the Jiangxi Tulian Waterborne Coatings Industrial Base Project invested and constructed by Jiangxi Tulian Group, the Yaka architectural paint production workshop in the first phase was completed and put into production recently. The project started construction on July 10, 2020, with a total area of ​​500 acres, of which: the first phase of the project covers an area of ​​300 acres and a total construction area of ​​230,000 square meters.</p><p>The total investment of the project is 1 billion yuan. It is designed to produce 500,000 tons of water-based environmental protection coatings, 200,000 tons of dry powder putty, 20 million square meters of polymer waterproof materials, 1 million square meters of thermal insulation and decoration integrated boards, and 50,000 tons of annual output. The construction emulsion and the annual output of 200,000 sets of coating packaging materials are expected to achieve an annual sales income of more than 1.5 billion yuan and an annual tax revenue of more than 45 million yuan after the project is completed.</p><p>“Anning Shares: At present, the company is going all out to promote the energy titanium project”<br>Anning Shares (002978.SZ) stated on the investor interaction platform on May 30 that the company’s fundamentals are good, cash flow is sufficient, and the asset-liability ratio is low. The company will always adhere to the prudent and stable business philosophy and adopt the strategy of “implementation in stages and dynamic adjustment”. At present, the company is going all out to promote the energy titanium project.</p><p>“China Nuclear Titanium Dioxide: Acquiring 50% Equity of China Nuclear Times with its Own Funds”<br>China Nuclear Titanium Dioxide (002145) (002145.SZ) issued an announcement on June 7, the company transferred its own funds of 977,900 yuan to Times Yongfu Technology Co., Ltd. Some have a 50% stake in Baiyin China Nuclear Times New Energy Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as “China Nuclear Times”). After the completion of this transaction, the company holds 100% of the equity of China Nuclear Times, and China Nuclear Times has become a wholly-owned subsidiary of the company.</p><p>Previously, in order to better implement the new requirements of the “dual carbon” goal and build a new green and circular economy, CNNC Titanium Dioxide and Times Yongfu signed the “Shareholders Agreement on the Establishment of a Joint Venture” on May 27, 2021. In the nuclear era, to promote the investment, construction and operation of comprehensive smart new energy projects such as photovoltaics, wind power, and energy storage. Among them, CNNC Titanium Dioxide and Times Yongfu subscribed for 50 million yuan respectively, each accounting for 50% of the registered capital of CNNC Times.</p><p>“Longbai Group develops efficiently and does a good job in extending, supplementing and strengthening the chain”<br>Longbai Group is in a period of rapid development. Since its successful listing in July 2011, the company has made two private placements, implemented equity incentives and employee stock ownership plans twice, and gave full play to its capital market advantages. In ten years, it has invested nearly 40 billion yuan in total. In project construction investment, product technology innovation and mergers and acquisitions, to help the rapid development of enterprises. Jiaozuo Park has built a 250,000-ton&#x2F;year sulfuric acid method titanium dioxide production line and a 400,000-ton&#x2F;year chloride method titanium dioxide production line, and implemented technological transformation and expansion. For the first time in 2021, the revenue will exceed 10 billion yuan; In the year of merger and acquisition, the production was resumed and the profit was made in the same year. At present, the production lines of chlorinated titanium dioxide and titanium sponge are in stable production, and the technological transformation and expansion are also progressing steadily. The company’s raw material base, the group will also make great efforts to increase investment, and spare no effort to carry out the investment and construction of extension chain and supplementary chain deep processing projects. In recent years, the average annual investment of the Group’s bases is about 4 billion to 5 billion yuan.</p><p>“Huiyun Titanium Industry Plans to Establish Three Subsidiaries to Expand Main Business Operations”<br>Huiyun Titanium Industry (300891) (300891.SZ) issued an announcement that in order to meet the needs of expanding main business operations and enhancing market competitiveness, the company plans to invest 10 million yuan (100% of the registered capital), establish a wholly-owned subsidiary Yunfu Huiyun Calcium Industry Co., Ltd.; plan to invest 10 million yuan (100% of the registered capital) to establish a wholly-owned subsidiary Yunfu Huiyun New Materials Co., Ltd.; It is proposed to invest 12 million yuan (60% of the registered capital); Yao Chuan, a natural person, will invest 8 million yuan (40% of the registered capital) to jointly establish a holding subsidiary Sichuan Yanyan Mining Co., Ltd.</p><p>The investment in the establishment of Huiyun Calcium Industry is mainly to produce calcium oxide to meet the needs of the company’s titanium dioxide production facilities and surrounding steel, chemical, environmental protection and other enterprises. The company invested in the establishment of Huiyun New Materials, under the background of the national “carbon peak” and “carbon neutral” policies and the rapid development of new energy technology, the company will use by-product waste acid, ferrous sulfate, etc. as iron phosphate. Produce raw materials, cut into the new energy iron phosphate industry, and realize the coupling of the titanium industry chain and the new energy industry chain. The investment in the establishment of Yanyan Mining is due to the intention of both parties to use their respective expertise and competitive advantages to jointly expand, integrate advantageous resources, and expand and strengthen related businesses, which is conducive to enhancing the company’s core competitiveness.</p><p>“Anning Shares: Bidding to Acquire 2.776% Equity of Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining”<br>Anning Co., Ltd. (002978) announced on the evening of June 22 that the company bid to obtain 2.776% equity of Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining Co., Ltd., and the final price was 140 million yuan. The target enterprise is one of the large vanadium-titanium magnetite mining and dressing enterprises in the Panxi region. The target enterprise completed and put into production in 2012 the mining and dressing scale of 3 million tons per year, and is currently actively applying for the mining right certificate of 10 million tons per year.</p><p>“Panshan Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium: The Company’s Comprehensive Energy Consumption of Titanium Dioxide Meets National Standards”<br>Panzhihua Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium (000629.SZ) stated on the investor interaction platform on June 21 that the company’s “2021 Panzhihua Iron and Steel Vanadium and Titanium ESG Report” comprehensively includes titanium dioxide The energy consumption of 1091.70Kgce&#x2F;t refers to the value of titanium dioxide by sulfuric acid method. According to the “Energy Consumption Limit of Titanium Dioxide Per Unit Product”, the comprehensive energy consumption of titanium dioxide of the company conforms to the national standard.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">1 Titanium Market Analysis
1.1. Market price analysis of titanium series
In June, the transaction price of Panxi Titanium Mine rose steadily. The cumulative increase of 46,10 mines was 30-50 yuan/ton, and the price of 38,42 mines rose by 30 yuan/ton at the end of the month. The prices of major manuf</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>In 2021, Sichuan&#39;s titanium concentrate production account for more than 90% of the country&#39;s</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/17/In-2021-Sichuan-s-titanium-concentrate-production-account-for-more-than-90-of-the-country-s/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/17/In-2021-Sichuan-s-titanium-concentrate-production-account-for-more-than-90-of-the-country-s/</id>
    <published>2022-06-17T02:53:46.783Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-17T03:08:08.815Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2021, the supply of titanium concentrate in Sichuan Province will reach a new high. The province’s annual output of titanium concentrate will reach 6.38 million tons, an increase of 460,000 tons or 8% year-on-year, accounting for more than 90% of the country’s total titanium concentrate.</p><p>The Panxi area of Sichuan Province is the main production base of titanium concentrate in my country. In 2021, Panzhihua City and Liangshan Prefecture contributed 5.3 million tons and 1.075 million tons of titanium concentrate respectively, providing solid raw materials for the development of my country’s titanium chemical industry and titanium metal industry. Assure. At the same time, Sichuan Province has formed an titanium concentrate industry cluster with Panzhihua Iron and Steel as the leader and LB Mining and Metallurgy, Anning Co., Ltd. and Chongqing Iron and Steel Xichang Mining as the backbone. Anning Co., Ltd. and Xichang Mining are the leading enterprises in the production of titanium concentrate with millions of tons, and they are the backbone enterprises in the supply of titanium concentrate in China.</p><p>Relying on its unique resource endowment and technological advantages, Sichuan Province has formed a whole industry chain of vanadium and titanium enterprises and industrial advantages represented by Panzhihua Iron and Steel Group, Longbai Group and Anning. Chemical and titanium production base.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">In 2021, the supply of titanium concentrate in Sichuan Province will reach a new high. The province’s annual output of titanium concentrate will reach 6.38 million tons, an increase of 460,000 tons or 8% year-on-year, accounting for more than 90% of the country’s total titanium concentrate.

The Pan</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="titanium concentrate production" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/titanium-concentrate-production/"/>
    
    <category term="sichuan&#39;s titanium" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/sichuan-s-titanium/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 market review of May 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/06/08/TiO2-market-review-of-May-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/06/08/TiO2-market-review-of-May-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-06-08T02:03:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-08T08:23:49.097Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In May, the Panxi titanium mine market was stable and weak, and the prices of small and medium-sized titanium mines continued to decline, ranging from 50-100 yuan&#x2F;ton. The prices of some large manufacturers fell by 50 yuan&#x2F;ton from the end of last month. The prices of small and medium-sized mines continued to decline in the first half of the month. The price is quite high; as of now, the price of 47 and 20 titanium ore in Panxi Dachang is 2400-2450 yuan&#x2F;ton, the transaction price of 46 and 10 titanium ore is around 2150 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the price of 38 and 42 ore excluding tax At 1500-1550 yuan &#x2F; ton; the downstream titanium dioxide market demand continues to be weak, the titanium ore market demand weakens, the orders of small and medium-sized manufacturers have decreased significantly, and the price has fallen; In the second half of the month, the inquiries and purchases of downstream enterprises increased, the confidence of small and medium-sized titanium ore manufacturers increased, and the miners were more willing to support prices; the price of raw ore remained stable at a high level, and the cost pressure of small and medium-sized mine manufacturers was relatively large, and the price of low-priced titanium ore rebounded slightly at the end of the month . The market demand for titanium dioxide is temporarily stable, and the overall supply of titanium ore is still tight. The prices of large manufacturers will remain stable in June, and the prices of small and medium manufacturers will also remain stable, and individual quotations may continue to rise.</p><p>The market price of imported titanium ore has remained stable. As of now, the price of Australian 50 titanium ore is 460 US dollars &#x2F; ton, the Kenmare 50 titanium ore price is 480 US dollars &#x2F; ton, Kenya 47-49 ore is temporarily not quoting, and Vietnam’s imported ore is not temporarily quoting; The demand for imported titanium ore in domestic and foreign markets continued to be strong, and the amount of imported titanium ore increased significantly in April. According to customs data, China imported 467,500 tons of titanium ore in April 2022, and the domestic production capacity of chlorinated slag and chlorinated titanium dioxide was gradually released. Market demand is also gradually increasing; at present, the supply of imported titanium ore continues to maintain a tense situation, and some prices have been slightly increased.</p><h2 id="Titanium-slag"><a href="#Titanium-slag" class="headerlink" title="Titanium slag"></a>Titanium slag</h2><p>The acid residue market is running weakly and steadily this month. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 6,060-6,250 yuan&#x2F;ton, and the ex-factory price including tax in Yunnan is 5,800-6,000 yuan&#x2F;ton. The downstream titanium dioxide market is weak, and the acid residue market is oversupplied. , the price has been under pressure, some small and medium-sized enterprises have made a small profit, and the mainstream price has remained basically stable; this month, with most acid residue enterprises in Yunnan reducing the operation, the supply and demand of the acid residue market is balanced, and the cost price is high and firm, the acid residue price is expected to continue. Hold steady.</p><p>The high slag market continued to rise in May. This month, the new tender price of ordinary high slag in the north was 10,400 yuan&#x2F;ton, up 200 yuan&#x2F;ton from the previous month. The downstream market demand of high slag continues to be strong, the inventory of manufacturers is not high, and the market supply is tight. In addition, the prices of raw materials and other materials continue to rise.</p><h2 id="Titanium-tetrachloride"><a href="#Titanium-tetrachloride" class="headerlink" title="Titanium tetrachloride"></a>Titanium tetrachloride</h2><p>This month, the market price of titanium tetrachloride has risen collectively, and the cost price has continued to rise. Titanium tetrachloride is under great pressure. At the beginning of the month, Longbai Group sent a letter to increase the price of titanium tetrachloride by 500 yuan&#x2F;ton. The titanium market quotation is 8,700-9,100 yuan &#x2F; ton; the cost price of raw materials and other materials remains high, coupled with the resumption of production and the release of new production capacity in the downstream sponge titanium market, the supply of titanium tetrachloride is tight, and the quotation rises; the price of titanium tetrachloride is high Enterprise profits have increased, some titanium tetrachloride manufacturers have resumed production, and the market supply and demand is balanced. It is expected that the price of titanium tetrachloride will remain stable.</p><h2 id="Titanium-dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium dioxide"></a>Titanium dioxide</h2><p>The titanium dioxide market improved in May. A total of five domestic companies sent letters to adjust prices, with an increase of 500-700 yuan &#x2F; ton. The international company Tenor issued a letter to increase the price by 200 US dollars &#x2F; ton since July 1; as of the end of this month, China The ex-factory price of rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 19,300-20,500 yuan &#x2F; ton, and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 17,800-18,500 yuan &#x2F; ton including tax; last month, factories that cut production and stopped production gradually resumed production, and the titanium dioxide market remains high; raw materials Titanium ore and sulfuric acid prices fluctuated at a high level, the overall pressure on titanium dioxide enterprises is still relatively large, and the cost price support is strong; the domestic demand market continues to be sluggish, titanium dioxide enterprises are under pressure to receive orders, and the market competition pressure is large; the foreign trade market remains good, according to customs The data shows that in April 2022, the export of titanium dioxide was 118,600 tons, a year-on-year increase of 10.64%. From January to April 2022, the cumulative export volume of titanium dioxide was 506,600 tons, an increase of 16.42% compared with the same period last year; the international market demand was temporarily stable, and the domestic market It will enter the traditional off-season, and the titanium dioxide market will continue to be strong in June.</p><h2 id="Sponge-titanium"><a href="#Sponge-titanium" class="headerlink" title="Sponge titanium"></a>Sponge titanium</h2><p>The market price of titanium sponge remained high in May. The current market price of titanium sponge is 74,000-85,000 yuan &#x2F; ton. The domestic and foreign market demand for titanium sponge is strong, the market supply is tight, and the inventory of manufacturers is not high. The export volume of titanium sponge in the international market in April There has been an increase, mainly due to the influence of Russia and Ukraine, and the shortage of titanium sponge resources in some countries; in June, the semi-process enterprises of titanium sponge will resume operation, and the new production capacity of other enterprises will be released, and the market supply of titanium sponge will continue to increase. Prices held steady.</p><p> June market forecast:</p><ol><li>The downstream demand is weak and stable, the cost is firm, and the price of titanium ore is stable;</li><li>The market demand for titanium dioxide is sluggish, and the market will continue to operate weakly;</li><li>The market supply of sponge titanium will increase, and the price will be firm.</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">In May, the Panxi titanium mine market was stable and weak, and the prices of small and medium-sized titanium mines continued to decline, ranging from 50-100 yuan/ton. The prices of some large manufacturers fell by 50 yuan/ton from the end of last month. The prices of small and medium-sized mines co</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Market overview on the first week of April, 1st-7th, April</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/Market-overview-on-the-first-week-of-April-1st-7th-April/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/Market-overview-on-the-first-week-of-April-1st-7th-April/</id>
    <published>2022-04-11T07:57:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-11T08:14:13.391Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Ore"><a href="#Titanium-Ore" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Ore"></a>Titanium Ore</h2><p>This week, the transaction price of small and medium titanium ore market fell slightly. Up to now, the transaction price of small and medium-sized titanium ore 46,10 is 2300-2350 yuan / ton, 47,20 ore is quoted at 2450-2550 yuan / ton, 38,42 titanium ore is quoted at 2450-2550 yuan / ton The quotation excluding tax is 1550-1600 yuan / ton; recently, the titanium ore market in Panxi area has been deserted, and the downstream titanium dioxide market demand has decreased, and the cost pressure of enterprises is relatively high. There is no pressure on the inventory of small mines and large factories, and some small factories are under great inventory pressure, reducing production and running, and the titanium ore market is under-operated. The market price of titanium ore in Yunnan and Chengde areas remained stable, the market transaction atmosphere was not high, and the market price of titanium ore remained strong.</p><p>The market price of imported titanium ore is stable at a high level. As of now, the price of Australian titanium ore is 450 US dollars / ton, the price of Kenmare 50 titanium ore is 450 US dollars / ton, Kenya 47-49 mine is temporarily not quoting, and Vietnam’s imported ore is not temporarily quoting; The supply of titanium raw materials in the international market continues to be tight, the supply of titanium ore in international titanium dioxide factories is insufficient, the transaction price is high, and the supply of domestic imported ore is scarce, and the market price remains high.</p><h2 id="Titanium-slag"><a href="#Titanium-slag" class="headerlink" title="Titanium slag"></a>Titanium slag</h2><p>This week, the high-titanium slag market maintained stable operation. The new tender price of high-titanium slag ordinary slag in the north was 9,900 yuan/ton, and the quotation for low-calcium-magnesium high-slag slag was more than 11,000 yuan/ton; , manufacturers mainly deliver pre-orders; downstream market demand is temporarily stable, some companies have tight supply of high-slag raw materials, and high-slag market quotations remain high.</p><p>The acid residue market is running stably. As of now, the ex-factory price including tax in Sichuan is 6060-6250 yuan/ton, and the ex-factory price including tax in Yunnan is 6,000 yuan/ton. The cost pressure of enterprises is relatively large; recently, the downstream titanium dioxide market has been under-operated, the market demand for acid residue has been reduced, and the market price of acid residue has remained stable.</p><h2 id="Titanium-dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium dioxide"></a>Titanium dioxide</h2><p>The titanium dioxide market is running steadily, and the overall market has not changed much. As of now, the ex-factory price of China’s rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 19,800-21,500 yuan/ton(3120 to 3400USD/MT), and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 18,500-19,500 yuan/ton(2920USD to 3080USD/MT).     The price of raw and auxiliary materials is high, the cost of titanium dioxide is still high, the pressure on enterprises is high, and the price of titanium dioxide is temporarily stable; the domestic market demand is weak, the downstream enterprises maintain rigid demand, and the transaction of new orders in the market is deserted; the current market transportation is still limited, and some manufacturers have high inventories , manufacturers reduce load production, individual enterprises are in a state of shutdown, and the titanium dioxide market is under-operated. The demand in the international market remains good, and the support for domestic titanium dioxide enterprises is strong. In addition, due to the impact of high-level raw materials, it is expected that the titanium dioxide market will maintain stable operation in the short term.</p><h2 id="Sulfuric-acid"><a href="#Sulfuric-acid" class="headerlink" title="Sulfuric acid"></a>Sulfuric acid</h2><p>This week, the domestic sulfuric acid market has been stable and small, and the market price has risen and fallen. As of now, the price of 98% smelting acid in Inner Mongolia is 500-820 yuan / ton, and the price of 98% smelting acid in Yunnan is 1000-1100 yuan / ton. The price of 98% smelting acid in Shandong is 920-1000 yuan / ton; this week, the acid price in Inner Mongolia, Northeast China and other regions has risen significantly, mainly due to the maintenance of the main acid plants in the region. The supply in the region is tight, and the price has increased; Compensation, due to the low acid price in the previous period, the acid price also increased significantly this week. In addition, due to the control of the epidemic, many acid plants were not transported smoothly, and the number of downstream companies that stopped and reduced production increased. The market supply and demand were both weak. Some acid plants made a profit due to inventory pressure.</p><h2 id="Market-outlook-forecast"><a href="#Market-outlook-forecast" class="headerlink" title="Market outlook forecast:"></a>Market outlook forecast:</h2><ol><li>The cost pressure of downstream titanium dioxide is relatively large, new orders of titanium ore are reduced, and the titanium ore market is running in a stalemate;</li><li>The cost of raw materials is high, and the market price of titanium dioxide is running on a solid ground;</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Ore
This week, the transaction price of small and medium titanium ore market fell slightly. Up to now, the transaction price of small and medium-sized titanium ore 46,10 is 2300-2350 yuan / ton, 47,20 ore is quoted at 2450-2550 yuan / ton, 38,42 titanium ore is quoted at 2450-2550 yuan / to</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The epidemic has repeatedly blocked logistics. How much is the cost of logistics enterprises?</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/The-epidemic-has-repeatedly-blocked-logistics-How-much-is-the-cost-of-logistics-enterprises/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/The-epidemic-has-repeatedly-blocked-logistics-How-much-is-the-cost-of-logistics-enterprises/</id>
    <published>2022-04-11T03:40:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-11T03:53:20.311Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Xinhua Finance, Shanghai, April 10 (Reporter Yang Youzong) The reporter saw in the Waigaoqiao area of ​​Pudong New District, Shanghai a few days ago that many container trucks were parked end to end on both sides of the road. These truck drivers can be as short as three to five days, or as long as they have no work to do for a week or two. Due to the control of the epidemic, it was difficult for some truck drivers to leave Shanghai, and the business volume shrank.</p></blockquote><p>The stranded truck drivers are a microcosm of the logistics obstruction caused by the epidemic. Since the current round of the epidemic, prevention and control measures have been upgraded in many places, and the travel of residents and the flow of goods have been affected to some extent. According to industry analysis, normalized prevention and control policies will increase the cost pressure of logistics enterprises, and will also make logistics industry practitioners face greater uncertainty.</p><p>The logistics system of truck drivers stranded is affected</p><p>In the Waigaoqiao area of ​​Pudong New District, Shanghai, the reporter saw trucks with Shanghai E, Shanghai F and Su E license plates parked on the side of the road on Gangjian Road, Shendong Road and other roads. Go to bed, or make phone calls anxiously.</p><p>The driver Guo Liutao, a native of Shenqiu County, Zhoukou City, Henan Province, is 32 years old this year. He has been working as a truck driver for two years, and usually runs the Yangtze River Delta route. “I stopped in Shanghai on April 3, and it has been 4 days now. I have food and lodging in the car. I haven’t worked for 4 days. It turned out to be more than 200 yuan for one trip a day. Now I can’t make any money. The boss doesn’t make any money either.”</p><p>Shanghai has one of the busiest ports in the world. Data show that in 2021, the container throughput of Shanghai Port will exceed 47 million TEUs, ranking first in the world for 12 consecutive years. Shanghai Port Group announced on April 2 that according to internal data monitoring, the current operation of Shanghai Port is stable and orderly, and the berthing efficiency of Shanghai Port is significantly better than the overall level in 2021. Since March 28, the average waiting time of container ships in Shanghai Port has been less than 24 hours, and the average waiting time has been less than 10 ships. SIPG emphasized that the production and operation of the terminal are normal, and there is no congestion of container ships.</p><p>Although terminal operations have not been affected, the reporter learned that under the epidemic prevention and control, the container transshipment system has been greatly affected, and inter-provincial transportation has been greatly affected.</p><p>Liu Min, deputy director of the Shanghai Municipal Commission of Commerce, said, “Shanghai is indeed facing some difficulties in ensuring the supply of living materials, such as the lack of smooth inter-provincial logistics due to the impact of the epidemic, and the lack of terminal capacity resulting in delayed delivery. We are working hard to get through with the support of all parties. Blocking points, solving difficulties, and trying to ensure the basic living needs of citizens during the epidemic.”</p><p><img src="/2022/04/11/The-epidemic-has-repeatedly-blocked-logistics-How-much-is-the-cost-of-logistics-enterprises/1.jpeg"><br>(The epidemic prevention seal on the collection card taken on April 7. Photo by Xinhua Finance reporter Yang Youzong)</p><p>On a Shanghai D license plate collection card in the Waigaoqiao area of ​​Shanghai, the reporter saw that a seal was pasted next to the driver’s cab, and the seal was signed as “Nantong Tongzhou District Traffic Port Prevention and Control Team”.</p><p>A driver said that many places are now unable to get off the high-speed, and the pass does not work, and some places do not recognize it . “Some drivers will not let them go to Jiangsu and Zhejiang, and can only pull the goods back.”</p><p>The driver, Zhang Chaohua, said that on April 1, he drove a pickup truck to a certain place in Jiangsu, where he queued from 7 am to 12 pm, but was told before getting off the expressway that the Shanghai license plate could not get off the expressway, so he had to go back the same way. .</p><p>Strict policies are behind the continuous tightening of epidemic prevention and control policies. On April 5 and April 6, Ningbo, Zhejiang reported 8 cases of infections related to road freight, including truck drivers, long-distance freight drivers, and gas station staff in high-speed service areas. After tracing the source of the flow, the trajectories of the cases focus on high-speed exits and high-speed service areas, especially restaurants, shower rooms, toilets, gas stations and other places in the high-speed service areas.</p><h2 id="The-cost-pressure-of-logistics-enterprises-will-increase"><a href="#The-cost-pressure-of-logistics-enterprises-will-increase" class="headerlink" title="The cost pressure of logistics enterprises will increase"></a>The cost pressure of logistics enterprises will increase</h2><p>The repeated outbreak of the epidemic will have a greater impact on the express logistics industry. Beginning in early March this year, affected by the epidemic in many parts of the country, some transit centers and outlets were closed, and express delivery in many places was interrupted in stages. Some e-commerce platforms also experienced delivery delays and suspensions.</p><p>According to a research report released by Sinolink Securities on April 5, the epidemic is expected to have a greater impact on express delivery services, and the volume of express delivery business is expected to decline.</p><p>Data from the State Post Bureau shows that the volume of express delivery business in March is expected to drop by 2.5% year-on-year, and the revenue of express delivery business is expected to drop by 4.4% year-on-year. The industry entered the off-season in March, and the price side remained stable.</p><p>The impact of the epidemic may disrupt the growth pace of the express delivery business in the early stage. Prior to this, the performance of many express delivery companies has entered the cashing period.</p><p>The main operating data released by YTO from January to February 2022 shows that its express delivery business completed 2.297 billion tickets, a year-on-year increase of 27.81%; the operating income was about 7.624 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 39.28%; the net profit attributable to the parent was about 545 million yuan. , a year-on-year increase of 186.36%.</p><p>According to the annual report of SF Holding, in the fourth quarter of 2021, the profit was 2.471 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 43.01%, and the non-net profit after deduction was 1.501 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 46.07%.</p><p>Guosen Securities analyst Jiang Ming said that it is estimated that in the past two to three weeks, the epidemic has caused the business volume of the express delivery industry to decrease by 10% to 20% compared with usual. At the same time, considering the impact of the reduced business volume on the allocation of fixed costs, it is expected that the short-term profits of express companies will be affected by The negative impact outweighs the business volume. However, the impact of the epidemic is one-off, and the short-term express demand is more suppressed rather than disappeared. Therefore, it believes that after the epidemic resumes, express demand is expected to rebound. “Considering that the profits of leading express delivery companies will be greatly restored this year, the current valuation is relatively cheap, and we continue to recommend leading express delivery companies.”</p><h2 id="The-global-logistics-supply-chain-continues-to-be-impacted"><a href="#The-global-logistics-supply-chain-continues-to-be-impacted" class="headerlink" title="The global logistics supply chain continues to be impacted"></a>The global logistics supply chain continues to be impacted</h2><p>The poor transportation of containers has affected the production and circulation of some enterprises. A person in charge of a company in Pudong said that the current circulation system is not smooth, and even if the company produces products, it is not easy to ship out, so the downtime is simply extended.</p><p>Wang Hai, editor-in-chief of the shipping industry network and an analyst in the shipping industry, said that although terminal operations have not been affected, the closure and control measures will have a certain impact on truck transportation and container turnover, which may lead to some container companies to take corresponding adjustment measures.</p><p><img src="/2022/04/11/The-epidemic-has-repeatedly-blocked-logistics-How-much-is-the-cost-of-logistics-enterprises/2.jpeg"><br>(A pickup truck parked in the Waigaoqiao area of ​​Pudong New District, Shanghai on April 7. Photo by Xinhua Finance reporter Yang Youzong)</p><p>Maersk, a container shipping company, stated on its official website that at present, Shanghai ports such as Yangshan Port and Waigaoqiao Port are still operating normally, but the warehouses in the closed area have been seriously affected, and the efficiency of Maersk’s freight services to and from Shanghai will also be further affected. Maersk said it will provide multimodal transport services by barge and rail as an alternative to transport between Shanghai and nearby cities.</p><p>Wang Ling, an analyst at East Asia Qianhai Securities, said that the lack of shipping capacity in the container industry has pushed up freight rates. In 2021, under the influence of multiple factors such as repeated COVID-19 epidemics, increased transportation demand, and limited supply of transportation capacity, the global logistics supply chain will continue to be challenged and impacted by complex situations such as port congestion, container shortages, and inland transportation delays, and the supply and demand relationship of container transportation will continue to be tense. . The container and dry bulk cargo industry already has the advantage of scale under the tight transportation capacity, and the leading enterprises in the global route are expected to benefit.</p><p>The epidemic has brought a new shock to the gradually recovering economy, and the impact may extend throughout the first half of the year, as demand recovery and expected improvement will take time. Sheng Songcheng, executive vice president of the CEIBS Lujiazui Institute of International Finance, wrote in an article that as the epidemic is repeated in China’s core cities , the spillover effect of the epidemic will be more obvious. We should pay close attention to weak links in the economy, stabilize employment, protect people’s livelihood, and promote consumption. Continue to rationally relax real estate regulation from the demand side. Take infrastructure investment as an important starting point for stabilizing growth. Fiscal policy should be more proactive. Monetary policy should now pay more attention to the use of quantitative tools.</p><p>“In fixed asset investment, infrastructure investment is more controllable, which can promote economic stabilization and improve market expectations in a relatively short period of time. Therefore, infrastructure investment is still an important starting point for stable growth this year, and under the impact of the epidemic, Infrastructure investment will play a more important role.” Sheng Songcheng said.</p><p>Statement: Xinhua Finance is a national financial information platform constructed by Xinhua News Agency. The information published on this platform does not constitute investment advice under any circumstances.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>@新华财经</strong><cite><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1729770818365244932&wfr=spider&for=pc">baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1729770818365244932&wfr=spider&for=pc</a></cite></footer></blockquote><blockquote><footer><strong>@GoogleTranslate</strong><cite><a href="https://baijiahao-baidu-com.translate.goog/s?id=1729770818365244932&wfr=spider&for=pc&_x_tr_sl=zh-CN&_x_tr_tl=en&_x_tr_hl=en&_x_tr_pto=wapp">baijiahao-baidu-com.translate.goog/s?id=1729770818365244932&wfr=spider&for=pc&_x_tr_sl=zh-CN&_x_tr_tl=en&_x_tr_hl=en&_x_tr_pto=wapp</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Xinhua Finance, Shanghai, April 10 (Reporter Yang Youzong) The reporter saw in the Waigaoqiao area of ​​Pudong New District, Shanghai a few days ago that many container trucks were parked end to end on both sides of the road. These truck drivers can be as short as three to five days, or as long as t</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Logistics" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Logistics/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Shanghai Lockdown" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Shanghai-Lockdown/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Truck driver Shanghai rafting</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/Truck-driver-Shanghai-rafting/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/04/11/Truck-driver-Shanghai-rafting/</id>
    <published>2022-04-11T03:12:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-11T03:36:40.225Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Some truck drivers were trapped in Shanghai for delivering supplies, some were blocked on highways, and some were quarantined at home because they had just returned to a medium-high-risk place. They are only one link in the construction of the logistics economy - the huge logistics chain is undergoing an unprecedented major test.</p></blockquote><p>Master Wei was wearing blue slippers and walking in the middle of the road. There were no moving cars on the road, nor could he hear any traffic or whistles. Every time he took a step, he could hear the rubbing of slippers and pebbles on the ground. The crickets in the open space on the side are also very lively. If you listen carefully, you can even find a few frog calls from the sound of the crickets.</p><p>This is the 12th day that Master Wei stayed in Shanghai, and the first night he moved to the roadside of Jingdong Road, Minhang District, Shanghai.</p><p>On March 28, Master Wei and two other truck drivers drove three vehicles, carrying nearly 100 tons of potatoes, from Laiwu, Jinan, to Shanghai. The plan of the three of Master Wei is to arrive in Shanghai in the early morning of the 29th, and after pulling the goods to the designated vegetable wholesale market, they will unload the truck and return, and they will be able to go home after two or three days.</p><p>However, this plan came to an abrupt end after arriving in Shanghai in the early morning of the 29th.</p><p>“The 29th is still normal, the 30th is basically half blocked, and the 31st is basically closed.” Master Wei told “Chinese Entrepreneurs”.</p><p>In the past, Master Wei also often traveled to Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai, but most of them were general goods such as construction site building materials and raw materials. This was the first time he shipped vegetables to Shanghai.</p><p>“This Shanghai epidemic, there are fewer people pulling food here, and the shipping fee is a little higher, so we came here.” Master Wei told us that the shipping fee is about 2,000 yuan higher than before. Usually, there is no free high-speed fee when going to Shanghai. One round trip can earn more than 3,000 yuan, and this time, it can earn more than 5,000 yuan.</p><h5 id="Like-the-flow-of-water-in-a-high-pressure-water-gun-the-truck-drivers-are-a-group-of-invisible-beings-They-circulate-on-highways-all-over-the-world-and-get-paid-by-settlement-From-the-departure-point-to-the-destination-they-pass-through-one-highway-intersection-and-service-area-one-after-another-In-the-ETC-era-they-don’t-even-have-to-meet-the-staff-of-the-artificial-window-Fast-through-toll-booths-in-minutes-Occasionally-encountering-toll-booths-that-require-manual-ticket-sales-they-just-roll-down-the-windows-hand-over-the-money-and-get-the-tickets-back-All-they-do-is-mileage-speed-and-destination"><a href="#Like-the-flow-of-water-in-a-high-pressure-water-gun-the-truck-drivers-are-a-group-of-invisible-beings-They-circulate-on-highways-all-over-the-world-and-get-paid-by-settlement-From-the-departure-point-to-the-destination-they-pass-through-one-highway-intersection-and-service-area-one-after-another-In-the-ETC-era-they-don’t-even-have-to-meet-the-staff-of-the-artificial-window-Fast-through-toll-booths-in-minutes-Occasionally-encountering-toll-booths-that-require-manual-ticket-sales-they-just-roll-down-the-windows-hand-over-the-money-and-get-the-tickets-back-All-they-do-is-mileage-speed-and-destination" class="headerlink" title="Like the flow of water in a high-pressure water gun, the truck drivers are a group of invisible beings. They circulate on highways all over the world, and get paid by settlement. From the departure point to the destination, they pass through one highway intersection and service area one after another. In the ETC era, they don’t even have to meet the staff of the artificial window. Fast through toll booths in minutes. Occasionally encountering toll booths that require manual ticket sales, they just roll down the windows, hand over the money, and get the tickets back. All they do is mileage, speed and destination."></a><font color=red>Like the flow of water in a high-pressure water gun, the truck drivers are a group of invisible beings. They circulate on highways all over the world, and get paid by settlement. From the departure point to the destination, they pass through one highway intersection and service area one after another. In the ETC era, they don’t even have to meet the staff of the artificial window. Fast through toll booths in minutes. Occasionally encountering toll booths that require manual ticket sales, they just roll down the windows, hand over the money, and get the tickets back. All they do is mileage, speed and destination.</font></h5><p><font color=red>Now, high-pressure water guns are turned into untightened faucets.</font></p><p>On April 8, Hangzhou issued a “Notice on Temporary Closure of Passage Measures at Some Expressway Toll Stations in Hangzhou”. 24 hour closing measures. It is understood that Hangzhou has closed 13 expressway toll stations including the Yuanpu exit of the Ring Expressway, the Huanghu exit of the Hangzhou-Changzhou Expressway, and the Zhangjiafan (in front of the institute) exit of the Hangjinqu Expressway.</p><p>In addition to Hangzhou, Shanxi, Shaoxing, Huainan, Hefei, Kunshan, Suqian, Xuzhou, Taizhou, Qingdao, Xi’an, Jinzhou, Shenyang and many other places have successively issued similar announcements, that is, due to the needs of epidemic prevention and control, some local expressways will be temporarily closed. toll. In addition to the closure of some expressways, Zhongshan, Hangzhou and other places have also issued notices to strengthen the management of epidemic prevention and control of truck drivers.</p><p><font color=red>Some truck drivers were trapped in Shanghai for delivering supplies, some were blocked on highways, and some were quarantined at home because they had just returned to a medium-high-risk place.</font> They are only one link in the construction of the logistics economy - the huge logistics chain is undergoing an unprecedented major test.</p><h5 id="After-being-trapped-for-12-days-use-potatoes-to-count-the-days"><a href="#After-being-trapped-for-12-days-use-potatoes-to-count-the-days" class="headerlink" title="After being trapped for 12 days, use potatoes to count the days"></a>After being trapped for 12 days, use potatoes to count the days</h5><p>“This is our car, this is the stove we use to make the fire, and this is the broken wood picked up from other people’s construction sites.” Master Wei showed us his current living area one by one - an open-air kitchen on the sidewalk.</p><p>The place where Master Wei builds a fire and eats. Source: Respondents</p><p>The stove was remodeled from a paint bucket, and a large square was cut at the bottom. In order to make the pot stand and keep it stable, the mouth of the bucket was shaped like a petal. After several days of use, the interior of this remodeled stove has been smoked black, and the white paint stains on the outside have turned yellow.</p><p>The 39-year-old Master Wei is from Jining, Shandong Province. He speaks fast and expresses directly. When introducing this open-air kitchen, he kicked the item being introduced. I don’t know that this is an attempt to make us see more clearly and intuitively. , I still have grievances about this pot and this stove - during this period of time in Shanghai, I ate two meals a day, and most of the time I ate boiled potatoes in water.</p><p>After the three of them arrived in Shanghai with nearly 100 tons of potatoes, they did not expect the vegetable market to be closed. So, who to give these potatoes to, how to unload them, and where should they go during this time have become problems.</p><p>This batch of potatoes was bought by Boss Xia in Shandong, and Master Wei took the order. Master Wei has been driving a truck for more than ten years. In the past, he drove a 6-meter-8 trolley. Three years ago, he replaced it with the current 13-meter-long trailer. This truck is full of more than 30 tons of potatoes.</p><p>On March 29, after learning about the closure of the vegetable market, Master Wei and his party were arranged to be in a warehouse rented by Boss Xia. This warehouse is located in Minhang District, Shanghai, next to Shanghai Hongqiao Airport. It is an Audi warehouse. The restaurants, supermarkets, and shops here have all closed, and you can only rely on yourself to eat and drink.</p><p>On the afternoon of April 7, Master Wei and his party stopped at a warehouse in Minhang District, waiting for the last truck of potatoes to be unloaded. Source: Respondents</p><p>In the first two days of arriving in Shanghai, Master Wei and his party still had some stored food, but the three adult men had three meals a day, and they ate them in three or four days. On April 3, Boss Xia entrusted two handfuls of noodles, oil and salt to be delivered. At that time, they had already eaten up their own stored food, so they began to eat this batch of potatoes shipped from Shandong, which was boiled without oil. Eat, you can fry and eat when there is oil.</p><p>On the afternoon of April 7, on the 10th day of being trapped in Shanghai, Mr. Wei’s potatoes in his car were all sold out, and there were still a whole carload of potatoes in the car of his friends, some of which were about to sprout. On the night of the 11th day of being trapped, nearly 100 tons of potatoes were sold out in three trucks.</p><p>“It didn’t work in the first few days. There were only a few boxes of goods a day, and it didn’t even move for a few days. It was better when it arrived on the sixth or seventh day. It was more than 100 boxes for a pull.” Master Wei said.</p><p>In the early morning of the 12th day of being trapped, Boss Xia withdrew from the warehouse, and they drove to the road more than 20 kilometers away from the warehouse, waiting for the lockdown to be lifted. Boss Xia, who never showed up, left two boxes of potatoes for Master Wei and the others, about 100 pounds in total, and some noodles.</p><p>“There aren’t many noodles, so we’ll eat it sparingly.” Now the three eat twice a day, the first at around 10 am and the second at around 3 pm. Judging from the current food, Master Wei estimates that it is about It can last six or seven days.</p><p>There are more than three people trapped in this Audi warehouse at the same time as Master Wei. Master Wei introduced that Boss Xia is from Anhui, and Boss Xia’s fellow villagers also pulled two trucks of goods and entered Shanghai at this special point, but they started from Hefei. During the waiting period, the number of drivers stranded here changed from 3 to 5, but we didn’t communicate much, just chatting occasionally.</p><p>In fact, Master Wei and other truck drivers have tried various channels to apply for a pass. <font color=red>“A friend who can apply for a pass in the circle of friends is just joking, and no one can get a pass for Shanghai. “</font></p><p>“My wife is on the phone with me every day, and it’s useless to worry.” When asking questions about family members, Master Wei’s speech rate will slow down. There are 6 people in Master Wei’s family. He is the pillar of the family and the main source of income for the whole family.</p><p>“We don’t know when we can go back.” Master Wei told us when contacted again on the evening of the 9th.</p><p><font color=red>On the afternoon of April 8, we called Boss Xia to learn more about the situation. He told us that he has been taken to the makeshift hospital, and it is inconvenient to disclose other things. </font>Master Wei told us that after eating potatoes for two or three days, Boss Xia was quarantined - Master Wei had already started counting the days when he went home with potatoes.</p><p>A Fantastic Drift of an Auto Parts Sample<br>About ten kilometers away from Master Wei, Liu Ronghui (pseudonym), who is located in Shanghai Pudong New Area, is isolated at home. This is the 17th day of his detention, and it is unknown how many days he is working from home.</p><p>“As a dead fat house, I didn’t lose weight by exercising every day. This time, I kept it at home, giving non-staple food to the elderly and children, and giving snacks to my wife. I went out to volunteer from time to time to help, and I lost 8 pounds…”</p><p>Where can I buy in groups, and where can I grab food? How to stabilize my daughter when her homework is decreasing day by day? How to answer the customer’s urging, how to online, as much as possible to ensure the supply? For nearly a month, these three questions have plagued him alternately.</p><p><font color=red>“I have used all my papering skills in my life, but I am still riddled with holes.” </font> Liu Ronghui told us. (Note: The paper craftsman was originally a paper-paper worker. Li Hongzhang also mocked himself as a paper-paper craftsman. Later, this statement was gradually extended in East China. There were beautification and patchwork, but there was no way to solve the core problem. mean.)</p><p>After 1985, Liu Ronghui worked for a well-known parts manufacturer in Shanghai, with customers all over the world. “Basically all mainstream car companies use my parts.” Liu Ronghui said.</p><p>On March 14, Pinghu City, Zhejiang Province issued a notice to initiate a Level I emergency response. From now on, the city will completely suspend work, business, school, public places, and crowd gathering activities. At the same time, strict transportation control measures will be adopted throughout the city.</p><p>In this case, the companies involved in the region will stop production, and the inter-provincial logistics and express delivery will also stop. However, the new project samples in charge of Liu Ronghui need to be assembled and sent from the factory in Pinghu.</p><p>Pinghu City is a county-level city hosted by Jiaxing City, Zhejiang Province, next to Shanghai, where many world-renowned multinational companies, global industry leaders, chain-owner companies and benchmarking companies gather here. Automobiles, high-end machine tools and new materials are the advantages here. industry.</p><p>According to the “China Economic Times” report: Pinghu City leverages the strong chain extension of the automobile industry with “chain master” enterprises. There are 272 auto parts companies, including 8 of the top 100 global auto parts companies such as ABB in Switzerland, GKN in the United Kingdom, and Lear in the United States. They have formed a complete industrial chain supporting capability of “production of the whole car in Pinghu”, and are associated with auto parts every year. The production capacity is more than 5 million units. At present, Great Wall Motors has more than 50 supporting enterprises in Pinghu. <font color=red> It is reported that Pinghu has become one of the largest new energy drive motor production bases in the country. The total output value of the automobile industry chain is expected to exceed 50 billion yuan within two years, and will reach a scale of 100 billion yuan in five years.</font></p><p>“The car is not allowed to go directly to Shanghai.” Because the sealed samples cannot be sent directly to customers in other regions, and the trucks that customers collect goods cannot pick up the goods, Liu Ronghui’s “paper pasting” skills have been inspired.</p><p>“First, I found a way to find a customer with a temporary correspondence certificate, took the samples out of the urban area, and sent a special car to the customer after thinking of the transit warehouse in Jiaxing City. I didn’t expect the logistics company there to say that it would not accept the order to Shanghai. The reason is very It’s simple, the return trip from Shanghai will require 14-day quarantine.” <font color=red>Faced with this situation, Liu Ronghui could only arrange a special logistics vehicle to the brother factory in Changzhou, Jiangsu, and then let other customers’ logistics vehicles that have not left Pinghu take the samples away. Completely bypasses Shanghai.</font></p><p>On the evening of March 18, the samples finally arrived in Changzhou. But what made Liu Ronghui feel devastated was that a notice was issued on the same day, saying that 19 daily states would also have 3 days of closure and control management and nucleic acid of all staff.</p><p>“The mood at that time was like a refugee who escaped from Hiroshima to Nagasaki in 1945.” Liu Ronghui said.</p><p>Fortunately, the samples finally arrived in the hands of the customer. After seeing the news of the closure and control, major OEMs rushed to Changzhou before 24:00 on the 18th, towed away all the finished product inventory that could be towed away by the supplier, and took samples along the way. .</p><p>“The industrial belt is going crazy. The Yangtze River Delta and the Pearl River Delta are the main suppliers. The mainland of Changchun is an ecu supplier. Changchun has been closed for almost a month. It’s gone.” Liu Ronghui said.</p><p>Companies such as Tesla and Weilai have been affected.</p><p>On March 28, according to Reuters , Tesla plans to suspend the production activities of its super factory in Shanghai from March 28 for 4 days due to the impact of Shanghai’s epidemic prevention policy. Bloomberg also previously reported that Tesla’s Shanghai plant will stop production for at least one day starting on Monday (March 28).</p><p>On April 8, Guotai Junan Futures wrote in a research report: Affected by the epidemic, the production of 550,000 tons of polyester bottle flakes in East China has recently been reduced to around 70%. Affected by the epidemic and logistics, some major polyester industrial yarn factories have reduced their production load or even stopped production this week, such as Yufu, Jinhuite and Wenlong have stopped production, and the load of Sunway and Sunfull has increased slightly. July 7), the overall theoretical start-up load of domestic polyester industrial yarn dropped to about 63%. In addition, Hilead’s current operating load is temporarily maintained, but the Haining area is controlled by the epidemic and cannot enter or leave the logistics. If there are not enough raw and auxiliary materials for Hilead and the logistics has not resumed, production must be reduced and stopped.</p><p>On April 9, NIO issued a “Note on Recent Production and Delivery”. NIO said that since March, due to the epidemic, the company’s supply chain partners in Jilin, Shanghai, Jiangsu and other places have successively stopped production. It has not been restored yet. Affected by this, Weilai’s vehicle production has been suspended.</p><p>Weilai said that the delivery of many users’ vehicles will be delayed in the near future. “I also ask for your understanding. The company will work with supply chain partners to resume production as soon as possible and deliver vehicles to everyone as soon as possible on the premise of meeting the requirements of epidemic prevention.”</p><p>Drivers become in short supply “materials”<br>As long as it can be delivered, regardless of the cost and transportation needs that do not consider the timeliness, logistics companies are also “papering”.</p><p>On April 3, Gaopeng received a notice in the tenant communication group in the park. The notice reads: According to the spirit of the “Kunshan Epidemic Prevention and Control Announcement No. 24 in 2022”, each company will take a silent break from April 3 to April 6, and employees of the company will return to their place of residence to participate in regional nucleic acid testing.</p><p>Gao Peng is the head of Huayuan World Logistics. The company is located in German Industrial Park, Zhangpu Town, Kunshan. Many precision machinery companies have settled in this park, such as Eisenmann China Automobile Assembly Line Production Base, Berger Precision Machinery Parts (Kunshan) Co., Ltd.; Jiangsu Changjiang Water Pump Co., Ltd.; and many logistics companies, such as DHL (Sinotrans) DHL).</p><p>It is understood that Kunshan is a major production center for PCB, electronic foundry, panels, and notebook computer components. Nandian, Xinxing, AUO, Visionox, Longteng Optoelectronics, Shishuo, Compal, and Luxshare have factories in the area. . The main customers of Huayuan Tianxia Logistics are mostly electronic components, packaging consumables and mold products from nearby factories.</p><p>“It hasn’t stopped since the New Year.” After seeing the notice, Gao Peng complained inwardly. But Tucao returned to Tucao, and the movements in his hands did not stop. Before the silence time came, Gao Peng and the others packed up the things that should be packed, and some colleagues who had come from Suzhou went back to Suzhou. It is understood that Huayuan World Logistics has two offices, one in Suzhou and the other in Kunshan.</p><p>“Not long after the New Year, there was an epidemic in Suzhou. After Suzhou, Shanghai came out, and then there were sporadic epidemics in Hangzhou and Zhejiang, which have always been around us.” Gao Peng concluded with a wry smile.</p><p>Master Gao is one of the hired drivers of Huayuan World Logistics. Unlike Master Wei, he is not personally affiliated. He is currently isolated at home and can still get the basic salary from the company.</p><p>On March 9, Master Gao received a notice from the community and asked him to isolate at home because he went to Shanghai once at the end of February and has never been to Shanghai since. Now, this is the second time he has been quarantined because of the epidemic in Kunshan itself, and the quarantine period starts on April 1.</p><p>“Since the outbreak of the epidemic, I have been in quarantine almost all the time, and I haven’t run much in the past two months. A colleague ran for a few days last month and has been in isolation.” Master Gao also told us that the company’s Kunshan side There are also seven or eight drivers, all of whom are in home quarantine.</p><p>A suitable driver has become a shortage of “materials”.</p><p>“For example, when you go to Henan, as long as you enter Henan, the green code will turn yellow (code). Henan is right in the middle of China, and many people who travel from south to north have to pass through Henan.” Gao Peng told us that after the epidemic in Shanghai became serious, Corresponding strict control measures have been issued in many places. These measures have become a sieve, and there are not many drivers who can stay.</p><p>In order to ensure the smooth passage of living materials, the green pass issued by Henan Province. Source: Respondents</p><p>Gao Peng told “Chinese Entrepreneurs” that many older drivers have a junior high school degree, or even less than a junior high school degree. It is very difficult to get a driver’s license. How to smoothly switch and use the health codes of various cities when crossing provinces and cities is a “threshold”.</p><p>“For example, from Nanjing to Suzhou, Suzhou has the code of Suzhou, and Nanjing has the code of Nanjing. They may not be able to get it when they are old, but this must be done by themselves.” Gao Peng explained, “The isolation of isolation, the yellow code I can’t run, and it will take several days to change back for the next job, and those who don’t know how to use these health codes, the transport vehicles are seriously insufficient now.”</p><p>In late March, Master Gao, who had just been released from the first quarantine, went out to deliver goods.</p><p>“At that time, the local area in Kunshan required a blue label, a green label, and an orange label. I set up a blue label and planned to go from Kunshan to Suzhou on the high-speed.” The color label in Master Gao’s mouth is similar to the “truck version” of the health code.</p><p>It is understood that on March 25, Kunshan City implemented the “Classification Management System for Trucks by Risk Level”, and applied “orange, blue and green” classification management signs for trucks based on the health information of truck drivers and passengers, and based on the “orange, blue, green” classification management system “Three-color signs for precise prevention and control.</p><p>Blue indicates that there is a history of passing through low-risk areas outside Kunshan City, and the itinerary card does not have an asterisk.</p><p>Recently, Mr. Gao got his salary for March, a total of more than 5,000 yuan. What is different from the past is that the income structure has changed from basic salary plus commission to basic salary plus subsidy.</p><p>“To be honest, it’s not a lot, because it’s a total of four or five days of class.” Master Gao said.</p><p>It is understood that in the logistics industry, many drivers who run long-distance trunk lines are paid by trip. For example, if you specially run from Beijing to Guangzhou, it will take four or five days for a round trip, and the intermediate loading and unloading will stay for one day. You can run three or four times a month, and the commission is the main source of income.</p><p>Gao Peng reluctantly said: “It may be a month, two months of hard support, and only three months to pay the basic salary. Large companies may be fine, but small and micro enterprises like us basically can’t stand it all the time. “</p><p>Source: People’s Vision</p><p>On the evening of April 7, Kunshan issued the No. 37 Circular on Epidemic Prevention and Control, and decided to extend the silence period for 4 days from 24:00 on April 8 to 24:00 on April 12, 2022.</p><p>On April 8, AUO, a major panel manufacturer, issued an announcement stating that its Kunshan subsidiary will suspend work from April 8 to 12 in cooperation with the local government’s epidemic prevention and control policy. During the shutdown period, inventory will be allocated to reduce the impact on customers.</p><p>Guanghua-KY, a car interior parts factory, pointed out that its subsidiary Xiangyang Guangjia has flexibly adjusted its production plan due to the suspension of production due to the tightening of epidemic control and logistics blockades in Shanghai, Wuxi and Kunshan for its main customers. At present, sufficient raw material inventory has been prepared to meet the production needs of customers after resumption of work.</p><p>According to the Aijiwei APP, other Taiwanese factories that have announced the suspension of the Kunshan subsidiary include AUO, Xinxing, Baicheng, Lantian, Huafu, Anli-KY, Shanghua, etc.</p><p>Compared with the material problems that can be perceived immediately, the B-side supply chain hiding behind the daily consumption of the public cannot be perceived at the first time.</p><p>“Adding all kinds of time costs, the transportation cost will definitely be high. As far as I know, these companies will lose a part of the money if they send a truck of goods, and the freight will increase by nearly four or five times.” Gao Peng told us.</p><p>wait for a rebound<br>For companies, transportation costs increase and production capacity is limited; for drivers, income decreases.</p><p>“The congestion started around 12 o’clock, and there are still about 3 kilometers to reach the toll station. It is estimated that it will be blocked until 6:00 in the evening to get off the expressway.” On April 8, we got in touch with Master Deng. Among the drivers, and among the acquaintances and colleagues around the driver, the only one still running on the road.</p><p>Master Deng mainly runs short and medium distances, mainly in Jiangsu. There are two main routes for frequent runs, Changzhou to Suqian and Changzhou to Xuzhou. He used to be an accountant in a factory mainly engaged in frozen chicken and duck agricultural products. Five or six years ago, the owner of the factory proposed to let him buy a car and help him pick up the goods. Master Deng started his career as a driver.</p><p>At 6:00 in the morning of April 7th, Master Deng set out from Changzhou and arrived in Suqian at 4:00 in the afternoon. After loading the goods, he went back from Suqian. He slept in the service area at night. If it is not blocked, he should be home soon when we contact him. .</p><p>In the mouth of truck drivers, roads are divided into “on the road” and “off the road.” The upper road is the expressway, and the lower road includes various national roads, provincial roads, and rural roads. Spanning hundreds of thousands of kilometers, except for large-scale logistics, few drivers will take high-speed all the way. Under the epidemic, in order to reduce the time stuck on the road, most of the drivers chose the high speed.</p><p>“If you go down the road, there are checkpoints in every region and every county, and they are all checked. The congestion will be even worse, and you may not be able to get there for a few days. Only the exit of the expressway is blocked, and the others are unblocked.” Master Deng told us.</p><p>Master Deng calculated an account for us: before the epidemic, it was about 4,000 yuan per order, and now it has increased by almost a few hundred, but it cannot reach the previous profit. Although the driver can get an extra subsidy of 500 yuan, it may cost 1,000 yuan to go on the highway. After all, the driver still earns 500 yuan less, and there are always traffic jams. The original cost, including fuel fees and high-speed charges, was about 2,000 yuan per trip, but now it’s about 3,000 yuan.</p><p>This means that the price of a single trip has increased, but the profit and one-month income have fallen.</p><p>“The outbreak of the epidemic in Shanghai was almost 10 times a month, but now it can only run about six or seven times. In the past month, the loss is nearly 10,000 yuan. It used to be about 20,000 yuan a month, but now I earn 10,000 yuan. Money is difficult.” Master Deng said.</p><p>In addition to fewer trips and profits for drivers, the company is also cutting production.</p><p>“Compared with the original, the company’s sales volume has decreased by about 30%. We are refrigerated, the shelf life is 12 months, and it is not affected by the weather very much. However, if it cannot be sold, the storage cost will increase, so we can only reduce production.” Master Deng, an accountant, keenly captured this change.</p><p>It’s not just Mr. Deng’s company that has increased costs.</p><p>“Recently, the Shanghai port is in a state of semi-paralysis. If the ship is not chartered, the freighter will jump to the port. If Shanghai is closed for two weeks, the freighter will first go to Fukuoka, Busan, and return after a month. The bulk parts are basically only safe stocks. Some small-volume materials can still be transshipped by the China-Europe Railway, and large-volume railway transportation costs are not worth the goods, so it is better to stop production.” Liu Ronghui told us that now OEMs are mainly eating inventory, and now physical goods and inventory are king. era.</p><p>Zheng Cuntuan of China-Europe Qatar Airways told us: China-Europe Qatar Airways has been operating normally, and its sources of goods are mainly from Fujian, Guangdong. And the company’s business has grown significantly. It’s hard to tell where the current growth is coming from, though, and it will take two months to know. Because many customers are in urgent need to go to China-Europe Qatar Airways, the planned cargo (after six months) will go slowly by sea.</p><p>As long as demand is there, the impact may be short-lived, and a rebound is just a matter of time.</p><p>“Maybe this period of time will have a serious impact on some small and micro enterprises, but in the long run, if you give some economic stimulus, you should be able to survive. In 2020, we will also send epidemic prevention materials to Wuhan. The first half of the year is very difficult. Difficulties, the manufacturing and logistics industries in the second half of the year are soaring. “ Gao Peng said.</p><p>“I believe that the vitality of the enterprise will not have much impact.” Zheng Cuntuan said.</p><p>The stabilization and recovery of the supply chain has already begun.</p><p>According to reports, on April 7, the Ministry of Transport held a meeting on the logistics guarantee coordination working mechanism. The National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Public Security, the Ministry of Commerce, and the Health and Health Commission and other members of the mechanism attended the meeting.</p><p>The meeting emphasized that coordinating the work of epidemic prevention and control and logistics security is an important task to win the new round of epidemic prevention and control, and it is to ensure the safety and stability of the industrial chain and supply chain, and maintain the normal production and living order of the people. important foundation.</p><p>The meeting pointed out that the problems of inadequate implementation of policies in some regions and overweighting at various levels still exist, and the problem of poor logistics operation in some epidemic-related regions such as the Yangtze River Delta is more prominent. The operation is smooth and the service guarantee for truck drivers is strengthened.</p><p>On April 8, Xiao Yaqing, Minister of China’s Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, said that all efforts should be made to stabilize the production of enterprises and the smooth connection of the supply chain, strengthen the coordination of logistics, transportation and factor guarantees, open up blocking points, and ensure the smooth transportation of key materials and important products.</p><p>On the evening of April 9, Master Wei was still counting potatoes on the side of the road, waiting to go home. We wanted to help him find some supplies to send as much as possible, but Master Wei refused, “Don’t bother, it’s all sealed here, it’s hard to get it, so don’t cause trouble for everyone.”</p><blockquote><footer><strong>@中国企业家杂志</strong><cite><a href="https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1729707066723417822&wfr=spider&for=pc">baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1729707066723417822&wfr=spider&for=pc</a></cite></footer></blockquote><blockquote><footer><strong>@GoogleTranslate</strong><cite><a href="https://baijiahao-baidu-com.translate.goog/s?id=1729707066723417822&wfr=spider&for=pc&_x_tr_sl=zh-CN&_x_tr_tl=en&_x_tr_hl=en&_x_tr_pto=wapp">baijiahao-baidu-com.translate.goog/s?id=1729707066723417822&wfr=spider&for=pc&_x_tr_sl=zh-CN&_x_tr_tl=en&_x_tr_hl=en&_x_tr_pto=wapp</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Some truck drivers were trapped in Shanghai for delivering supplies, some were blocked on highways, and some were quarantined at home because they had just returned to a medium-high-risk place. They are only one link in the construction of the logistics economy - the huge logistics chain is undergoi</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Logistics" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Logistics/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Shanghai Lockdown" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Shanghai-Lockdown/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>China TiO2 market overview Mar.2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/04/06/China-TiO2-market-overview-Mar-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/04/06/China-TiO2-market-overview-Mar-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-04-06T02:35:16.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-06T02:59:18.076Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Minerals"><a href="#Minerals" class="headerlink" title="Minerals"></a>Minerals</h2><p>Inquiries in the titanium ore market were deserted this week, and the quotations of some small and medium-sized miners fell slightly. As of now, the transaction prices of 46,10 titanium mines of small and medium-sized manufacturers are at 2400-2480 yuan / ton, and the quotations of 47,20 mines are 2550-2650 yuan / ton. 38,42 The price of titanium medium ore excluding tax is 1650-1700 yuan / ton; the titanium ore market is stable as a whole, the supply of raw material medium ore is high and the price is high, and the market is under-operated; the recent market has been affected by the public health incident, many downstream manufacturers The transportation of raw materials is difficult, the market demand for titanium ore has declined, and there are not many new orders in the market. Some miners are panicked, the market quotation has declined, and the transaction price has fallen. At the end of the month, the environmental protection team settled in the Chengde area. Titanium ore manufacturers are in a state of suspension. There are not many new orders in the market. Some manufacturers have placed orders in the early stage until the end of April. Chengde market price is strong.</p><h2 id="Titanium-Dioxide"><a href="#Titanium-Dioxide" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Dioxide"></a>Titanium Dioxide</h2><p>The international titanium dioxide company Chemours issued a letter to raise the market price of titanium dioxide. Since May 1, the price will rise by 200 US dollars / ton. As of now, the ex-factory price of China’s rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 19800-21200 yuan / ton, anatase type titanium dioxide. The ex-factory price of titanium dioxide including tax is 18,500-19,200 yuan/ton. Affected by the increase in raw materials and inventories, some manufacturers reduced production and stopped production, and the titanium dioxide market started to decline gradually; this week, the price of sulfuric acid continued to rise at a high level, the price of titanium ore remained high and firm, and the cost pressure of titanium dioxide raw and auxiliary materials was still relatively large; the domestic market demand is still not high. High, maintaining just-needed purchases, the international titanium dioxide market maintains a good trend, some manufacturers export well, and more export orders are delivered. In addition, the international titanium dioxide enterprise Chemours has raised the market price of titanium dioxide, and the rise in international prices is good for the domestic titanium dioxide market. Under the support of cost, the price of titanium dioxide remains high, and it is expected that the titanium dioxide market will operate stably in the short term;</p><h2 id="April-market-forecast"><a href="#April-market-forecast" class="headerlink" title="April market forecast"></a>April market forecast</h2><p>1.The transaction in the titanium ore market is not good, some miners panic, and the price of small and medium titanium ore is expected to decline slightly again;<br>2.The cost of titanium dioxide raw materials is under great pressure, the market inventory has increased, and the price of titanium dioxide is expected to run strongly;</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Minerals
Inquiries in the titanium ore market were deserted this week, and the quotations of some small and medium-sized miners fell slightly. As of now, the transaction prices of 46,10 titanium mines of small and medium-sized manufacturers are at 2400-2480 yuan / ton, and the quotations of 47,20 mi</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="China TiO2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/China-TiO2-market/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 market overview" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-market-overview/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 Price Index reached a new high.</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/03/14/TiO2-Price-Index-reached-a-new-high/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/03/14/TiO2-Price-Index-reached-a-new-high/</id>
    <published>2022-03-14T06:59:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-14T07:12:17.224Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>According to Tio2.pro, The TiO2 index increased 2.5% to 3219 this week.<a href="https://tio2.pro/index.php/2022/03/14/the-tio2-index-reached-a-new-high/">TiO2.pro</a><br>On 09th March. The LB group announced the increasing for 150USD/MT, driven by the raw masterial cost rising and the market needs increasing. Raw material is at high level constantly pressuing the TiO2 industry, but with the price increasing, the confident is recovering. Which was considered as a response to recent up increasing trends leaded by Kronox, Tronox and chemours.<br>With the price reaching a new high, the market is getting more hesitant to purchase, but with the hot season coming, the needs will certain turn to orders even if in a high ground.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">According to Tio2.pro, The TiO2 index increased 2.5% to 3219 this week.TiO2.pro
On 09th March. The LB group announced the increasing for 150USD/MT, driven by the raw masterial cost rising and the market needs increasing. Raw material is at high level constantly pressuing the TiO2 industry, but with </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Kenmare: Production of all products increased significantly in 2021</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/02/21/Kenmare-Production-of-all-products-increased-significantly-in-2021/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/02/21/Kenmare-Production-of-all-products-increased-significantly-in-2021/</id>
    <published>2022-02-21T03:03:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-21T03:49:47.422Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The production of heavy mineral concentrate (HMC) in 2021 is 1.5559 million tons, an increase of 30% compared to 2020 (1.2011 million tons). This was due to the relocation of WCP B to the high-grade Pilivil belt in the third quarter of 2020, resulting in a 19% increase in ore grade to 4.63%. The increase in HMC’s production also benefited from a 14% increase in the volume of ore mined.<br>Volumes of all products increased in Q4 2021 compared to Q4 2020, thanks to higher HMC processing. Production of ilmenite in Q4 2021 is 246,000 tonnes, a 12% increase compared to Q4 2020 and above the 4% increase in HMC processing. This is due to increased recoveries and a drop in intermediate magnetic reserve in Q4 2021. Zircon sand concentrates performed similarly, with an 11% increase in production.<br>2021 was a record year for cargo volumes, with 1,285,300 tons of cargo shipped. This was a 51% increase from fiscal 2020 (853,100 tonnes), reflecting improved transshipment capacity, lower finished goods inventories and higher production. Cargo also benefits from increased transshipment capacity due to previously completed upgrades. Shipments during the year included 118.69 tonnes of ilmenite, 52,900 tonnes of zircon sand, 3,700 tonnes of rutile and 41,800 tonnes of medium tailings.<br>Higher average prices for all products in FY21, a momentum that continues into H1 2022 due to strong demand for Kenmare products and low ilmenite stocks in the global supply chain.</p><h2 id="Table-Production-output-and-forcast"><a href="#Table-Production-output-and-forcast" class="headerlink" title="Table: Production output and forcast"></a>Table: Production output and forcast</h2><p>| Production | Q4 2021(Mt) | vs Q4 2020 | FY 2021(Mt) | vs FY 2020 | 2022 traget |<br>| - | - | - | - | - | - | - |<br>|Ilmenite|246,000|12%|1,119,400|48%|1,125,000-1,225,000|<br>|Zircon|12,400|11%|56,300|30%|54,400 - 63,200|<br>|Rutile|2,100|50%|8,900|48%|9,500 - 11,500|<br>|Zircon Middle tailings|11,300|31%|43,900|25%|40,300 - 46,800|<br>|Freight volume|368,600|15%|1,285,300|51%|/|</p><h2 id="Overview"><a href="#Overview" class="headerlink" title="Overview"></a>Overview</h2><p>At the end of fiscal 2021, HMC closed stocks at 11,600 tonnes, compared to 50,200 tonnes at the start of the year. Finished goods inventories were below the normal level of 88,700 tonnes at the end of 2021 (2020 tonnes: 145,500 tonnes), reflecting a significant increase in shipments this year driven by strong demand for Keniel’s products. Finished goods inventories are expected to rise to more normal levels in 2022.<br>Production of all finished products in fiscal 2022 is expected to be higher than in fiscal 2021, mainly due to higher daily production extracted, which is 4.2% above expected levels. Ilmenite production in fiscal 2022 is expected to be between 1.125 million and 1.225 million tonnes.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">The production of heavy mineral concentrate (HMC) in 2021 is 1.5559 million tons, an increase of 30% compared to 2020 (1.2011 million tons). This was due to the relocation of WCP B to the high-grade Pilivil belt in the third quarter of 2020, resulting in a 19% increase in ore grade to 4.63%. The inc</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Kenmare" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Kenmare/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Comment on the tio2 market during the first week of 2022</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/01/11/Comment-on-the-tio2-market-during-the-first-week-of-2022/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/01/11/Comment-on-the-tio2-market-during-the-first-week-of-2022/</id>
    <published>2022-01-11T08:29:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-11T08:58:10.538Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the former announced price increased taken into effect from 1st Jan.2022.<br>The whole market was in highly concern over the market. The most frequently asked question was that has the price increase actually came into been.<br>Yes, it was done.<br>Moreover, last week, GDPR also announced 1000CNY/MT increase. Up to now, the ex-factory price of China’s rutile titanium dioxide including tax is 18,700-22,500 CNY/MT(FOB 3,000USD/MT- 3550USD/MT), and the ex-factory price of anatase titanium dioxide is 17,500-20,000 CNY/MT(FOB 2,800USD/MT- 3,200USD/MT). This week, some manufacturers resumed production, and some manufacturers plan to overhaul. The overall supply of titanium dioxide is stable. According to data from Toodudu.com, China’s titanium dioxide production in 2021 total about 3,813,500 tons, an increase of 8.24% year-on-year. Production increased by about 290,500 tons. At present, manufacturers have more orders in hand, the downstream market demand has not increased significantly, and the demand remains weak, and manufacturers mainly deliver pre-orders. Recently, individual manufacturers have determined the new execution price in January, and the manufacturer’s quotation has been slightly raised compared with the previous period. The overall market is in a wait-and-see mood, waiting for the price news of LB. According to market news and rumors, the price may rise slightly.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">With the former announced price increased taken into effect from 1st Jan.2022.
The whole market was in highly concern over the market. The most frequently asked question was that has the price increase actually came into been.
Yes, it was done.
Moreover, last week, GDPR also announced 1000CNY/MT inc</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="weekly updates" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/weekly-updates/"/>
    
    
    <category term="tio2 market 2022" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-2022/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Africa&#39;s first titanium dioxide plant is scheduled to be completed and put into operation in 2023</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2022/01/05/Africa-s-first-titanium-dioxide-plant-is-scheduled-to-be-completed-and-put-into-operation-in-2023/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2022/01/05/Africa-s-first-titanium-dioxide-plant-is-scheduled-to-be-completed-and-put-into-operation-in-2023/</id>
    <published>2022-01-05T02:21:22.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-05T03:01:56.176Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, South Africa Nyanza Light Metal Mining Company announced that it will invest 4.5 billion rand (about 280M USD) to build Africa’s first titanium beneficiation plant and produce titanium dioxide. It is expected to be completed in 2023 with a production capacity of 80,000 tons/year.<br>The construction site of the project is located in the Richards Bay Industrial Zone in KwaZulu-Natal Province. The first phase is a technical service center and a pilot plant worth 200 million rand, and the second phase is the main factory. In addition to the 80,000 tons of titanium dioxide per year, other titanium-based materials will be produced from titanium slag.<br>South Africa imports up to 35,000 tons of titanium dioxide each year, while the data for the entire Africa exceeds 150,000 tons. In order to build the titanium dioxide project, Nyanza hired Intertek, a well-known testing and certification company earlier, to make the first titanium dioxide project in Africa famous, thereby transforming South Africa from direct export of ore to deep processing of mineral products.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">A few days ago, South Africa Nyanza Light Metal Mining Company announced that it will invest 4.5 billion rand (about 280M USD) to build Africa’s first titanium beneficiation plant and produce titanium dioxide. It is expected to be completed in 2023 with a production capacity of 80,000 tons/year.
The</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="Africa&#39;s first titanium dioxide plant" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Africa-s-first-titanium-dioxide-plant/"/>
    
    <category term="Nyanza" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/Nyanza/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Is it the last radiance of the setting sun? LB followed the increase trend.</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/12/14/Is-it-the-last-radiance-of-the-setting-sun-LB-followed-the-increase-trend/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/12/14/Is-it-the-last-radiance-of-the-setting-sun-LB-followed-the-increase-trend/</id>
    <published>2021-12-14T08:13:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-14T09:40:07.453Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Background"><a href="#Background" class="headerlink" title="Background"></a>Background</h2><p>Finally the LB group announced the price increased yesterday after the global players with domestic 1000CNY/MT increase, and foreign market 150USD/MT increase, which fllowed by tens of manufactures in China till now.</p><p>In the last month of 2021, the market of tio2 suddenly sore with a new trend of increasing after several months silence.<br>2021 definitely is the most vibrant year of the last decade. But there are obvious reasons for the increases before as,</p><ul><li>The economic recovery boost the needs.</li><li>The pandemic reduces the outputs.</li><li>The global power crisis.</li><li>And the prolonged supply chain.</li></ul><p>But this time, the new trend in this month looks unfamiliar. The needs-supply background is not changed, but why do they increase? It is hard to find out why, but after talking with few experts in our channel, we conclued something in common.</p><p>When we asked, is there any shortage of the ilmenite? power? labor? or productive elements?</p><ul><li>No.</li></ul><p>Is there any policies which reduces the output? What is the quantity estimated to be influenced?</p><ul><li>Not yet but yes, will be. The government is expected to announce the production limits policy to grante the blue sky during winter olympics in northern China for 30-50days. The quantity is arround 100k-120k tons in total.</li></ul><p>Will the production limits policy break the balance of the supply-needs background?</p><ul><li>Not likely. Even there might be 100k-120k tons outputs will be cut, but the spring is always the off-season in tio2 market. Traditionally, the manufactures were likely to spend 15-20days for maintainance during spring.</li></ul><h2 id="Explain"><a href="#Explain" class="headerlink" title="Explain"></a>Explain</h2><p>So, why do they do it?</p><ul><li>To follow up with global trend, the international plays such as Kronos, Tronox, Venator, Chemours, and more announced their increase will effect on in Jan 1st. 2022. After Jan 1st, 2022, there will be more users shifting to China SP grades tio2. Last several monthes, the Western CP grades in western world was in shortate meanwhile the China SP grades price is catching up with the western CP in Asia pacific, africa and many other regions. The increasing price of China SP in some degree enlarge the needs of Western CP grades. But with the official increasing of the western CP grades price, the price gap between China and Western tio2 will be again enlarged. So the Chinese manufactures do belive that there could be another chance of the increasing. But will it come out as they expected?</li></ul><h2 id="Forcasting"><a href="#Forcasting" class="headerlink" title="Forcasting"></a>Forcasting</h2><p>It is the last radiance of the setting sun.</p><ul><li>Since the mid of Oct. 2021 the market is in chill. The manufacturers did not get orders abundant enough as they did in the first half of this year. Some of them even start to reducing the price to test the market. And there are still no new booming of the orders.</li><li>The cost is not incresing, this time the increase is not stand on a solid ground.</li><li>All the announced increasing is effected on Jan 1st. 2022 instead of next week or immediately as they did before. So they are more likely testing the market other than determined increasing.</li></ul><p>So we do have reasons to believe that after the Chinese New Year, without seeing orders booming, the decrease will start sliently. And trust me, more and more suppliers will start to contact you actively.<br>All in all, buy in needs.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Background
Finally the LB group announced the price increased yesterday after the global players with domestic 1000CNY/MT increase, and foreign market 150USD/MT increase, which fllowed by tens of manufactures in China till now.

In the last month of 2021, the market of tio2 suddenly sore with a new </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="tio2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>TiO2 analysis on 3rd Dec. 2021 by ICIS</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/12/06/TiO2-analysis-on-3rd-Dec-2021-by-ICIS/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/12/06/TiO2-analysis-on-3rd-Dec-2021-by-ICIS/</id>
    <published>2021-12-06T07:26:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-13T01:41:56.468Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry this article was not authorised for public sharing. For more detail, please contact us.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Sorry this article was not authorised for public sharing. For more detail, please contact us.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="tio2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="tio2 market analysis" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market-analysis/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The coming 2022 was set to start from a higher ground.</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2021/11/25/The-coming-2022-was-set-to-start-from-a-higher-ground/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2021/11/25/The-coming-2022-was-set-to-start-from-a-higher-ground/</id>
    <published>2021-11-25T06:16:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-25T06:43:09.357Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Kronos’ announcement in 02nd Nov, on 17th Venator announced the 400USD/MT increase in asia pacific region since 1st Jan. 2022. And today, TRONOX announced the 350USD/MT increase in the same region.<br>At the meanwhile, the Chinese suppliers is quiet and easy. Some of them lower their price a little, but most of the suppliers kept their price still. In a whole view, the price is stable. But now, the dealers’ stock is not abundant. If the output comes into a shortage, the price will jump quickly.</p> <span id="more"></span><p><img src="/2021/11/25/The-coming-2022-was-set-to-start-from-a-higher-ground/venatorpriceincreasing.png" alt="Venator price increase announcement"><br><img src="/2021/11/25/The-coming-2022-was-set-to-start-from-a-higher-ground/tronoxpriceincreasing.png" alt="Venator price increase announcement"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">After Kronos’ announcement in 02nd Nov, on 17th Venator announced the 400USD/MT increase in asia pacific region since 1st Jan. 2022. And today, TRONOX announced the 350USD/MT increase in the same region.
At the meanwhile, the Chinese suppliers is quiet and easy. Some of them lower their price a litt</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="tio2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="tio2 market" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/tio2-market/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
