<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>TiO2 Info</title>
  
  <subtitle>All info about Titanium Dioxide</subtitle>
  <link href="https://tio2.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://tio2.info/"/>
  <updated>2024-11-06T00:50:24.098Z</updated>
  <id>https://tio2.info/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>TiO2 Info</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.2</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/11/06/2024_11_06-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.2/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/11/06/2024_11_06-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.2/</id>
    <published>2024-11-06T00:50:23.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-11-06T00:50:24.098Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. Current low transaction prices are around 2060 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 290.60 USD&#x2F;ton), while high-priced shipments face significant pressure.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-grade titanium slag market remains sluggish with chaotic pricing. Some transactions are below 7000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 987.43 USD&#x2F;ton). Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and downstream market operations are insufficient, leading to a weak market for high-grade slag.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 846.53-902.95 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have seen lower transaction prices. The market is under operating pressure with insufficient production, resulting in prices that are weak but stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary grade sponge titanium market price for civilian products is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approx. 5,926.30-6,067.19 USD&#x2F;ton). Downstream demand remains weak, with some enterprises facing significant inventory pressure and insufficient production, compounded by production cost pressures. Thus, sponge titanium prices are weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2131.2, an increase of 10 from yesterday. The market is in a slow season, with overall demand being poor. Titanium dioxide enterprises face increased shipment pressure due to high competition, resulting in prices remaining low.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market is experiencing weak supply and demand, with prices showing a weak trend. Current low transaction prices are around 2060 CNY/ton (approx. 290.60 USD/ton), while high-priced shipments face significant pressure.

Titanium Slag: The</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2129.95</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/31/2024_10_31-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.95/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/31/2024_10_31-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2129.95/</id>
    <published>2024-10-31T09:20:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-31T09:20:19.605Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The downstream market remains weak, providing insufficient support for the titanium ore market. Due to supply issues, domestic titanium ore prices are also quite chaotic.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-grade slag market remains sluggish, with chaotic pricing. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the market continues to operate weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Titanium tetrachloride market prices are quoted at 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 843.24-899.58 USD&#x2F;ton. In some regions, there are lower-priced transactions. Despite high costs and production pressure, the downstream market’s sluggishness drags down the titanium tetrachloride market, with prices temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around 4.2-4.3 CNY&#x2F;ton, equivalent to approximately 590.19-604.22 USD&#x2F;ton. Production remains stable, but demand is still weak, making it difficult to balance production and sales, with prices remaining weakly stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2129.95, down by 1 from yesterday. Environmental inspection teams have been patrolling factories in the Panzhihua area, affecting production at titanium dioxide plants within the park, leading to a decline in operations. Recently, the market has been weak and stable, with chaotic execution prices. Market sentiment is largely pessimistic, and downstream purchasing remains cautious, with titanium dioxide prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The downstream market remains weak, providing insufficient support for the titanium ore market. Due to supply issues, domestic titanium ore prices are also quite chaotic.

Titanium Slag: The high-grade slag market remains sluggish, with chaotic pricing.</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.45</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/30/2024_10_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.45/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/30/2024_10_30-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.45/</id>
    <published>2024-10-30T07:39:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-30T07:40:15.667Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The downstream titanium dioxide market is sluggish, with resistance to titanium ore prices and a strong sentiment for price-cutting. Environmental inspections in the Panxi and Shandong areas have tightened titanium ore supply, leading prices to temporarily stabilize. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The cost pressure for high titanium slag is significant, with many companies operating at a loss and low market activity. Northern enterprises have not tendered this month. The high slag market has low production, and there is an oversupply, leading to continuous market weakness. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,437 and $9,000 per ton, with lower prices in some regions. High production costs and downstream market sluggishness are creating pressure, keeping market prices temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is around $5,961 to $6,043 per ton. After a decline, magnesium ingot prices have stabilized, slightly alleviating costs, but companies are still operating at a loss, leading to weak price stability. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2131.45, unchanged from yesterday. This month, major enterprises offer a discount of $28 per ton to distributors fulfilling task volumes, with only a few companies making minor price adjustments, while others maintain stable prices. This week, environmental groups inspected factories in the Panzhihua area, limiting production and reducing titanium dioxide output. Due to weak demand and low market purchasing sentiment, there is a strong wait-and-see attitude among enterprises, resulting in chaotic market prices, maintained on a case-by-case basis. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The downstream titanium dioxide market is sluggish, with resistance to titanium ore prices and a strong sentiment for price-cutting. Environmental inspections in the Panxi and Shandong areas have tightened titanium ore supply, leading prices to temporar</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2131.15</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/29/2024_10_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.15/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/29/2024_10_29-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2131.15/</id>
    <published>2024-10-29T01:22:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-29T01:23:07.991Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains tight in supply, while the downstream market is overall sluggish. There is significant cost pressure, and market prices are rather chaotic. High-quality imported titanium ore has decreased this year, putting pressure on prices, which remain temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The cost pressure for high titanium slag is substantial, leading to losses for many companies. The market has low operating rates, with northern companies not tendering this month. The high-slag market has low production levels, resulting in an oversupply and continued weak market conditions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,437 and $8,997 per ton. In some regions, transactions occur at lower prices. The market remains stable but has a subdued trading atmosphere, with some companies maintaining production cuts. Prices are temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is approximately $5,963 to $6,046 per ton. After a decline, magnesium ingot prices are stable, slightly easing sponge titanium costs. However, companies are still operating at a loss, and prices are weakly stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2131.15, down by 1 from the previous working day. Demand is sluggish, and companies face significant pressure to sell. Some companies have slightly reduced prices for new orders, keeping the titanium dioxide market in a weak state.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains tight in supply, while the downstream market is overall sluggish. There is significant cost pressure, and market prices are rather chaotic. High-quality imported titanium ore has decreased this year, putting pressure on p</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2132.27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/26/2024_10_26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/26/2024_10_26-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/</id>
    <published>2024-10-26T05:22:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-29T01:23:07.991Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises suffering losses and low production activity. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, resulting in a chaotic market and unstable high-titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $843.49 and $899.47 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, with significant fluctuations recently. Enterprises are cautious in raw material procurement, and the downstream market is experiencing reduced production, causing pressure on the market and stabilizing prices for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium products is around $5,902.39 to $6,042.20 USD per ton. Sponge titanium enterprises are still under inventory pressure, and overall downstream demand remains weak, leading to a temporarily weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2132.27, down by 2 from yesterday. Market demand continues to be weak, and competition is intense, with many waiting for price updates from leading enterprises. The titanium dioxide price is maintained on a per-order negotiation basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.

Titanium Slag: The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises su</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-18 to 2024-10-25</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-18-to-2024-10-25/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-18-to-2024-10-25/</id>
    <published>2024-10-25T03:47:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-25T03:47:43.349Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is relatively stable, with prices for current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Domestic downstream markets are weak, leading to increased pressure on enterprises to sell their stock. Additionally, environmental inspections and mining permit issues have tightened the supply of titanium ore, contributing to high raw material costs.</li><li>Exports of titanium dioxide remain strong, supporting high production levels despite domestic market challenges.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide pigment market remains weak. Enterprises face significant inventory pressure due to sluggish domestic demand, and there is cautious purchasing behavior among buyers.</li><li>Despite high production costs, export markets are providing some support, allowing for high operational rates among manufacturers.</li><li>Some top manufacturers may offer discounts to distributors to stimulate demand, and there may be price adjustments by other producers in the future.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Due to weak downstream demand, titanium dioxide prices are expected to remain stable with a slight weakness.</li><li>The market for titanium dioxide pigments will likely continue to be weak due to ongoing demand softness.</li><li>The imbalance in the supply and demand of sponge titanium will keep prices weak.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is relatively stable, with prices for current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.
 * Domestic downstream markets </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2132.27</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/2024_10_25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/25/2024_10_25-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2132.27/</id>
    <published>2024-10-25T03:44:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-25T03:47:43.345Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises suffering losses and low production activity. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, resulting in a chaotic market and unstable high-titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $843.49 and $899.47 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, with significant fluctuations recently. Enterprises are cautious in raw material procurement, and the downstream market is experiencing reduced production, causing pressure on the market and stabilizing prices for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium products is around $5,902.39 to $6,042.20 USD per ton. Sponge titanium enterprises are still under inventory pressure, and overall downstream demand remains weak, leading to a temporarily weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2132.27, down by 2 from yesterday. Market demand continues to be weak, and competition is intense, with many waiting for price updates from leading enterprises. The titanium dioxide price is maintained on a per-order negotiation basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market remains temporarily stable with limited supply and cautious downstream purchasing, leading to a stalemate in transactions.

Titanium Slag: The high-titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many enterprises su</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2133.77</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/24/2024_10_24-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2133.77/</id>
    <published>2024-10-24T09:06:08.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-24T09:06:36.498Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,436 and $8,998 per ton, with some low-price transactions in certain regions. The price of liquid chlorine has fluctuated significantly today, causing enterprises to be cautious with raw material procurement. The downstream market is also experiencing a decline in activity, putting pressure on the titanium tetrachloride market, though prices remain stable for now.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The market price for grade one sponge titanium is approximately $5,962 to $6,043 per ton. Inventory pressure remains high, and competition in the market is intense, putting pressure on enterprises to sell their products.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2133.77, which is a slight decrease of 1 from yesterday. Market demand is weak, leading to significant sales pressure and inventory challenges for manufacturers. According to market sources, leading companies might implement discount policies, and there have been minor price reductions for some new orders recently, indicating a weak titanium dioxide market.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: High titanium slag is facing significant cost pressures, leading to losses for many enterprises. The market is operating at low capacity, and there has been no bidding from northern enterprises this month, resulting in a chaotic market with unstable hi</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.67</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/23/2024_10_23-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.67/</id>
    <published>2024-10-23T06:52:25.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-23T06:53:03.742Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable high titanium slag prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $844.31-$900.36 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have seen lower prices, but the market has low operating rates. High costs of raw materials exert pressure on companies, and the market price remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $5,909.92-$6,051.40 USD&#x2F;ton. The inventory pressure remains high, and market competition is intense, creating pressure on companies to sell.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current titanium dioxide price index is 2134.67, a decrease of 4 from the previous day. New orders are not performing well, leading to increased inventory for some manufacturers. With high raw material costs, small and medium-sized manufacturers face significant production pressure. The market remains cautious, with prices weakly stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market is under significant cost pressure, with many companies operating at a loss. Market activity is low, particularly in the northern regions, where there are no new tenders for this month. The market is chaotic with unstable </summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-11 to 2024-10-18</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-11-to-2024-10-18/</id>
    <published>2024-10-18T02:11:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T02:16:50.899Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Demand remains lackluster, resulting in large inventory pressures on manufacturers. Environmental regulations and equipment maintenance have led to reduced production in several regions, including Southwest China, East China, and Shandong.</li><li>Despite high raw material costs, manufacturers face significant cost pressures. However, due to the weak domestic demand and the imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil on Chinese titanium dioxide, there is considerable pressure on export prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>The market for titanium dioxide pigments is also under pressure, with several companies reducing prices to stimulate demand. The market remains subdued, with transactions being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</li><li>The imposition of anti-dumping duties by Brazil has added to the challenges faced by Chinese manufacturers. Duties include $578 per ton for LB Group and $654 per ton for Anhui Jin Xing, among others.</li><li>Domestic trade continues to be sluggish, and manufacturers are struggling to balance production and sales, with operating rates hovering around 80%.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Downstream demand is expected to remain weak, leading to continued pressure on titanium dioxide prices.</li><li>Manufacturers are likely to maintain reduced production levels due to environmental and market pressures.</li><li>Export challenges, due to international trade measures, will continue to impact the market, requiring strategic adjustments by manufacturers.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium dioxide market is experiencing weak stability. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.
 * Demand remains lackluster, resulti</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/2024_10_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/18/2024_10_18-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/</id>
    <published>2024-10-18T02:10:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-18T02:12:32.999Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the downstream market remains sluggish. High-titanium material is significantly impacting the market, with production at slag factories being inverted. Some transaction prices in the market continue to weaken, making the operation of the titanium slag market difficult.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between $8,442.56 and $9,003.41 per ton. In certain regions, lower prices have been observed. Raw material prices are relatively unstable, and production pressures are high. The sponge titanium industry is weak, while the demand from the pearlescent industry remains stable, providing strong support for the titanium tetrachloride market. The market price is temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium civilian products is approximately $5,964.18 to $6,047.13 per ton. Enterprises face significant sales pressure, and prices are relatively low. The production of sponge titanium has decreased, and market information is chaotic, maintaining prices at a low level.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2134.82, remaining unchanged from yesterday. Market demand is weak, and raw material costs are relatively high. Manufacturer quotes remain stable. Some major manufacturers are undergoing maintenance, and the titanium dioxide market is temporarily stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. Northern enterprises have not yet tendered this month, and the downstream market remains sluggish. High-titanium material is significantly impacting the market, with production at slag factories being inverted</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2134.82</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/17/2024_10_17-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2134.82/</id>
    <published>2024-10-17T08:43:18.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-17T08:43:55.705Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions where companies have not yet engaged in tendering this month. The downstream market is sluggish, and the influx of enriched titanium materials has had a substantial impact. Production at slag plants is inverted, and some transaction prices continue to weaken, making the slag market difficult to operate.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Prices range between 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 844.46 to 900.38 USD&#x2F;ton). Some regions have seen lower prices. The raw material price for liquid chlorine is unstable, while titanium raw material prices are stable. Titanium tetrachloride producers are under production pressure, but quoted prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium civilian products is approximately 42,000 to 43,000 CNY&#x2F;ton (approximately 5,909.43 to 6,048.54 USD&#x2F;ton). The market demand is weak, and companies are under pressure to sell. Price competition is intense, with some transactions occurring at lower-than-average prices. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2134.82, a decrease of 9 from yesterday. Market demand remains weak, competition is intense, and new transactions are lacking momentum. The market is weakly stable, with prices being negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The mainstream prices of Panzhihua titanium ore remain stable. However, downstream sectors are experiencing significant cost pressures, leading to cautious procurement.

Titanium Slag: The market is quite chaotic, particularly in the northern regions wh</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2144.14</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/16/2024_10_16-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2144.14/</id>
    <published>2024-10-16T03:35:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-16T03:36:28.830Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered, downstream market demand is sluggish, market information is confusing, and production pressure on enterprises is high. Downstream market purchasing remains cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $847.71-$904.11 USD&#x2F;ton. In some regions, there are transactions at lower prices. The price of raw material liquid chlorine is unstable, and titanium raw material prices remain steady. Production pressure is high for titanium tetrachloride enterprises, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium for civilian use is about 4.2-4.3 CNY&#x2F;ton, which is approximately $593.42-$607.55 USD&#x2F;ton. Enterprises continue to face pressure to ship, and there are some transactions at lower prices in the market. The sponge titanium market is operating weakly.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2144.14, down by 9 from yesterday. Manufacturers in the Southwest, East China, and Shandong regions are undergoing maintenance. Market demand remains weak, and enterprises face significant pressure to ship. This month, market operation has slightly declined, but supply remains adequate. Prices continue to be negotiated on a per-order basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The titanium slag market is quite chaotic. This month, northern enterprises have not yet tendered,</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.52</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/15/2024_10_15-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.52/</id>
    <published>2024-10-15T02:17:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-15T02:18:29.081Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern enterprises not yet tendering this month. Downstream market demand is sluggish with mixed signals. Companies are facing significant production pressure, and downstream purchases are cautious.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges between $8,504 and $9,068 per ton, with some regions experiencing lower transaction prices. Raw material liquid chlorine prices are unstable, but titanium raw material prices are steady. Production pressures are significant, and prices are temporarily firm.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream market price for Grade 1 titanium sponge is approximately $6,007 to $6,099 per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, and as production declines, recent prices remain stable. Market sentiment is cautious, with new transactions still weak.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The titanium dioxide price index is 2152.52, unchanged from the previous working day. Market quotations remain stable, and some manufacturers have slightly eased inventory pressure compared to earlier, but demand is still poor. Many enterprises are adopting a wait-and-see approach, with transaction prices negotiated on a case-by-case basis.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The titanium ore market is experiencing a reduction in both supply and demand, with stagnant market transactions. Prices in the Panxi titanium ore market remain temporarily stable.

Titanium Slag: The high-speed market is rather chaotic, with northern e</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium Dioxide Industry Perspective Weekly-2024-10-08 to 2024-10-12</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/Titanium-Dioxide-Industry-Perspective-Weekly-2024-10-08-to-2024-10-12/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T08:51:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T08:54:34.278Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="Market-Report"><a href="#Market-Report" class="headerlink" title="Market Report"></a>Market Report</h1><h2 id="1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis"><a href="#1-Titanium-Dioxide-TiO2-Market-Analysis" class="headerlink" title="1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis"></a>1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis</h2><ul><li>The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.</li><li>Imported titanium ore prices are stable, with Mozambique ore priced at approximately $368 per ton and Kenyan 47-49 grade ore at $362 per ton.</li><li>The titanium slag market remains weak due to oversupply and low demand, with prices under pressure from low rutile prices.</li></ul><h2 id="2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends"><a href="#2-Titanium-Dioxide-Pigment-Market-Trends" class="headerlink" title="2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends"></a>2. Titanium Dioxide Pigment Market Trends</h2><ul><li>Titanium dioxide pigment prices have decreased by $28-$42 per ton post-holiday. Current prices for Chinese rutile titanium dioxide are around $2112-$2252 per ton, and anatase titanium dioxide is around $2009-$2064 per ton.</li><li>Leading manufacturers like the LB Group have lowered prices for both sulfate and chloride process TiO2 by $28-$42 per ton, following the general market trend.</li><li>Weak end-user demand and high raw material costs continue to apply pressure on production, leading to reduced output as some companies have begun maintenance shutdowns.</li></ul><h2 id="3-Market-Forecast"><a href="#3-Market-Forecast" class="headerlink" title="3. Market Forecast"></a>3. Market Forecast</h2><ul><li>Ilmenite supply will remain tight, and prices are expected to stay stable.</li><li>The titanium dioxide market remains weak, with prices expected to hold at lower levels.</li><li>Sponge titanium production is decreasing, maintaining weak price stability.</li></ul><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Market Report
1. Titanium Dioxide (TiO2) Market Analysis
 * The titanium ore (ilmenite) market is experiencing tight supply, causing prices to remain stable. Current prices for titanium ore are $304-$310 per ton for 46,10 grade and $326-$333 per ton for 47,20 grade.
 * Imported titanium ore prices a</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.19</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/12/2024_10_12-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.19/</id>
    <published>2024-10-12T02:11:44.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-12T02:12:34.913Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high titanium slag market remains weak but stable. Northern enterprises have not announced any new tenders this month. Downstream demand is decreasing, creating significant pressure on the high titanium slag market. Some enterprises in the north are reducing or halting production, leading to insufficient market activity and pessimistic market sentiment. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride ranges from 6000 to 6400 CNY&#x2F;ton, approximately $849 to $905 USD&#x2F;ton. Some low-price transactions occur in certain areas, but overall sales volume is low. Despite high raw material costs, the titanium tetrachloride market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 4.2 to 4.3 million CNY&#x2F;ton, which converts to approximately $594,000 to $608,000 USD&#x2F;ton. There is high inventory pressure, and as production decreases, recent sponge titanium prices remain stable. The market is in a wait-and-see mode, with weak new orders. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, maintaining low prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> The current price index is 2152.19, down by 1 point from yesterday. With Brazil’s anti-dumping preliminary ruling publicized, export tax rates for enterprises are high, contributing to the pessimistic market sentiment. Domestic demand remains unsatisfactory, and the titanium dioxide market is weak but stable.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: The supply is limited, downstream demand is weak, and production is declining, leading to a stalemate in the titanium ore market. Prices remain stable, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: The high titanium slag market rem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2152.8</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/11/2024_10_11-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2152.8/</id>
    <published>2024-10-11T01:22:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-11T01:23:06.082Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-demand imbalance and competition from rutile prices. The market is under pressure, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 6,000 to 6,400 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 849 to 905 USD per ton. Some regions report lower transaction prices. External sales are low, but high raw material costs keep the market stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 42,000 to 43,000 CNY per ton, equivalent to approximately 5,943 to 6,084 USD per ton. There is significant inventory pressure, with excess supply keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2152.8, a decrease of 5 points from yesterday. New contract prices are being executed, but demand remains weak. Companies are adopting a wait-and-see approach, and the market remains weak.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Supply remains tight in Panzhihua, with stable prices. In Yunnan, mining operations are restricted due to permitting issues, leading to a shortage of titanium ore and firm prices.

Titanium Slag: Prices for high-grade slag remain low due to a supply-dem</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2158.3</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/10/2024_10_10-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2158.3/</id>
    <published>2024-10-10T01:12:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-10T01:13:46.814Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causing significant production pressure, leading to a weak market.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from approximately $851.43 to $907.96 per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. Despite higher raw material costs, the market remains stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The primary market price for Grade 1 sponge titanium is around $596,056 to $610,165 per ton. Demand remains weak, with some market inventory, keeping prices low.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s price index is 2158.3, a slight increase of 2 points from yesterday. The overall market remains weak with high competition. Some factories are undergoing maintenance, slightly reducing production. Manufacturer inventories are high, and terminal demand is weak, leading to weak price trends.</p><p>This summary provides an overview of the current state of various titanium-related markets, highlighting price trends, market pressures, and operational impacts.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Insufficient production; prices remain stable. The market is maintaining basic demand, with cautious procurement and weak price movements.

Titanium Slag: Low production in the high-temperature market, with low prices. High raw material costs are causin</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2156.16</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/09/2024_10_09-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2156.16/</id>
    <published>2024-10-09T02:18:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-10-09T02:19:29.213Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grade titanium slag, and prices may continue to weaken.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> The market price for titanium tetrachloride is between 6000-6400 CNY per ton, which is approximately 850.52-907.10 USD per ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices. The external market sales volume is low, and with high titanium raw material prices, the market for titanium tetrachloride continues to remain stable.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for grade one sponge titanium is around 42,000-43,000 CNY per ton, which is approximately 5,954.63-6,097.70 USD per ton. Demand has significantly reduced, leading to an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to cut production in October, and the output of sponge titanium continues to decline.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2156.16, a decrease of 45 from the previous business day. As leading companies lower their prices, post-holiday titanium dioxide companies have gradually adjusted their prices, mostly by 200 CNY per ton, which is approximately 28.36 USD per ton. The price of titanium dioxide is stable but weakening.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Slag: The price of high-grade titanium slag remains low. With the downstream market’s operational expectations declining, demand for high-grade titanium slag may reduce. Additionally, the price of rutile is impacting the market, putting pressure on high-grad</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Titanium dioxide price index 2201.26</title>
    <link href="https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/"/>
    <id>https://tio2.info/2024/10/01/2024_10_01-Titanium-dioxide-price-index-2201.26/</id>
    <published>2024-10-01T09:29:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2024-09-30T09:30:46.794Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary"><a href="#Titanium-Industry-Market-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Titanium Industry Market Summary"></a>Titanium Industry Market Summary</h2><p><strong>Titanium Ore:</strong> Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.</p><p><strong>Titanium Slag:</strong> The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The downstream market is weak, and the high slag industry is sluggish.</p><p><strong>Titanium Tetrachloride:</strong> Market prices range from 857.12 to 914.27 USD&#x2F;ton. Some regions have lower transaction prices due to weak demand. The domestic titanium dioxide market is under pressure with high raw material costs, leading to stable prices.</p><p><strong>Sponge Titanium:</strong> The mainstream price for first-grade sponge titanium is around 5999.14 to 6141.23 USD&#x2F;ton. Downstream demand is weak, and there is an oversupply of sponge titanium. Some companies plan to reduce production in October, leading to a continued decline in output.</p><p><strong>Titanium Dioxide Pigment:</strong> Today’s titanium dioxide price index is 2201.26, unchanged from yesterday. The market is in a wait-and-see state before the holiday, with poor transaction conditions. Prices are negotiated on a case-by-case basis, and the market is on hold.</p><blockquote><footer><strong>Source & Copyright: @TIO2PRO</strong><cite><a href="https://tio2.pro/">tio2.pro</a></cite></footer></blockquote>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">Titanium Industry Market Summary
Titanium Ore: Prices remain high, resulting in significant cost pressures for downstream industries. Transaction activity is low, and the market is on hold before the holiday.

Titanium Slag: The high slag market is operating at low capacity with lower prices. The do</summary>
    
    
    
    <category term="Industry news" scheme="https://tio2.info/categories/Industry-news/"/>
    
    
    <category term="TiO2 price trend" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-price-trend/"/>
    
    <category term="TiO2 Price index" scheme="https://tio2.info/tags/TiO2-Price-index/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
